<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>News</title>
            <author>
            	<name ref="corpusmd:CM">Charly Mörth</name>
            </author>
            <principal>
                <name ref="corpusmd:SP">Stephan Procházka</name>
            </principal>
            <funder>
               <name ref="https://ror.org/013tf3c58">FWF Austrian Science Fund</name>
            </funder>
         </titleStmt>
	<publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
	            <name ref="https://ror.org/028bsh698">Austrian Centre for Digital Humanities and Cultural Heritage</name>
            </publisher>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">
                  <p>The Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC BY 4.0) licence applies to this document.</p>
               </licence>
            </availability>
            <date>2023</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>This is a born digital document</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
          <projectDesc>
            <p>This document was created and is made available in the framework of the project "The Shawi-type Arabic dialects". This project has received funding from the Austrian Science Fund (FWF) under the grant agreement No. P 33574.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <listPrefixDef>
             <prefixDef ident="corpusmd" matchPattern="^(.+)$" replacementPattern="../../103_tei_w/shawiCorpus.xml#$1">
               <p>In the context of the SHAWI project, references using the "corpusmd" prefix point to any element in the corpus metadata document via its ID.</p>
            </prefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="texts" matchPattern="^(.+)$" replacementPattern="../../vicav_texts/shawi/$1.xml">
               <p>In the context of the SHAWI project, references using the "texts" prefix point to an XML document in the paratext directory.</p>
            </prefixDef>
    </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc status="draft">
		 <change when="2023-09-21" who="corpusmd:DS">set up templates for SHAWI paratexts</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>

   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:id="shawi.paratexts.about">
            <head>About the Project</head>
		<p>Funded by the Austrian Science Fund FWF (P 33574), SHAWI studies the Arabic dialects of the so-called Shawi-type dialects spoken by small cattle breeding Bedouin tribes in various regions of the Fertile Crescent. Compared to the sedentary dialects of the region, the number of studies that provide linguistic data on Shawi dialects is still relatively small and there exists neither a comprehensive grammar nor a dictionary for any particular variety.</p>

		<p>The project's focus is on the Arabic minority variety spoken in the Harran-Urfa region of Southeastern Turkey. Moreover, linguistic data from speakers in Syria and Iraq will be collected. The project aims to provide three main contributions: (1) a text corpus based on audio recordings, (2) a comprehensive grammar, and (3) a digital dictionary. The basis of all three contributions is new data gathered from the field.</p>

         </div>

      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
