<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>News</title>
            <author>
            	<name ref="corpusmd:CM">Charly Mörth</name>
            </author>
            <principal>
                <name ref="corpusmd:SP">Stephan Procházka</name>
            </principal>
            <funder>
               <name ref="https://ror.org/013tf3c58">FWF Austrian Science Fund</name>
            </funder>
         </titleStmt>
	<publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
	            <name ref="https://ror.org/028bsh698">Austrian Centre for Digital Humanities and Cultural Heritage</name>
            </publisher>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">
                  <p>The Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC BY 4.0) licence applies to this document.</p>
               </licence>
            </availability>
            <date>2023</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>This is a born digital document</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
          <projectDesc>
            <p>This document was created and is made available in the framework of the project "The Shawi-type Arabic dialects". This project has received funding from the Austrian Science Fund (FWF) under the grant agreement No. P 33574.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <listPrefixDef>
             <prefixDef ident="corpusmd" matchPattern="^(.+)$" replacementPattern="../../103_tei_w/shawiCorpus.xml#$1">
               <p>In the context of the SHAWI project, references using the "corpusmd" prefix point to any element in the corpus metadata document via its ID.</p>
            </prefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="texts" matchPattern="^(.+)$" replacementPattern="../../vicav_texts/shawi/$1.xml">
               <p>In the context of the SHAWI project, references using the "texts" prefix point to an XML document in the paratext directory.</p>
            </prefixDef>
    </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc status="draft">
		 <change when="2023-09-21" who="corpusmd:DS">set up templates for SHAWI paratexts</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:id="team">
            <head>Team</head>
		       <p>The SHAWI Team is made up of experts both from the field of Arabic Variantional linguistics and the digital humanities.</p>
               <div>
                  <head>Stephan Prochàzka</head>
                  <p>The project is lead by Stephan Procházka, Institute of Oriental Studies, University of Vienna</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Charly Mörth</head>
                  <p>… is research director of the Austrian Centre for Digital Humanities and Cultural Heritage of the Austrian Academy of Sciences and acts as the national research partner.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Miriam Al Tawil</head>
                  <p>… is a researcher at the Institute of Oriental Studies and has transcribed and annotated the SHAWI corpus.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Aozan Hussien</head>
                  <p>… is a researcher at the Institute of Oriental Studies and has transcribed and annotated the SHAWI corpus.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Mau Abraham</head>
                  <p>… has been working on the integration of the SHAWI corpus in the VICAV application framework.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Levente Kiraly</head>
                  <p>… is reimplementing the frontend of VICAV, which the SHAWI application is built upon.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Omar Siam</head>
                  <p>… acts as the project's interface to the ACDH-CH's infrastructure unit and coordinates the frontend reimplemntation of VICAV.</p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Christoph Hoffmann / Stefan Probst</head>
                  <p>Leads of the ACDH-CH's Frontend Team have shared much of their expertise to the application's user interface, making sure it is aligned with current best-practices.</p>
               </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
