<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-01-10T01:55:01+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-033_Sheikh_Nifil-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:79a23962-a426-4070-b4c9-db01012a6547</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">113</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="7770"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="25160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="25160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="40480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="40480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="57660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="57660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="77101"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="77101"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="86490"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="86500"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="101630"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="101630"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="117640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="117650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="130650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="130650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="144650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="144660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="150980"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="150990"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="167130"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="167140"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="174990"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="174990"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="192480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="192480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="207640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="207640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="225670"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="225670"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="232110"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="232120"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="251630"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="251640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="267710"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="267710"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="278230"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>nahāṛ b-al-ayyām ʕala ayyām dōr zimān ar-rasūl ʕalē-´ aṣ-ṣalāt w-as-salām, hazreti Muḥammad, rāyḥīn ʕa-l-ḥarib, ʕa-l-ḥarib, ḏ̣āllīn hafte, xamǝsṭaʕš yōm, ʕišrīn yōm b-al-ḥarib.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts2" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-yōm-in rāyḥīn, ḏ̣āllīn b-al-ḥarib ǧaʕ-yruddūn min al-ḥarib ʕala byūt-hum, ᵊbsāgt aṣ… ᵊbsāgt aṣ-ṣaḥābt an-nibi wāḥad zād ism-u Nifil, Nifil ᵊbsāgt an-nibi ʕalē-´ aṣ-ṣalāt w-as-salām. Nifil.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a12"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>b-al-ḥarib hāḏa, mistašhid, šahīd, ṣāyir šahīd, maḏbūḥ yaʕni mayyit, ṣāyir šahīd w-ar-rasūl ʕalē-´ as-salām w hazreti ʕAli w-Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣaddīq dāmmīn-u mǝṭraḥ-in mištahid [recte mistašhid] w ǧāyīn ʕala byūt-hum.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a19"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Nifil, yōm-in rāʕit bēt-u, ḥurumt-u aaa ṭābi mihni ʕala gaḷib-ha inn-u zlimit-he mayyit ta-ngūl waḷḷa xāyfe, ʕalē-ha xōf, wāǧfe ʕala… aṣ-ṣaḥābe w-ar-rasūl yōm-in yiǧūn ʕala darib-hum gāṭṭit-il-hum. awwal ar-rasūl qāfilt-u min ǧiddām, ǧaʕ-tiǧi,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāḷat “yā ḥabīb Aḷḷa, yā rasūl Aḷḷa! ᵊzlimt-i Nifil, wēn-u mū rāḥ ᵊbsāgit-hum ḥarām māmiš, mū yamm-ak.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a28"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts13">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ar-rasūl ʕalē-´ aṣ-ṣalāt w-as-salām ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ. gāḷ “š-ilhe dā_gūl al-ḥurma š-arīd agūl l-al-ḥurma hāḏi agūl-l-ha ahnī-he yaʕni, āā axaǧil-he wēya mā_dri šnōn agūl yaʕni aḥazzin-he.” ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ waṛā-´ hīčiḏ</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a33"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts12" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ waṛā-´ in hazreti ʕAli raḏ̣iya ḷḷa ʕan-hu zād b-al-qāfilt al-ikinǧiyye al-ma… aṯ-ṯānye. ǧāye qāfilt hazreti ʕAli zād saʕalatt-u zād ʕayne. gāyilt-ill-u “yā ʕAli ḥarām ᵊzlimt-i rāʕi bēt-i Nifil,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a37"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts17">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>saʕalt ar-rasūl w gāḷ isʕali ʕAli, inte tʕarif aṣṣōb-u wēn ᵊb-hay qāfile?” hazreti ʕAli raḏ̣iya ḷḷāhu ʕan-hu gāḷ “yāw āni šnōn al-ḥurma ḏīye ahnī-he, axaǧil-he. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a41"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts16" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ar-rasūl ʕalē-´ aṣ-ṣalāt wa-salām mā ʕallam-he, w āni šnōn agul-il-he?” zād ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ waṛā-´ hīčiḏ in Abu Bakir, qāfilt Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq. Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq maʕnāt-u aṣ-ṣadīq ṣiddīq mā-y… alle yʕidd aṣ-ṣiddīq ṣādiq.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a46"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāḷ “isʕali hīčiḏ!” mādd b-uṣbuʕ-u zād lē waṛā-´, gāḷ “isʕali Abu Bakir, ǧa-yiǧi huwwe balči yʕarif”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a48"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>uxṛa tānye guṭma ǧāy Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq, yōm-in ǧāy Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq gāyilt-ill-u “yā Abu Bakir, ᵊzlimt-i Nifil, ḥarām, mū maʕā-kum mū bsāgt al-qāfile mū bsāgt aṣ-ṣaḥāba. mū rāḥ ᵊbsāgit-kum, wēn-u?” Abu Bakir aṣ-ṣiddīq ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ gāḷ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a54"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“rasūl aḷḷa mā ʕallam-he, hazreti ʕAli mā ʕallam-he. w-āni šnōn?” yōm-in ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ waṛā-´ hīčiḏ zād mā ḏ̣āll ta-ygūl, ymidd uṣbuʕ-u lē waṛa.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a57"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts24" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts27">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ṣāyiḥ “Aḷḷa!” Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq ṣāyiḥ “aḷḷa!” yōm-in ṣāyiḥ “aḷḷa!” hīčiḏ miltafit waṛā-´ in Nifil rāčib ᵊḥṣān-u w-ǧaʕ-yiǧi waṛā-´. gāl “yā umm-i hāḏa inn-u ǧaʕ yiǧi waṛā-yi.” gāyilt-ill-u “tamām, xurf aḷḷa ʕalē-k, ǧīy.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a63"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts26" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts29">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōminn-u ǧāy Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq damm-u b-īd-u, huwwa damm-u b-īd-u. w ǧī yōm-in ṣāḥ aḷḷa ǧī waṛā-´. ǧī ʕala rasūl aḷḷa, humma aaaa komutanım ḥabībo Muḥammad! ǧī ʕala rasūl aḷḷa, gāḷ “yā ʕala rasūl aḷḷa!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a68"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts28" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>šinhi al-ḥāl? masʔala šnōn hāḏi ṣārat?” gāḷ “ʕalēš yā Abu Bakir?” gāḷ “āni ṣiḥit inte mā ʕallamit-he w Ali mā ʕallam-he. w-āni zād ṣiḥit aḷḷa waḷḷa w inn-u Nifil waṛā-yi rāčib b-al-xēr w ǧaʕ… kidīš w ǧaʕ-yiǧi. šinhi hāḏi ḥikmit-he?” gāḷ-lu “yā Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīqi inte ʕamann-ak ṣiddīq</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a74"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts30" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā tigdar ḥēš-ak, ḥēš-ak mā tigdar tikḏib mā maddēt īd-ak inte alle trīd aṣ-ṣiddīq.” ism-u ṣiddīq.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a76"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“yōm-inn-ak ṣiḥit aḷḷa rabb al-ʕālamīn bi-ʕizzt-u wa-ǧalāl-u, Aḷḷa, darrab-li Ǧabrāyīl w gāl-ill-i “gūl ʕal ḥabībi ta-ygūl l-Abu Bakir l-Abu Bakir, yēlōn-u ṣāyiḥ marrtēn, nōbtēn aḷḷa b-al-ḥarib hāḏa š-gadd-mu mustašhidīn aš-šǝhada aṣ ṣāraw al-mayytīn, xamsmiyya wēya alif wala sabʕimye,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a84"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts37">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yēlōn ṣāyiḥ nōbtēn “aḷḷa” kull-hum āni gawwamit-hum w darrabt-hum bsāgit Nifil, bass sāḥ marra wəḥde miššān Nifil bass gawwamt-ill-u Nifil. ʕamann-u ṣāḥ wəḥde “aḷḷa” āni hemen ǝnṭēt rūḥ-u raddadit rūḥit Nifil ʕala ha… ʕala badan-u,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a91"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts36" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w ramšit ʕēn xallēt-u waṛa Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq ta-mā yičḏib  kalām-u ta-yṣīr yḏ̣all dawām ṣiddīq winn-u waṛā-´, hal-masʔala hāḏi hiyye.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a95" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>One day, in the days and times of the prophet Muḥammad, peace and blessing be upon him, they went to war, to the war, they were away for a week, fifteen days, twenty days they were in the war.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a96" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>After they had gone and stayed in the war, they came back from the war to their houses, together with the companions of the prophet. The name of one of them was Nifil; Nifil was with the prophet, peace and blessing be upon him. Nifil.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a97" ANNOTATION_REF="a12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He had died in this war, he had become a martyr, I mean, he had been killed, he was dead, he had become a martyr, and the prophet, peace and blessing be upon him, ʕAli and Abu Bakr aṣ-Ṣiddīq had burried him at the place where he died. And then they were on their way home. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a98" ANNOTATION_REF="a19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Nifil’s spouse, his wife, of course she had fears in her heart that her husband was dead, let’s say, or she was afraid, she had fears on her. So she was standing (on the road); and when the companions and the prophet passed by she cut their way. The prophet’s caravan was in the front. She went towards them</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a99" ANNOTATION_REF="a25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>and said, “O you beloved of God, messenger of God! My husband, Nifil, where is he? Didn’t he go with them? How come that he is not here, that he is not at your side.”  </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a100" ANNOTATION_REF="a28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The prophet, peace and blessing be upon him, looked around and said (to himself), “What should I tell this woman? What will I tell her? If I tell her… I feel sorry for her. And I don’t know how to say, I mean I will make her sad.” He looked behind him like this.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a101" ANNOTATION_REF="a33">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When he looked behind him, lo and behold, ʕAli, may God bless him, was in the second caravan, in the second. When ʕAli’s caravan came, she asked him the same saying to him, “O ʕAli, how come, my man, my husband Nifil,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a102" ANNOTATION_REF="a37">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>I have already asked the prophet and he said, ‘Ask ʕAli!’ Do you know where he is, where, in which caravan?” ʕAli, may God bless him said (to himself), “How can I let this woman down? I feel sorry for her?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a103" ANNOTATION_REF="a41">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The prophet, blessings and peace be upon him hasn’t told her, and how am I supposed to tell her?” So he looked behind him like this, where he saw Abu Bakr aṣ-Ṣadīq’s caravan. Abu Bakr aṣ-Ṣiddīq, which means “the honest” is honest, he doesn’t... the honest one must be honest.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a104" ANNOTATION_REF="a46">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “Ask him!” He pointed with his finger backwards saying, “Ask Abu Bakr, he is coming, maybe he knows.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a105" ANNOTATION_REF="a48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Again she waited a while, then Abu Bakr came. When Abu Bakr aṣ-Ṣiddīq had come, she said to him: “O Abu Bakr, my husband Nifil, how come that he is not with you; he is not with the caravan, he is not with the companions. Didn’t he go with you? Where is he?” Abu Bakr aṣ-Ṣiddīq looked around and said (to himself) </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a106" ANNOTATION_REF="a54">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“God’s messenger has not told her, ʕAli has not told her, how can I?” When he looked behind him like this, no one was left, let’s say, so he stretched out his finger and pointed backwards.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a107" ANNOTATION_REF="a57">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He shouted, “God!” Abu Bakr aṣ-Ṣiddīq shouted, “God!” When he had shouted, “God!” he turned around and, lo and behold, Nifil was riding on his horse and coming behind him. He said, “My dear lady, there he is coming behind me” She said to him, “Perfect, thank you, he has come (back).”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a108" ANNOTATION_REF="a63">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When Abu Bakr aṣ-Ṣiddīq came, his blood was in his hands (it was his responsibility), his blood was in his hands. And when he shouted, “God”, he (Nifil) came behind him. He came to God’s messenger (and said), “My leader, my beloved, Muḥammad.! He came to God’s messenger, and said, “O God’s messenger!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a109" ANNOTATION_REF="a68">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>What is going on? How did this happen?” He said, “Why, Abu Bakir?” He said, “I shouted that you hadn’t told her and ʕAli hadn’t told her, and I called God and suddenly Nifil was behind me riding safely on a horseand coming closer. What is the wisdom of this?” He said to him “Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq, since you are ṣiddīq (honest)</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a110" ANNOTATION_REF="a74">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>you cannot, God forbid, God forbid, you can not lie. You did not point with your hand backwards, but to want to be honest.” His name is ṣiddīq (the honest).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a111" ANNOTATION_REF="a76">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“When you called God, the Lord of the worlds, he, with his glory and majesty, sent Gabriel to me and said, “Tell my beloved to tell Abu Bakir, Abu Bakir: If he would have shouted twice, two times, God, regardless how many have died in this war, have become martyrs, have perished, five hundred or one thousand or seven hundred…</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a112" ANNOTATION_REF="a84">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>If he had shouted twice, “God!” I would have revived all of them and sent them with Nifil. However, he shouted only once for Nifil, so I just revived Nifil. As he shouted “God” once, I immediatly gave his soul back, I gave Nifil’s soul back to... to his body. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a113" ANNOTATION_REF="a91">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And in the blink of an eye, I made him (appear) behind Abu Bakr aṣ-Ṣiddīq, so he won’t be a liar, so his words will always be ṣiddīq (honest) and so he appeared suddenly behind him.” And that's the way it is.  </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
