<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2023-08-16T15:40:17+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-061_Life_of_al-Harrani-Harran-2010.wav"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="../../../Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-061_Life_of_al-Harrani-Harran-2010.wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:d1bbdad9-7f83-4eaf-abce-aed92d85ab39</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">92</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="10"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="48010"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="48023"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="79813"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="79836"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="155058"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="155069"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="197974"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="197974"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="209215"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="210240"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="224130"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="224130"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="238560"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="238560"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="250410"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="250420"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="264840"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="264840"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="277910"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="277910"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="286640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="286650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="297100"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="297100"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="308550"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="308550"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="319590"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="319590"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="332920"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="332920"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="346510"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="346510"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="357160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="357160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="367479"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a89"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Yṣīr aswad, yṣīr šakl-u aswad, iḥna hina ḥamar, la-l-baṭāta, al-gaʕa šlōn al-gaʕa yṣīr ḥamur ʕala lōn al-gāʕa yṣīr aw lōn ᵊtrāb, ʕala lōn al-gamuḥ, īh! ʕala lōn al-gāʕa awwali bilči ʕan marčūba al-čime al-awwalīn baʕd yāšiya al-ᵊkbār-na ysammu ygūlu al-maṭar lēle yōm yṣīr al-maṭar ygūlu hāḏ al-maṭar čime maṭar ačime w-maṭar al-xōfa an-nahār al-mayṣūm haḏāk.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a90"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Ma ṣār maṭar awwali al-kočari  yšīlūn min al-bīr mayye ykubbūn ba-l-gāʕ ṭalʕat čime. Yaʕni ḏāk al-yōm mayyit ḏāk al-yōm ma ṣār maṭar, maṭar ač-čime yšīlūn mn al-bīr yiṭalʕūn mayye mn al-bīr w-ykubbūn ba-l-gāʕ w-uxra ṣīr čime yaʕni ʕa-ḏāk al-yōm amr Aḷḷa xuṭrat čime ani gilt ill-ak awwali ēh? Al-mayye an-nahār xutrat al-čime w-xuṭratan ḥalīb xuṯrat al-kafi zād zayy šīl-u al-yōm </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a91"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Al-awwalīn baʕaḏ̣-hum yaʕni mu kull-hum yṣīr maṭar al-maṭar haḏāk zād mxaṯirīn al-ḥalīb ṣāyir xāṯir al-awwalīn yaʕrfūn-u ani ma ʕārf-u. al-manṭar hi ši miṯil al-šisir ifṭirt miṯil aṭ-ṭarši haḏāk manṭar yaʕni inčān zaʕzīl fōg an-nār yaṯami ʕadwi bi-miləḥ iṭaʕamtu čiṯīr zēn al-xōǧe čiṯīr zēn. Al-ᵊfṭər naʕam </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a92"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>šlōn yqasslūn-u baʕd čamm sane yiftaḥūn-u, ba-s-sabiʕ snīn ā xōǧe awwali kull iḥna nagadi zurna šēx ḥayāt al-ḥarrāni fotōgrāf gabl-u zēn ġādi 

xōǧe hina huwwa faqīr
šēx ḥayāt al-ḥarrāni huwwa xōǧa al-ǧāmiʕ awwali</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Šēx Ḥayāt al-Ḥarrāni, huwwa awwali b-Ḥarrān faqīr, maḥḥad ytiṣannat-ill-u, maḥḥad ysōlf-u, huwwa ṯarīy-u xōǧe b-Ḥōrān, Ḥōrān mā nindall aṣṣōb-ha.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts13">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa rāyiḥ wāḥad ʕa-l-ʕaskariyye yrūḥūn ʕa-l-ʕaskariyye. yōm-inn-u rāyiḥ ʕa-l-ʕaskariyye, lā, rāyiḥ ʕa-t-tiǧāṛa, yōm-inn-u rāyiḥ ʕa-t-tiǧāṛa ʕa-l-Yaman, yōm-inn-u ʕa-t-tiǧāṛa ʕa-l-Yaman al-gāmiyye txarab tinkasir. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts12" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w yirga w ʕala xšēbe w ʕala xšibe tāxḏ-u ǧǧīb-u b-al-baḥar ʕala ḥarf ǧazṛa, yḏ̣all ᵊb-gaḷb aǧ-ǧazṛa yōm-in ydaḥḥiǧ la-ḥōl-u la-ḥawalēn ahal Ḥarrān. ydaḥḥiǧ mā ḥōl-u mā ḥawalē-´ ydaḥḥiǧ ǧāmiʕ, biʕīd.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts14" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in yrūḥ ʕa-l-biyāḏ̣a yimši yōm-in yiǧi l-aǧ-ǧāmiʕ ʕind aǧ-ǧāmiʕ, ǧāmiʕ, in-hum ǧāyīn ᵊmṣallyīn. al yiǧūn b-aǧ-ǧāmiʕ yṣallūn tiǧi al-malāyka, ᵊṣṣalli b-aǧ-ǧāmiʕ. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a29"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w gāylī-l-u, “inte mīn w mnēn ǧīt?” gāyil, “āni ǧīt ʕala [l-]Yaman ʕa-t-tiǧāṛa w-al-gāmiyye nkasrat w xirbat w-al-ᵊxšēbe ǧābat-ni ʕala ḥarf aǧ-ǧazṛa, w daḥḥagit hīčiḏ w šifit biyāḏ̣a ǧāmiʕ w ǧīt ʕa-ǧ-ǧāmiʕ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a35"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts18" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāylīn “ᵊnḏ̣all hēne b-aǧ-ǧāmiʕ. yiǧi imām al-ǧāmiʕ, al-xōǧe. maḥḥad yāxḏ-ak ʕala Ḥarrān alla l-xōǧe ḏāk.” yōm-inn-u ǧaʕad ᵊbgaḷb aǧ-ǧāmiʕ ǧāy al-xōǧe. yōm-in ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a40"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts20" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>abū! w-inn-u al-faqīr Yaḥya hēne al mā ydaḥḥǧū-l-u. inn-u hāḏa xōǧt aǧ-ǧāmiʕ! gāyim ᵊmṣalli b-aǧ-ǧimāʕa, yōm-in ᵊmṣalli b-aǧ-ǧimāʕa yrīd yrūḥ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a44"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in w-yrīd yrūḥ al-xōǧe hāḏa urkuḏ̣ ᵊb-ḏ̣har-u, gāyil-l-u, “daxīl-ak!” gāyl-ill-u, “āxḏ-ak, amma mā tʕallim ḥade! mā tʕallim!” gāyil, “mā͡ ʕallim.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a48"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts24" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts27">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil-l-u “qammḏ̣ ᵊʕyūn-ak!” yōm-in ᵊmqammiḏ̣ ᵊʕyūn-u mqammiḏ̣ ᵊʕyūn-u, az-zlime. hāḏa yōm-in ᵊmqammiḏ̣ ᵊʕyūn-u w yšīl b-amr aḷḷa ysitt-u b-Ḥarrān.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a53"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts26" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts29">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-innu fākk ᵊʕyūn-u winn-u b-Ḥarrān, fākk ᵊʕyūn-u w ǧāy ᵊflān ʕugub sabʕ ᵊsnīn, ʕugub sabʕ ᵊsnīn tā ǧī flān ǧī flān ǧāy ʕala bēt-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a57"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts28" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ǧāʕid haḏāk uxṛa yiǧi yṣalli al-xōǧe Yaḥye, Yaḥye. yōm-inn-u ǧāy al-ʕaǧāwīn, “ᵊmhabūl,” ygaṭṭbūn-u b-al-ḥaǧar yihnūn-u. w-al-gāyil il mart-u, “š-il-hum b-al-faqīr hāḏa?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a62"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts30" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts33">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yḥāčūn-u hāḏa yēlōn yʕarfūn-u šnōōōn!” mart-u gāyme tisʕal-u, “š-bī-´ š-mā bī-´?” gāyil, “hāḏa huwwa l ǧāb-ni min Ḥōrān, mn-al-Yaman ǧāb-ni hēne!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a68"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts32" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w gāyme tgūl il ǧārit-he: “lā tsōlfūn-u! hāḏa hīčiḏ w hīčiḏ. hāḏa hīčiḏ šēx hāḏa hīčiḏ.” al-… ahal Ḥarrān gāymīn yurkuḏ̣ūn ᵊb-ḏ̣har-u ta-yuguḏ̣būn-u ta-yitimassaḥūn bī-´. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a73"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yiǧi l-arḏ̣ al-gabǝṛ w yxušš hināk ᵊbgaḷb al-gabǝṛ tiftakk al-gāʕ w yxušš bī-he w yrūḥ w-ᵊttičallat.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a75" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sheikh Ḥayāt al-Ḥarrāni was in former times a poor and strange  man in Harran. Nobody listened to him and nobody talked to him. Reportedly he was a scholar from Ḥōrān. I don’t know where Ḥōrān  is.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a76" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Once there was one who went to the military service, they go to the military service. When he went to the military service – no, he went for business! He went for business to Yemen. When he went for business to Yemen the ship broke (and sunk).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a77" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He climbed on a small piece of wood which took him out on the sea and then to coast of an island. He stayed in the middle of the island and looked around (to find) people from Harran. He looked at what was around him and saw a mosque far away.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a78" ANNOTATION_REF="a23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When he went (in the direction of) the white (building) he came to the mosque. The mosque where people were praying. Those who had come to the mosque were praying and (also) the angels had come to pray in the mosque.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a79" ANNOTATION_REF="a29">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They said to him, “Who are you and where are you from?” He said, “I came to Yemen for business. My ship broke up and went into pieces. Lumbers brought be to the coast of the island and when I looked around I found something white, a mosque, and so I came to the mosque.””</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a80" ANNOTATION_REF="a35">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They said, “Let’s stay here in the mosque! The imam of the mosque will come and there is nobody except that imam who can bring you back to Harran.” When he stayed in the mosque, the imam came. When he looked at him, (he said to himself), </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a81" ANNOTATION_REF="a40">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“Hey man, this is the strange Yaḥya at whom nobody looks here (at home). And he is the imam of the mosque!” He (the imam) started to pray with the community and when he had prayed with the community he wanted to go.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a82" ANNOTATION_REF="a44">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When the imam wanted to go he rushed after him and said, “I beseech you!” He said to him, “I will take you (with me), but don’t let anybody know! Don’t tell it!” He said, “I won’t tell.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a83" ANNOTATION_REF="a48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said to him, “Close your eyes!” When he had closed his eyes, this man… When his eyes were closed he took him and—by God’s order—he let him down in Harran.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a84" ANNOTATION_REF="a53">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When he opened his eyes, he was suddenly in Harran. He opened his eyes. And after seven years somebody came. After seven years somebody came to his house.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a85" ANNOTATION_REF="a57">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He was sitting when imam Yaḥya came to pray again (with him). When he came (to the town) the children shouted, “He’s crazy!” They threw stones at him and so on. He said to his wife, “What do they want with this dumb man?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a86" ANNOTATION_REF="a62">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They insult him but if they knew him—how (different would they behave)!” His wife asked him, “Who then is he?” He said, “He is the one who brought me from Ḥōrān, from Yemen he brought me back here.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a87" ANNOTATION_REF="a68">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>She stood up and said to her neighbour, “Don’t talk to him like this! He is this and that. He is a sheikh, so it is.” The people of Harran rushed after him to grasp and touch him. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a88" ANNOTATION_REF="a73">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He came to the site of the grave and entered it. The earth opened, he entered it, went away and (the earth) shut.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
