<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2023-09-30T13:51:57+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-105_Life_in_Former_Times-Harran-2010.wav"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="../../../Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-105_Life_in_Former_Times-Harran-2010.wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:b0807e0d-766a-4ad7-a04d-40544cc32f9a</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">74</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="10"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="71485"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="71485"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="115512"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="115512"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="167080"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="167080"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="204770"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="204782"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="243215"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="254323"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="298904"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="298904"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="362648"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="362648"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="402526"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="402526"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="418499"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="418499"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="462763"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="462763"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="486769"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="486771"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="516078"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="516092"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="541045"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="541068"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="588240"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gabǝḷ-ma tiǧi al-mayye, činna nizraʕ ʕala l-fiddān ʕa-l-bǝgaṛ, ʕa-l-bǝgaṛ, ᵊnšidd ᵊbgaṛtēn b-an-nīr al-xašab w-al-ʕidde xašab, ᵊnḥuṭṭ bī-ha ḥadīde hīčiḏ tišxaṭ al-gāʕ, al-maʕāš zifit, ᵊnšidd ᵊmn-aš-šufāg al-awwali nāxuḏ ṯumnītēn ḥunṭa, nizraʕ ᵊṯnēne fiddānēn ᵊnsūg wāḥad yizraʕ mn-aš-šufāg l-al-maġrib, aṯ-ṯumnītēn, ᵊnšidd aṭ-ṭabbān zād, ᵊnsawwi ṭabbān. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts2" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ā, niǧi tibin čān tibin. ᵊnḥuṭṭ at-tibin miššān al-bǝgaṛ yākl-u al-bǝgaṛ yišbaʕ, ᵊnnām, nnām sāʕtēn gūm saḥḥǝr al-bǝgaṛ nsaḥḥǝr al-bǝgaṛ w mn-aš-šufāg uxṛa nšidd. šuqul-ne maʕāš-ne hāḏa hū čān. awwali aṭ-ṭāḥūn aṭ-ṭaḥīn fōg b-aǧ-Ǧillāb hīčiḏ ᵊb-Āḏane Dōdāš filān. ašidd al-biʕīr min hēn,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕa-l-biʕīr ʕa-ǧ-ǧamal ʕa-č-čaḥaš, “rūḥ ʕa-ṭ-ṭāḥūna ʕa-l-mayye tiṭḥan.” sǝra yox  arbaʕ tiyyām xamǝs tiyyām dört gün beş gün, ekmek yox, aç, kimse yox, sıra yox, arbaʕ tiyyām xamǝs tiyyām nitna tā tiṭḥan aṭ-ṭaḥīn al-bēt hēn mayyit mn-aǧ-ǧūʕ, māmin xubuz. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕala-ma niǧi ʕa-l-bēt inn-u mn-aǧ-ǧīrān nāxuḏ ṭaḥīn aǧ-ǧīrān kull-u ta-nxabiz. niǧi wǝḥde mn-al-ᵊfrād ᵊtrūḥ l-al-gurḏ̣a (gap Turkish 2.57-3.11) wāḥad ᵊmn-al-ᵊfrād yḏ̣all, farde, hā ʕašǝr tiyyām ᵊtxalaṣ, uxṛa nšidd rrūḥ ʕala… hāḏa maʕāš-ne ṃayy māmin.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a26"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>b-al-fiddān taʕabna ᵊmn-aṣ-ṣubuḥ ʕa-l-maġrib ssūg w timši, ᵊmn-aṣ-ṣubuḥ ᵊnšidd l-al-maġrib yēlōn arīd amši ʕala riǧlay-ye aṭubb Āḏane, Āḏane aṭubb-ha hā! mn-aš-šufāg al-xalāṭ aḏ̣-ḏ̣alām māši ʕala riǧlay-ye, yēlōn-i amši hīčiḏ aṭubb Āḏane, min Ḥarrān aṭubb Āḏane, hā hīčiḏ maʕāš-ne čān.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a31"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-ḥurma tilbas ṯōb wāḥad, awwali az-zlime lū ṯōb wāḥad. alḥaz az-zlime lū ʕišrīn ṯōb, al-ḥurma laha ʕišrīn ṯōb kull-ha nāylōn. gāmin yšiddin rūs-hin min waṛa miṯl ad-deve ysawwin miṯl al-biʕīr. salām al-biʕīr yā! ṣār xarāb čān awwali nāmūs ḥayā šī. az-zilime lē rād yufūt al-ḥurma tigaf xamsīn mītraw</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a36"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>tigaf w tilimm ṯōb-ha hīčiḏ. miṯil al-yasīr miṯil al-ēr ʕind al-yüzbāši. lummin-ma az-zlime yfūt tā hī tfūt. čān ṣudug, awwali čān nāmūs. wāḥad lē tiḏ̣āyag al-ʕašīre kull-he tgūm ᵊbsāgt-u. nāmūs ḥayā qayriyye, ē has-sāʕa hāḏiy al-axx umud-u b-axū-´ ʕalag ᵊb-an-nāṛ, nāmūs mā ḏ̣all, ḥayā mā ḏ̣all. al-ḥurma gāmat ᵊtdūs fōg gaḷb az-zilime hīčiḏ ᵊtfūt. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a57"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-ᵊkbāṛ ġābat yeni moda çıktı naylōn naylōn. awwali čān ǧūx, yirmi sine aǧ-ǧūx tilbas hū yḏ̣all ǧidīd. alḥaz naylōn šahar yʕallig yrūḥ. awwali činna ʕala l-xēl nirkab al-xēl nifzaʕ b-at-tfungāt ᵊnḥāmi waṭan-ne.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a48"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-lēl w-an-nahāṛ ᵊnḥāmi l-waṭan, lā yiǧī-na dišmān min Sūrīye. yiǧi yāxuḏ qanam-ne yāxuḏ baʕar-ne yāxuḏ ḥalāl-ne</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a49"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts18" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>at-tfunge b-īd-ak b-al-lēl b-an-nahāṛ miṯl al-ʕaskariyye. min ᵊtnām haḏāk yiǧi yāxuḏ ḥalāl-ak yiḏbaḥ-ak. hā hīčiḏ čān. alḥaz ṣār as-sayyārāt nāmūs mā ḏ̣all ṣār guṭun ṣār mǝṣāri ṣār mǝṣāri xērsīz. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a54"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts20" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>awwali činna b-wrugət pangalōt tā rrūḥ ʕa-l-midīne tā rrūḥ aw niǧi. alḥaz b-al-malyār ᵊtrūḥ l-al-madīne tiǧi bōš. xērsiz bereketsiz, ē alḥamdilla ʕala d-dawle alḥamdilla ʕala ḥukūmit-ne, alḥamdilla ʕala Turkīt-ne. aḷḷa ygawwi al-bērag al-ḥamar</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a58"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>wa-ḥne ǧawwā-´. aḷḷa lā yqarrb-in-na w yrazzil-na miṯl al-qēr. inšaḷḷa l-bērag al-ḥamar hāḏe yiḏ̣aḷḷ ʕalēne hīčiḏ. ayyıldız. iḥna ʕāyšīn kēf alḥaz ǧawwā-´. inšaḷḷa dāyme yḏ̣all hīčiḏ fōg-ne. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a59"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>aḷḷa yʕammir at-Turkiyye. awwali čānu ʕArab Ḥarrān yrūḥūn ʕala Sūriyye miššān kīlow čāy yōma kīlow ghawa. al-ʕaskar yuḏ̣urbūn-u ʕa-l-ᵊḥdūd zād ymūt. alḥaz kullši b-Turkiyye šīy, aḷḷa berekettir aḷḷa yhannī-ne ᵊm-maʕāš-ne! – āmīn.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a60"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>iš-šū ᵊb-duwal al-aǧnabiyye kull-u ʕind-ina b-Turkiyye, hā hīčiḏ w-inšaḷḷa dāyme hīčiḏ, aḷḷa yistir-ne, min gaḏ̣ab aḏ̣-ḏ̣ulum w-ač-čiḏib. ē mū hīčiḏ yā wald axū-y? – naʕam naʕam!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a61" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Before the water came we used to cultivate the fields with animals, with cows, with cows. We used to tie two cows to the wooden yoke; the plough was also made of wood and we put a ploughshare of iron onto it. Like this it ploughed the soil. The earnings were misarable.  Formerly we used to work from dusk and took only two ṯumniyye of wheat. We cultivated two acres (fiddān = 4,200 sqm). One would had to work on the soil from dusk to dawn for two ṯumniyye of wheat.  We also pulled the ṭabbān, we did the work with the ṭabbān (which is used to cover the seeds).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a62" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Yes, we also came for the straw, there was the straw. We took the straw for the cows to eat, in order that the cows get full. We slept two hours, and then got up and fed the cows. We fed the cows and worked on the soil again from dusk onwards. This was our work and our income. And the mill for the flour was up there in aǧ-Ǧillāb, in Āḏane, in Dōdaš, and so on. I went from here</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a63" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>with the camels. On the back of the camels and the donkeys. “Go to the water mill to grind the crop!” There was a long queue; four, five days, four five days no bread, hunger, nobody; and a long queue. We waited for four or five days in order to mill the flour while the family here was dying of hunger, because there was no bread.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a64" ANNOTATION_REF="a21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Until we came home they (lit. we) took the neighbours’ flour to bake bread. One female member of the family went to borrow something. One of the the family members used to do this, one female member. Well, and after ten days it (the flour) was finished and we went again. This was our life, there was no water. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a65" ANNOTATION_REF="a26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>With draught animals; it is tiring to work from the morning to evening on the field! We ploughed from morning to evening and if I had walked (the same distance in one direction) I would have reached Adana, yes I had reached Adana! From dusk to nightfall I was walking and if I had walked (straight) I had reached Adana; from Harran I had reached Adana. Like this was our life.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a66" ANNOTATION_REF="a31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The woman used to wear one single garment and the man had one single garment in former times. Now the man has twenty garments and the woman has also twenty garments, which are all made of nylon. They have begun to bind their hair in ponytail style (lit. camel) like a camel’s tail. Like a camel! Everything has become spoiled; in former times their was honour and shame. When a man liked to pass by the woman stood behind fifty metres.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a67" ANNOTATION_REF="a36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>She stopped and tightened her garment like this. Like a prisoner, like a private in front of a lieutenant. When the man had passed then she was allowed to pass. There was honesty; there was honour in former times. When one had problems the whole tribe was on his side. There was honour, shame, and helpfulness. But nowadays a brother’s hope is that his brother burns in the fire. Neither honour nor shame has remained. The woman has begun to step on the man’s heart; like this she goes on.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a74" ANNOTATION_REF="a57">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The old are gone. There is a new fashion out, namely, the nylon. It was the felt in the former times. Even if you wear felt for twenty years, it would stay new, but nowadays the nylon clothes are worn out within a month. Formerly, we used to ride on horses; we went to the rescue with rifles and protected our homeland.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a68" ANNOTATION_REF="a48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>We were protecting the country day and night that no enemy would come from Syria; somebody who would come and take our sheep, he would take our camels, he would take our cattle.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a69" ANNOTATION_REF="a49">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The rifle must remain in your hand day and night like in the military. If you fall asleep, he (the enemy) will come and take your cattle and kill you. It was like that. Nowadays there are cars (instead of horses). There is no honour anymore. There is cotton and therefore more money, bad money.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a70" ANNOTATION_REF="a54">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>In the former times we used to go to the city and come back with one banknote, but nowadays you go to Urfa with 1 billion Turkish pounds and come back empty-handed. It is bad money nowadays, with no blessing. Thank God for the state, our government and our Turkey. May God strengthen the red banner!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a71" ANNOTATION_REF="a58">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>We are inside the country (under its shadow). May God not make us flee and suffer like the others. God willing this red banner will stay upon us like this. The crescent and the star. We live happily here. May it always remain like this!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a72" ANNOTATION_REF="a59">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>May God let Turkey prosper. In the former times, the Arabs of Harran used to go to Syria for a kilo of tee or coffee and the soldiers shot at them when one approached the border. Nowadays there is everything in Turkey. God has blessed it. May God make us satisfied with our income. – Amen.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a73" ANNOTATION_REF="a60">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Whatever there is in the foreign countries, we have it all here in Turkey too. Yes, it is like that, and God willing it will always be like that. May God save us from the wrath of injustice and lies. Isn’t like that, my cousin? Yes, definitely. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
