<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-01-11T11:08:53+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Y:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-122_Nimrod-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:81e18d34-66bf-4af2-884a-f92a1d53852b</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">40</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="0"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="19358"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="19361"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="30138"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="30138"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="53305"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="53305"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="75166"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="75193"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="87915"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="87971"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="100443"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="100443"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="118138"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="118165"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="130526"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="130555"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="147082"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="147110"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="163527"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="163527"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="173194"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="173225"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="182792"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="182804"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="196977"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="196977"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="210138"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="210193"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="229110"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="229131"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="241377"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="241395"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="254263"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="254282"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="271281"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Namrūd, xōǧam, ᵊb-zimānāt ʕāyiš b-Uṛfa, huwwa as satt Ibrāhīm al-Xalīl b-al-mayye b-an-nāṛ. Namrūd siʕīd, siʕīd, aḷḷa ḥābb-u awwal nōb awwal aḷḷa ḥābb-u ʕala gōl al-awwalīn yaʕni ygūlūn</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a2"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ygūl “āni tanrə, āni rabb.” yaʕni tōba astaġfir aḷḷa, ḥāša yā rabbi, huwwa ygūl, Namrūd. Namrūd min gadd mū-hu siʕīd. ᵊǧbilit Namrūd šifit-he?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a3"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>– ē, šifit-he. ygūl, yōm-in yirga ʕa-ǧ-ǧbile rāčib al-kidīše, w yirga ʕa-ǧ-ǧbile, min amr_aḷḷa al… al-kidīše riǧlēn-ha aǧ-ǧiddāmiyyāt yṣīrin giṣīrāt, yigṣaran, yigṣaran, taʕrif yigṣaran? w riǧlēn-ha al-warāniyyāt, arqa ayaqlar ta-ngūl ygūl at-turuk, yiṭwalan tā trūḥ ʕadil, mā tmayyl-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a4"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yirga ʕa-ǧ-ǧbile il-məṭraḥ-u mn-asfal, min ad-dūz il-makān-u. w ygūl yōm-inn-u yḥawwil asfal, asfal yaʕni yḥawwil mn-aǧ-ǧbile asfal yinḥadir, ǟǟǟ, al-kidīše riǧlēn-ha aǧ-ǧiddāmiyyāt yuṭwalan w-al-warāniyyāt yigṣaran tā mā tmayyl-u, yḏ̣all yḥawwil hīčiḏ dūz biša… ʕadil.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>lummin-ma yḥawwil b-al-gāʕ, w baʕdēn yitidazginin min amr aḷḷa. aḷḷa ḥābb-u, siʕīd, ḥābb-u. bass huwwa ḥaḏ̣ḏ̣-u fāyin, mā aslam yēlōn-u muslim daha zēn ṣār, amma Namrūd!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>šī ǧarye hēne isim-he al-Qazāni, al-Qazāni asfal yamm ǟǟǟ… ta-ngūl b-al-ōvat Ḥarrān asfal ygūl, b-al-Q… al-Qazāni maʕnāt-u qazāni ǧidir yaʕni qazāni, b-at-turuk qazāni. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ygūl al-ʕēš yistawi, a… aǧ-ǧidir al-ʕēš, ḥamīṣt al-laḥam ta-ngūl yišwūn-he wēya qazan kebāb wēya o zaman huwwa š-yākul mā nindall. yigūl min īd lē īd ynawwšūn-u, lummun-ma yrūḥ l-aǧ-ǧbile ygūlūn bi-xaməs daqāyiq yiṣal aǧ-ǧidir, yiṣal ḥāṛṛ, al-ʕēš ḥāṛṛ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yiṭbaxūn-u asfal b-al-Qazāni w ydarrbūn-u ʕalē-´ l-aǧ-ǧbile elden ele ygūl at-turuk, min īd lē īd, min īd lē īd, min īd lē īd, inn-u wāṣl-u b-xaməs sitt daqāyiq, ʕašər daqāyiq aǧ-ǧidir yrūḥ ḥārr.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>huwwa siʕīd. Namrūd, maḥḥad yigdar-l-u abad, yaʕni ẓālim bir hükümdār, rabb al-ʕālamīn bi-ʕizzt-u w ǧalāl-u, tabi al-ʕulama gā… ygūlūn gāylīn “ti-tiǧi bagga w ti-tiḏbaḥ Namrūd.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yaʕni al-millt al mā ǧidrat-l-u, al-millt… ᵊšgadd ḥārab mā māt, amma bagga, bagga trīd tiḏbaḥ Namrūd. ygūlūn al-awwalīn. huwwa ʕād al-məbāšrīt-u ʕind-u yaʕni ta-ngūl al… al yduggūn b-aṛ-ṛamil, alle yšūfūn aǧ ǧiddām, xawāǧt-u  al ʕind-u</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a11"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāylīn “yā Namrūd”, ǟǟǟ yxāfūn ʕalē-´, gāyil “bagga ti-tiḏbaḥ-u maʕ al-asaf.” yōm-in gāylī-l-u “ti-tiǧī-k bagga w tiḏbaḥ-ak.” yāw al gāyil “al-bagga šnōn tiḏbaḥ-ni?”  </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a37"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“waḷḷa” gāylīn “yā Namrūd, al-bagga tiḏbaḥ-ak inta xušš ǧawwa! čalliṭ ʕala ḥāl-ak al-bāb w lā tiṭlaʕ baṛṛa! lummin-ma nšūf, ta-nšūf ᵊšnōn yṣīr.” </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a38"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>xāšš ᵊmčalliṭ ʕala ḥāl-u al-bāb b-ad-dār ᵊmčallṭīn al-qīrān aṭ-ṭūg, mū mxallīn šakle txušš ᵊb-nōba, bass ᵊmxallīn hnīt al-bāb arəḏ̣ al-miftāḥ hāḏi, nāsyīn-he, ḏ̣ālla maftūḥa w ǧāye l-bagga xušši min ġādi, hīčiḏ aḷḷa darrab-ha ʕalē-´.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>xāšša l-bagga ʕalē-´ ǧawwa zzzzzzz w xušši b-xašm-u min xǝššt-u min xašm-u xušši w rāgye ʕala mǝxx-u. huwwa ʕād ᵊb-mǝxx-u Namrūd ǧaʕad ta-ngūl tgūm al-bagga tākul ətsāwī-´ raḥatsīz ᵊb-mǝxx-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts29" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w bass yihabbṭūn hīčiḏ ʕala kellt-u hīčiḏ ǧāʕdīn ʕind-u wāḥad w yhabbiṭ b-šīt-in xafīfe: ṭǝqq! ṭǝqq! yhabbiṭ ʕala kafft-u tā al-bagga mā tigaf. nahāṛ nahāṛēn ṯalāṯe xamse ʕašra mn-al-iyyām gāyl-il-hum “nahāṛ huwwa mū yirīd ymūt?” gāyil “al-kelle hāḏiy al-bagga ḏī mā tuṭlaʕ min-he.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a16"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts31" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“w-az-zēn intu sāwū-l-i kallit ḏahab, min ḏahab sāwū-l-i kalle tā hāḏi agṭaḥ-ḥa w-aḥuṭṭ al kallt aḏ-ḏahab haḏīč al-bagga (mā taʕnī-he) mā tʕadī-he”, gāylīn “tamām!” huwwa maḥḥad yiǧarrib yixālf-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a17"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>nahāṛ ǧāybīn waḷḷa ǧā… ǧāy… ǧā… ǧāybīn as-sēf w-al-mūs wāḥad ǧāybīn ᵊmsāwī-l-u kellit ḏahab. w gāṭʕīn kellt-u w ḥāṭṭīn kellt aḏ-ḏahab fōg-u w yraččbūn-he yrīdūn tā yxayyṭūn-he Namrūd rāḥ māt!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a18"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-kalle rāḥat al-bani ādam in ᵊngaṭʕat kallt-u, yḏ̣all ṭayyib? – lā! – w māt ʕād Namrūd gāḷaw ʕād al-bagga ṣārat-ill-u aǧal, ṣārat-ill-u aǧal, al-bagga sabab w-al-bagga ktilat an-Namrūd.  w salāmt-ak w-al-ʕāfiye!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a19" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Nimrod, my teacher, lived once in Urfa and he was the one who threw Abraham (into the water) into the fire. Nimrod was lucky, God loved him; according to what the ancestors say, first God loved him, so they say.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a20" ANNOTATION_REF="a2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>(But then) he said, “I am God, I am the Lord.” Penance, I ask God’s foregiveness, God forbid, that’s what he said. Nimrod was so lucky! Have you seen Mount Nimrod? </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21" ANNOTATION_REF="a3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>– Yes, I’ve seen it. It is said that, when he went up the mountain riding his horse, when he climbed the mountain, God gave it that the horse’s fore feet became shorter and its hind feet – arqa ayaqlar they say in Turkish – became longer. They became longer so that it (the horse) went up even and did not bring him in a bent position.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a22" ANNOTATION_REF="a4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He went up the mountain to his place from below, from the plain to his place. It is said that when he went down from the mountain, when he descended, the horse’s fore feet became long and the hind feet became short. So that it did not bring him in a bent position; he kept on descending like this, upright.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23" ANNOTATION_REF="a5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When he came back to the plain they (the horse’s feet) returned to their right position by God’s command. God loved him, he was lucky, He loved him. However, his luck dwined, (because) he did not became Muslim. If he had become a Muslim it had been better, but he was Nimrod (and hence undiscerning).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a24" ANNOTATION_REF="a6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>There is a village here whose name is al-Qazāni, al-Qazāni down there next to… down in the Plain of Harran. The meaning of al-Qazāni is cauldron, in Turkish kazan.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>It is said that the food was cooked in the cauldron, roasted meet which they had grilled, or kebab in a pot or – I don’t know what they used to eat at that time. It is said that, when he went up to the mountain, they passed the pot from one hand to the other within five minutes so that the food arrived there hot.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a26" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They cooked the food down in al-Qazāni and sent it up the mountain to him, elden ele they say in Turkish, from hand to hand. The pot reached him within five, six or ten minutes, still hot.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a27" ANNOTATION_REF="a9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He was lucky. Nobody was able to harm him, he was a tyrannic ruler. The Lord of the universe, by His power and virtue… the learned men said, “A mosquito will come and will kill Nimrod.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a28" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The people could do him no harm, how much they fought him he did not die. But a mosquito, a mosquito will kill Nimrod. So say the ancestors. How many experts he had, let’s say those who could foresee the future in the sand, all the wise men he had.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a29" ANNOTATION_REF="a11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They said, “O Nimrod!” They were afraid for him and said, “Unfortunately a mosquito will kill him. When they said to him, “A mosquito will come to you and kill you”, he said, “Dude, how can a mosquito kill me?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a39" ANNOTATION_REF="a37">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“By God”, they said, “O Nimrod, the mosquito will kill you. Go inside, close the door and don’t come out again! Then we will see what will happen.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a40" ANNOTATION_REF="a38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He went inside and shut himself away in the house. They closed all holes and windows and left nothing where anything could have entered. However, they forgot the thing in the door, the keyhole. They left it open and – lo and behold! – the mosquito came through it. So God sent it to him.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a32" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The mosquito came inside, zzzzzzz and – lo and behold! – entered his nose and through his nose it came up to his brain. Now the mosquito was in his, Nimrod’s brain and began to make him uncomfortable. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a33" ANNOTATION_REF="a15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They patted his head like this; they were sitting beside him and one always striked him gently (on his head): tok tok. He patted his head in order that the mosquito falls out of it. One, two, three, five, ten days passed. He said to them, “One day more and he will die indeed!” He (Nimrod) said, “This mosquito will not leave my head.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a34" ANNOTATION_REF="a16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“The best is that you make me a golden head. Make me a head of gold so that I can cut this one and put on the golden head which the mosquito cannot harm.” They said, “Okay!” Nobody dared to object to him.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a35" ANNOTATION_REF="a17">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The next day they brought a sword and a big knife and they had made for him a golden head. Then they cut his head and put the head of gold on him and fixed it. They wanted to stitch it on him, but Nimrod died!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a36" ANNOTATION_REF="a18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The head was gone! When the head of a man is cut off, can he stay alive? – No! – So Nimrod died and they say that a mosquito was his fate, it was his fate, the mosquito was the reason and it killed Nimrod. Enjoy it!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
