<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2023-12-19T16:47:59+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-092_Sultan_Murad-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:14ffdc72-a5cc-4739-bbbe-f63805da5c0f</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">196</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="4880"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="22040"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="22050"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="41090"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="41090"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="62190"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="62205"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="81081"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="81171"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="97413"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="97413"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="110565"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="110586"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="125412"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="125412"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="141750"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="141760"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="156610"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="156620"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="174680"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="174716"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="193999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="193999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="208380"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="208381"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="226030"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="226030"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="246450"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="246460"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="259660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="259660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="280150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="280150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="300270"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="300280"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="312524"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="312534"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="325878"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts39" TIME_VALUE="325878"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts40" TIME_VALUE="341070"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts41" TIME_VALUE="341070"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts42" TIME_VALUE="361350"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts43" TIME_VALUE="361354"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts44" TIME_VALUE="376804"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts45" TIME_VALUE="376816"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts46" TIME_VALUE="390830"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts47" TIME_VALUE="390840"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts48" TIME_VALUE="409870"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts49" TIME_VALUE="409870"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts50" TIME_VALUE="422478"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts51" TIME_VALUE="422492"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts52" TIME_VALUE="442424"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts53" TIME_VALUE="442424"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts54" TIME_VALUE="453020"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts55" TIME_VALUE="453044"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts56" TIME_VALUE="471274"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts57" TIME_VALUE="471316"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts58" TIME_VALUE="489209"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts59" TIME_VALUE="489244"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts60" TIME_VALUE="502337"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts61" TIME_VALUE="502337"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts62" TIME_VALUE="512140"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts63" TIME_VALUE="512140"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts64" TIME_VALUE="540427"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>as-sulṭān Murād, ᵊb-zimānāt ʕala dōr al- ʕuṯmāniyye. huwwa ḥākim zād belli bi… zimān ᵊmsawwi qǝrāliyye bāše yaʕni ʕa-l- ʕuṯmāniyye. huwwa ḍurum, ḍurm-u ṣāyir guṭma ḏ̣aʕīf, ḏ̣aʕfān.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a165"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ḏ̣aʕfān ḍurm-u dawilt-u yaʕni min ṭaraf al-ʕaǧ… ʕaskarīt-u, min ṭaraf silāḥ-u w-min ṭaraf šakl-u ḏ̣aʕfān, yaʕni ʕind-u xāynīn ṣāyrīn wuzārat-u wazīrīt-u wzārt-u. ar-rūs, ač-čār ar-rūs, ar-rūs čārǝ gāyil-l-u mdizz-ill-u xabar,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil-l-u yā… də-rūḥu gūlū-l-u, mdarrb-ill-u ēlčiyye gāyil ǟǟǟ… “arīd minn-u ḥarib, sawaš, ḥarib arīd minn-u ḥarib ta-ntaḥārab,” w-gāyil, “tamām!” Sulṭān Murād gāyil masale ʕugub hafte ta-yḥaḏ̣ḏ̣ir ʕaskar-u ta-niǧi ntaḥārab ʕa-l-ᵊḥdūd.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sulṭān Murād qāft-u mašġūḷa. ǧaʕ- ydawwir b-al-ᵊhniyye ǧāy ᵊmxalli as-sarāy ᵊmxalli kullši ṭāliʕ ʕa-ǧ-ǧbile w ǧaʕ-ydawwir hīčiḏ miṯl al-maǧnūn, miṯl al-ᵊmhabūl ydawwir b-aǧ-ǧbile. hināk mitxaṭṭm-u rāʕi.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a166"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in šāyif ar-rāʕi, ar-rāʕi mā yʕarf-u inn-u Murād. mā yʕarif inn-u l-qǝrāl. gāyil-l-u “š-bī-k yāba? ǧūʕān? taʕāl āni ʕind-i xāṯir w ḥalīb w… w ǧubun, xubuz, taʕāl w-ukul yā šāyib yā ʕamm-i! ukul! āni daḥḥiǧ ʕind-i xāṯir w xubuz, taʕāl! tifaḏ̣ḏ̣al ukul!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a167"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ar-rāʕi faqīr yaʕni dīwāne. mənṭī-´ gāyim yiṭʕam-u xāṯir w ǧubun w ḥalīb w mišbiʕ-u w gāyil-l-u: “čalēt xāṯir w-ᵊhniyy inčād ᵊtrīd xāṯir zād anṭī-k saṭəl.” gāyil “yā axū-ye, iš-l-i bī-´?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a168"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mənṭī-´ zād saṭǝl xāṯir gāyil hāḏa uxḏ-u li-bēt-ak hadiyye. balči inte faqīr ašūf-ak b-ᵊhniyye b-qāft-ak čiṯīr mašġūḷa. as-sulṭān māxḏ-u w-gāyil as-sulṭān zād gāyil “bāčir āni uxra arīd, bēt-ak aṣṣōb-u?” gāyil “bēt-i b-al-balad hēne,” ta-ngūl.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a30"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāl “bēt-ak aṣṣōb-u?” gāyil “bēt-i b-al-midīne.” gāyil “ē,” gāyil “bāčir āni arīd aǧi ʕa-l-balad,” ar-rāʕi, “bāčir āni aǧi ʕa-l-balad, w inčād ᵊtgūl tā d-aǧīb-l-ak zād saṭəl xāṯir, aṣṣōb bēt-ak? bēt-ak aṣṣōb-u?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a34"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>waḷḷa gāyil “bēt-i āni, mā tindall bēt-i bass tiǧi ʕa-l-ᵊhniyye ʕal… – ta-ngūl – ʕa-s-sarāy, āni aštaġil b-as-sarāy qādi šāġūl,” mū mʕallim ʕala ḥāl-u, “bass ᵊtgūl minu?” gāyil “ism-ak šinu?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a38"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil “ʔin saʕalit ᵊtgūl Murād ač-čibīr humma kull ḥade yaʕrif-ni qādi, ydallūn-ak ʕalayye bēt Murād ač-čibīr,” gāyil l-ar-rāʕi.  “tamām,” gāl ar-rāʕi.” waḷḷa ar-rāʕi rāyiḥ w-ǧāy ʕala s-sulṭān Murād ᵊmḥawwil ʕala bēt-u ǧāy, </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a169"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ṯāni nhāṛ ar-rāʕi msāwi saṭǝl xāṯir w yḥuṭṭ-u b-īd-u  w gāyil “arīd arūḥ āxuḏ l-aš-šāyib haḏāk al-faqīr. ᵊb-xēr-i tā_nṭī-´ saṭǝl xāṯir.” yōm-inn-u minkatt ʕa-s-sūg ǧāy ʕa-l-balad, yisʕal b-al-ʕaskar ǧāy ʕa-l-bāb ʕa… ta-ngūl awwali š-isim-he, as-sūr.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a48"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yrīd yxušš min as-sūr ǧawwa mā-yxallūn-u gāyil “walu! hāḏa hēne wāḥad yištaġil  ʕid-kum ism-u Murād ač-čibīr, w āni ǧibt-il-lu saṭəl xāṯir.” “wal” gāylīn “yā xayyo hēne māmiš Murād ač-čibīr, inte yaġnīš! iḥne mā ʕid-na Murād ač-čibīr, ʕid-na wāḥad sulṭān Murād.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a170"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts27">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE> “w-as-sulṭān šinu šuġ… inte ǧāyb-ill-u l-as-sulṭān saṭǝl xāṯir, ᵊtrūḥ ǧawwa yiḏbaḥ-ak.” “wal” gāyil “yā ǧimāʕa āni mā-li šuġul ʕid sulṭān Murād, ani arīd Murād ač-čibīr, asʕal ʕin Murād ač-čibīr, Murād. hāḏa min fōg hīčiḏ, mā_dri šnōn, lāyḥ-u, šāyf-u al-Murād,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a56"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts26" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>as-sulṭān Murād šāyif ar-rāʕi w gāyil “xallū-´ hōbhōb ṣīḥū-l-u hāḏa xallū-´ yiǧi ǧawwa! iftaḥū-l-u, fukkū-l-u al-bāb! fukkū-l-u al-bāb xall yǧī-ni ǧawwa. fākkī-l-u al-bāb, “wal” gāyil “wal inte mā tʕallim-ni ya wal, ṯarīy-ak inte s-sulṭān. ᵊtgūl āni Murād ač-čibīr, demek tiḏ̣ḥak ʕalay-ye. ʕalē-ma ʕallamit-ni?” ar-rāʕi ygūl ʕal-Murād ʕa-l-pādišāh.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a61"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts29" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ǧāy xāšš ǧawwa “abū wal” gāyil “inte ḥarām ʕind-ak xadādīm w ʕind-ak zilum. mā tʕallim-ni wal albāriḥ āni agūl aš-šāyib al-faġīr hāḏa, ʕaǧal mn-aǧ-ǧbile ataltil ᵊb-saṭl al-xāṯir w-inte hēne kullši ʕind-ak. mā tgūl-l-i?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a65"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts30" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts33">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil “waḷḷa, yā xayyo, hīčiḏ āni gilt ašūf al-mille yōm-in-ha agūl-l-he kull-he tgūm ᵊtgallǧ-ill-i, ssāwī-l-i yaʕni, ē,  yiḥibbūn-ni ʕamann-i qrāl. inte ḥabbēt-ni ʕamann-i faqīr ǧibt-ill-i saṭǝl xāṯir.” gāyil “ugʕud ugʕud ta-nšūf ta-ntiharraǧ āni w-inte,” as-sulṭān ygūl l-ar-rāʕi.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a70"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts32" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“gūl! yā xayyo iš-bī-k?” gāl “yā, yā xū-ye huṃṃa ǧimīʕ ǧāʕdīn waḥad-hum” gāyil “āni xulg-i ḏ̣ayyiǧ w ṭǝlaʕit ǧīt ʕa-ǧ-ǧbile, ar-rūs, dawlit ar-rūs w fakkat ʕalay-ye ᵊtrīd minn-i ḥarəb. w-āni mā ǧaʕad atigēwan ᵊb-ʕaskar-i wālīt-i qāymaqāmīt-i, ta-ngūl ḏīč as-sāʕa ši-agūl-il-hum?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a75"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā ǧaʕad atigēwan bī-hum tā_ḥārb ar-rūs axāf ar-rūs yqallib-ne. yuqlub-ni, mā ǧaʕad atigēwan ᵊb-millt-i.” gāyl-lu: “ʕalēh mā ttigēwan?” gāyil “waḷḷa yā ḥa… mā_ndall mā ǧaʕad atigēwan.” .</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a171"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts37" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil “inte ʕaǧal ᵊmhabūl ʕaǧal? mǝnte qrāl ʕalē-hum? mā ssāwī-hum mā tṭawwaʕ-hum [tṭawwaḥ-ḥum] mā tdazgin-hum.” “šnōn asāwī-hum” gāyil, inte šnōn ᵊssāwī-hum?” hāḏa, “ʕǝṭ-ni msāʕde hafte zimān, āni adazgin-he. adazgin ʕaskar-ak.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a172"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts39" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts40">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“tsss” gāyil “xayyo dazgin! ʕind-inn-ak inte tdazgin-he tā¬_rīd ašūf ᵊšnōn ᵊtdazgin-he.” gāyil “awwal bādye inte ʕaskar-ak, tinṭī-ni hafte š-mā asāwi mā ḥad, mā ttiqāraš ᵊb-šuġl-i!” gāyil “iš-mā tsāwi inte serbest!” gāyil l-ar-rāʕi.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a173"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts41" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts42">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ar-rāʕi gāḏ̣ib awwal mu… lāmm gāyil “čam wulāye šī ʕa-l-ʕuṯmāniyye?” ta-ngūl imyit wulāye imyit wulāye, al-wulāyāt hāḏi mdarrib ʕalē-hum xabar lissa hafte šī ʕād ʕa-r-rūs mdarrib ʕalē-hum xabar gāyil kull-kum bāčir baʕad bāčir ti-tiltammūn tiǧūn hēne b-as-sarāy, aḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur hēne arīd-kum. ʕugub ṯalaṯ tiyyām. .</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a174"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts43" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts44">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mdarrib ʕalē-hum ṭurrāše yaʕni ṭurrāše xabarǧi kull-hum ṣāyiḥ-il-hum b-al… lāmm-hum b-al-ḥōš yōm-in lāmm-hum gāyil kull awwali yilbasūn zibnāt ʕabāt ta-ngūl kallīge dišdāše</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a175"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts45" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts46">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil aḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur “daḥḥǧu!” lāmm al-ʕaskar ḥōl-ma ḥawālē-hum gāyil “daḥḥǧu! š-mā_gūl āni ti-ssāwūn?” gāylīn “ī!” ygūl “tek tek” gāyl-lil-hum “šīlu ʕabāt-kum lē fōg!” sarāwīl mū lābsīn “šīlu ʕabāt-kum tā_rīd adaḥḥič aslām alle min nuṣāra.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a96"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts47" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts49">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yaʕni bī-hum xāynīn, huwwe yrīd huwwe… dawle islāmiyye al-ʕuṯmāniyye ʕalēš wgaʕat? gāyil “šīlu!” ydaḥḥič “hāḏa ᵊmṭahhar hāḏa ygūl ṣaġlam, uṭluʕ min hēne! hāḏa mū ᵊmṭahhar, hāḏa” ygūl “guṭṭu kallt-u!” awwal bādye ᵊmṣaffi al-wāliyye al-qāymaqāmiyye ḥəkkām-u</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a101"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts48" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts50">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ᵊmṣaffi al-miṭṭahhrīn w-al mū miṭṭahhrīn gāyil ta-ngūl ḏ̣āllīn ʕašra xamǝsṭaʕš miṭṭahhrīn ʕišrīn w-ṯimānīn mū miṭṭahhrīn demek ki kull-ha xāyne b-dawəlt-u mū m-Islām ᵊmsawwīhum wāli qaymaqām ḥākim.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a176"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts51" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts52">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>as-sulṭān Murād ydaḥḥiǧ ʕalē-´ min qādi, yā wal gāyil šūf ar-rāʕi l-ᵊmhabūl qāft-u tištaġil axēr minn-i. qāft ar-rāʕi tištaġil axēr minn-i āni yaʕni zād demek bōš ṣāyir pāše ṣāyir padišāh. ʕugub-mu ᵊmṣaffī-hum gāyil arīd-kum kull min ʕaskar-kum ᵊtḥaḏ̣ḏ̣rūn ʕaskar-kum kāmil w tiǧūn ʕugub hafte ar-rūs ᵊnrīd ᵊnḥārb-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a109"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts53" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts54">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in lāmm ʕaskar-u w ʕaskar-u kull-hum ǧāyīn ṣaġlam. ʕaskar-hum haḏōle, intu haḏōle ḏabbaḥ-hum. yōm-in ǧāyib-hum yirīd yḥārb ar-rūs, al-xabar rāyiḥ ʕala rūsye.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a177"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts55" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts56">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>wāḥad ǧāsūs min-hum minhazim, rāyiḥ ʕa-r-rūs gāyil “yā xayyo, as-sulṭān Murād lāgī-l-u wazīr-in ʕāǧil čiṯīr ʕāǧil w ǧuwāsīs-ne kull-ha ḏabaḥ-ḥa, w lā tgārbūn luwwa tarā-hu yqallib-kum tarā yqallb-ak” ar-rūs “šnōn” gāylīn, gāḷ “kull ǧuwāsīs-ne guṭaʕ klāl-hum.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a178"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts57" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts58">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-wazīr aǧ-ǧidīd w al ʕind-u saġlam ʕaskar-in ṣaġlam, han-nōba tara yqallbūn-ak lā tḥārb-u! āni agul-l-ak lā tḥārb-u!” ar-rūs ʕād gāḏ̣ib ta-ydarrib xabar uxṛa ʕala sulṭān Murāḍ gāyil “xayyo āni mā ʕād aḥārb-ak as-sawaš mā ʕād arīd-u. sawa... al-ḥarib mā arīd minn-ak, baṭṭalit ʕin al-ḥarib.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a179"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts59" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts60">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w wāǧif yōm-in ǧāy aṭ-ṭāriš al-mar… as-sulṭān Murād gāyil “ᵊšnōn mā ǧā-k al-xabar?” ar-rāʕi ygūl l-as-sulṭān Murād “mā ǧā-k al-xabar?” gāyil “šinu min xabar?” gāyil “mā ǧā-k al-xabar mā yḥārbūn-ak da-axabar l-ak.” gāyil “ᵊšnōn?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a180"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts61" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts63">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāḷ āni aʕarif iḥna al-ʕaskariyye al-ordi hāḏi maḥḥad yiqlab-ha b-ad-dinye. alḥaz yiǧī-k ṭāriš” w ṣaḥīḥ ǧāy-u gāyil “mā yḥārbūn-ak gǝḏ̣at, w-salāmt-ak w-al-ʕāfiye.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a123"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts62" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts64">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕugub-min qādi ʕād han-nōb sulṭān Murād gāyl-ill-u gāyil l-ar-rāʕi gāyil “xayyo mā ḏ̣all ʕind-i yaʕni wuzart-in mhabale [wazīrt-i mhabbil] mahbūl, inte ḏ̣all ʕind-i ṣṣīr wazīr!” gāyil “abū-ye āni, āni šuġl-i āni rāʕi kull-min ysāwi šuġl-u maḥ… āni šuġl-i rāʕi arūḥ ʕala qnim-i w-inte zād šuġl-ak sulṭān ilg-ill-ak wazīr-in zēn han-nōba wāḥad-in ʕāǧil w sāw dawilt-ak idāra! ᵊmsallim ʕalē-k w-ad-arūḥ.” w-salāmt-ak w-al-ʕāfiye!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a131" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sultan Murad was, in his time, in the era of the Ottomans, a ruler. It’s known that he was a king, a pasha for the Ottomans. But his situation was a little bit weak and fragile.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a181" ANNOTATION_REF="a165">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>His situation and his country were weak. Weak with regard to his soldiers, with regard to his weapons, and with regard to his inner state. That means, his ministers have become treacherous. The Russians, the Tsar of the Russians, has sent him a message,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a133" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>telling him… “Go and tell him!”—He had sent to him messangers—“I want war with you, fighting, I want war with you, let’s fight!” Sultan Murad said, “Agreed! After one week—to prepare his soldiers—let’s fight at the border!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a134" ANNOTATION_REF="a15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sultan Murad’s mind was very busy. He was looking for something, he left his palace, he left everything and went up to a mountain seeking for something like crazy, like a madman. There, a shepherd met him.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a182" ANNOTATION_REF="a166">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When the shepherd saw him, he didn’t know that he was (Sultan) Murad. He did not know that he was the king. He said, “What’s wrong with you, daddy? Are you hungry? Come! I have yoghurt, milk, and cheese, and bread. Come and eat, old man, my uncle! Eat! Look, I have yoghurt and bread! Come, help yourself, eat!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a183" ANNOTATION_REF="a167">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The shepherd was naïve and indigent. He gave him yoghurt, cheese and milk to eat and thus filled him. Then he said, “ You have eaten yoghurt and if you want more yoghurt I’ll give you a whole bucket.” He said, “My brother, what I’m doing with all that?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a184" ANNOTATION_REF="a168">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He gave him a bucket full of yoghurt and said, “Take this home as a present! Maybe you are poor and I see that your mind is very much occupied with something.” The sultan took it and then (the shepherd) said, “Tomorrow I will (bring you) more, where is your house?” He said, “My house is in the town.” Let’s say.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a138" ANNOTATION_REF="a30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “Where is your house?” He said, “My house is in the town.” He said, “Okay, tomorrow I will come to town.” The shepherd said, “Tomorrow I will come to town and if you agree, I will bring you another bucket of yoghurt. Where’s your house?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a139" ANNOTATION_REF="a34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“My house,” he said, “You don’t know my house, just come to the whatsit, to the palace. I work in the palace, I am a worker there.” He did not reveal himself. (The shepherd) said, “Just say who… what is your name?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a140" ANNOTATION_REF="a38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said to the shepherd, “When you ask, say Murad the elder, they all know me there and will show you the way to me, to the house of Murad the elder.” The shepherd said, “Agreed!” and (the next day) he went to Sultan Murad, he went down to his house there.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a185" ANNOTATION_REF="a169">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The next day he prepared a bucket of yoghurt, took it in his hand and said, “I want to go and bring it to this old, poor man. Do a good deed and let’s give him a bucket of yoghurt!” When he came down to the market, to the town, he asked the soldiers at the gate, at the… how did they call it formerly? The city wall. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a142" ANNOTATION_REF="a48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He wanted to go inside through the city wall, but they did not let him in. He said, “Hey dude, there is one here working with you whose name is Murad the elder and have brought a bucket of yoghurt for him.” They said, “Hey brother, here is no Murad the elder, you are wrong! There is only one Murad, the sultan.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a186" ANNOTATION_REF="a170">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“The sultan has got nothing to do with you.” If you go inside and give him a bucket of yoghurt he will kill you.” He said, “ Guys, I have nothing to do with Sultan Murad, I want Murad the elder, I ask for Murad the elder, Murad!” That one, Murad—I don’t know how—saw him from above and recognized him.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a144" ANNOTATION_REF="a56">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sultan Murad saw the shepherd and said, “Get a move on! Call him and let him come inside! Open the gate! Open the gate and let him come to me!” After they had opened the gate for him he said, “Hey guy, you haven’t told me that you are apparently the sultan. You said to me, ‘I am Murad the elder,’ which means you made fun of me. Why didn’t you tell me?” said the shepherd to Murad, to the Padishah.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a145" ANNOTATION_REF="a61">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When he came in he said, “Indeed! I see that you have servants and other men! You didn’t tell me about this. Yesterday I thought you are a poor, old man and therefore I carried this bucket of yoghurt down from the mountain. And you have everything here. Why don’t you tell me?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a146" ANNOTATION_REF="a65">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “By God, my brother! I see that the people just adulate me, they do me… let’s say they only like me, because I am a king. But you liked me because of my poverty and you gave me a bucket of yoghurt. Sit down and let us have a chat.” The sultan said this to the shepherd.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a147" ANNOTATION_REF="a70">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“My brother, what’s wrong with you?” He said, “My brother, they all are sitting around alone (i.e. they do not co-operate). I am in despair and so I went up to the mountain. The Russians, the State of the Russians declared war to me, but I can not trust my soldiers, deputies, and governors. What should I do now?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a148" ANNOTATION_REF="a75">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>I do not trust them to fight the Russians and I am afraid that the Russian will defeat us. They will defeat me and I do not trust my people.” He said, “Why don’t you trust them?” He said, “By God, I don’t know it, but I don’t trust them.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a187" ANNOTATION_REF="a171">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “Are you crazy? Arent’t you king over them? And you don’t put them right, you don’t make them to be obedient and don’t sort them out.” He said, “How can I put them right?” He said, “Give me permission to do it,  just a for a week, and I will sort them out. I will make your soldiers obedient.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a188" ANNOTATION_REF="a172">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“Tsss,” He said, “My brother, sort them out! Whereas you will sort them out, I will look how you do this.” He said, “First of all, (regarding) your soldiers, give me one week and whatever I do, do not intervene!” He said to the shepherd, “Whatever you do, you are free.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a189" ANNOTATION_REF="a173">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>First the shepherd (wanted) to bring and gather them. He said, “How many provinces are there in the Ottoman Empire?” Let’s say there are hundred, hundred provinces. So he sent a message to these provinces that there is one week left until (the fight) with the Russians. He sent a message saying, “All of you have to come tomorrow (or) after tomorrow and gather in the palace at noon. I want to have you here after three days.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a190" ANNOTATION_REF="a174">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He sent messangers to them, heralds, to call all of them and to gather them in the courtyard. When they had gathered in the courtyard… at that time everybody wear cloak-like wraps.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a191" ANNOTATION_REF="a175">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>At noon he said, “Look!” The soldiers have had gathered around them. Then he said, “Look! You will do what I say?” They said, “Yes!” He said, “One after the other!” Then they said to them, “Lift your robes  up!” They did not wear trousers. “Lift your robes up! I want to see if you are Muslim or Christian.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a154" ANNOTATION_REF="a96">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>There were traitors among them and he wanted (to find out) why the Ottoman had become weak although they are a Muslim country. He said, “Lift up!” then he looked and said, “He is circumcised, he is allright, go away from here! He is not circumcised, cut his head off!” First of all he sorted out the governors, the rulers.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a155" ANNOTATION_REF="a101">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He sorted out those who were circumcised and those who were not circumcised. There left ten, fifteen or twenty circumcised men. Eighty were not circumcises which means they were all traitors in his country, they were not Muslim, but he had made them governors and rulers.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a192" ANNOTATION_REF="a176">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sultan Murad looked at him from far and said, “Hey, look at this crude shepherd, his brain works better than mine. The brain of this shepherd is better than mine. I have become a Padishah and a Pasha for nothing!” After he had sorted them out he said (to his generals), “I want from you that all your soldiers are completely ready after a week; then we will fight the Russians.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a157" ANNOTATION_REF="a109">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When he had gatherd his soldiers they were all allright. As for the other soldiers, he had killed them. When he brought them to fight the Russian the news had reached the Russians.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a193" ANNOTATION_REF="a177">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>One of their spies had escaped, went to the Russians and said, “My brother, they have found a very intelligent vizier for Sultan Murad and they killed all our spies. Do not come near him as he will certainly defeat you.” The Russians said, “How come?” He said, “They cut the heads of all our spies.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a194" ANNOTATION_REF="a178">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The new vizier has reliable soldiers, this time they will certainly defeat you, don’t fight them! I tell you, don’t fight them!” And then the Russians sent another message to Sultan Murad saying, “My brother, I do no longer fight you, I don’t want war, I don’t want fighting, I have dismissed fighting.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a195" ANNOTATION_REF="a179">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When the messanger came to Sultan Murad the shepherd said to him, “Haven’t you got the news?” Haven’t you got it?” He said, “What kind of news?” He said, “Haven’t you got the message that they will not fight you? I want to inform you.” He said, “How come?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a196" ANNOTATION_REF="a180">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “I know that these soldiers, this army cannot be defeated by anyone in the world. Now, a messenger is going to come to you.” And right, he came to him and said, “They will not fight you, (war) is over, may you be safe and sound!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a164" ANNOTATION_REF="a123">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>After that Sultan Murad said to the shepherd, “My brother, no stupid viziers have remained with me, so you become my vizier!” He said, “My father, my job is to be a shepherd and everybody should do his job. My job is to be a shepherd, and so I go with my sheep. Your job is to be sultan, so find yourself a good vizier, a clever one, and set your country in order! So I say good bye and go away.” 
Enjoy it!

</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
