<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2023-02-09T16:13:13+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Y:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-012_Lentils-Harran-2010.wav"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="../../../Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-012_Lentils-Harran-2010.wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:b5cd475c-e71a-43c7-9eca-dfeefaeac03d</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">169</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="4220"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="24507"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="24511"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="42596"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="42596"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="62895"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="62895"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="84934"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="84934"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="104356"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="104363"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="119774"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="119788"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="135999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="135999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="149366"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="149375"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="171431"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="171440"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="194852"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="194852"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="210540"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="210540"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="228567"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="228568"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="251934"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="251944"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="278302"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="278302"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="296000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="296013"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="312830"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="312830"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="328100"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa al-ˁadas, yizraˁūn-u ˀonikinǧi ˀay ˀonbirinǧi ay xamǝs tušhur yḏ̣all hīčiḏ arbaˁ tušhur, xamǝs tušhur sitt tušhur baˁdēn yiǧūn yiḥaṣṣdūnu  b-al-mōṭōrāt yōm-innu yības ˁugub xamǝsṭaˁǝš yōm hīčiḏ , baˁad-ma yības b-al-mōṭōrāt yiḥaṣṣdūn-u yuṭluˁūn at-tibin ˁayrǝ</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>tibnu w-al-ˁadas ˁayrǝ , w-al-ˁadas ˁād  yāxḏūn-u ˀahal-u ybīˁūn-u  b-al-ˁarṣa b-al-ˁarṣa yibīˁūn-u, al-ˁadas taqrīban al-ˁadas al… hāḏa al-xaḏ̣ar ᵊngul-l-u, yeşil mercimek ybīˁūn kīlawu waraqa wruga, al-kīlo, al-ˁadas</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-at-tibin ybīˁūn-u  ʔimyit ǧiriš ʕašər ᵊgrūš  – ˁašr ᵊgrūš  – ˁašr ᵊgrūš yaˁni  al-ˁašǝr kīlawāt waraqa at-tibin w-al-ˁadas, baˁdēn-ma yāxḏūn-u ˁa-l-fabrikāt tkassr-u  ysāwūn-u  qišimtēn yṣīr kīlawu (b-)malyūnēn gišr-u yiṭlǝˁūn-u yiṭlǝˁūn gišr-u  yṣīr al-kīlu (b-)malyūnēn</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a37"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>b-al-markēt, b-as-sūpermarkēt b-al-baqqāl yibīˁūn-u  b-wrugtēn w-nuṣṣ,  waraqtēn w-nuṣṣ yaˁni waraqtēn zād ybīˁūn-u taqġrīban bir yūrow  yaˁni yūrow avrūpa ˁa-l-bēt  iḥna nrūḥ nāxuḏ xamǝs  kīlawāt, yāzī-na šahrēn ṯalāṯ al-… an-nuṣṣ kīlo rubuʕ kīlu ysāwi ʕēš lin-ne, nuṣṣ kīlo ysāwī-na ʕēš šōraba</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a51"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts8" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-hāḏi l-gāˁ?  al-gāˁ hāḏi siǧīy. hāḏi siǧīy ˀī, hāḏa l-ˁadas hāḏa siǧīy maˁṭīn-u mayye yēlōn mū siǧīy mā yṣīr al-ˁiḏīy mā yṣīr hēne čünkü al-ˁiḏīy yibas mā ṣār mǝṭar  yibas min hāḏa ysawwūn-u siǧīy</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a61"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā ššūf al-buwāri haḏanne yǧībūn-hin  ysāwūn siǧīy yisǧūn bī-hin al-ˁadas al-mayye… b-al-buwāri haḏanne yisḥabūn mayye w-yisǧūn al-ˁadas w-al-mayye hāḏi mayyt al-barāǧ hāḏi mayyit al-barāǧ hāḏi – hāḏi mayyt al-barāǧ - – hāḏi mayyit al-barāč.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a67"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>tiǧi hēne yōm-in al-barāč ydaššrūn al-mayye yḥuṭṭūn ṣīfōn ᵊbgaḷǝb-ha, buwāri, ṣīfōn, halḥīn mayye māmiš, magṭūʕa, hāḏi timtali mayye yḥuṭṭūn al-būri, aṣ-ṣīfōn hēne yḥuṭṭūn, w-min hēne tgūm ᵊtkubb yisǧūn al-ʕadas bī-´.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a75"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts14" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yinṭūn-u mayye yōm-innu yaʕṭaš, yisgūn-u mayye, al-mayye taġrīban ʕal-ʕadas marra wəḥde mayye šahar ᵊtkaffīy, tāzīy. baʕd aš-šahar uxṛa yisḥabūn yaʕṭūn-u mayye ta-mā yibas.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a81"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-mayye ṣārat al-ʕadas vērm-u yṣīr zēn yaʕṭi ta-ngūl ad-dönem hemen hemen iṯnaʕaš dönem ʔiḥna hēne nsammī-´, nsammī-´ čēl – čēl – al-gāʕ ngūl-lhe iṯnaʕaš dönüm nsammī-´ čēl, ač-čēl yaʕṭi al tizraʕ-u ta-ngūl čēl</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a92"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕadas ač-čēl al-ʕadas mītēn kīlōw, al-mītēn kīlōw yiǧi xams ᵊṭwān ʕadas. al-xams ᵊṭwān, al-kīlōw yiǧi xamsa w-ʕišrīn kīlo, al-vērim maḥṣūl. yōm-in yiǧi xamsa w-ʕišrīn kīlōw kwayyis yaʕni zēn hemen hemen yiǧi la-l-xams ᵊṭwān arbaʕ ᵊṭwān xams ᵊṭwān yiǧi l-ʕadas. ʔač-čēl, ʔiṯnaʕaš dönüm</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a101"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts20" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʔiḥna hēne ʕa-l-guwāʕi, ᵊtgūl [dgūl]“ʔašgadd ʕind-ak gāʕ?” ᵊtgūl “ʕind-i ʕašər tičāl ʕašǝr čēlāt.” al-ʕašǝr čēl miyye w-ʕišrīn dönem, miyye, ad-dönem iṯnaʕaš dönem čēl nsammī-´ b-al-ʕarab, čēl ᵊngūl. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a108"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts22" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>čēl gāʕ, čēl ḥunṭa, al-ḥunṭa čēl-he, miyye w-arbaʕa w-ṯimānīn kīlōw b-al… b-ad-dibābi, ad… dabbītha aṯ-ṯimantaʕaš lītər, ʔiṯnaʕaš dabbīt ḥunṭa li-ṯumm-ha nčīl-he nsammī-he čēl. – ʔā, fhimt-ak.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a117"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʔiṯnaʕaš dabbīt ḥunṭa nsammī-he čēl. ᵊtgul-lu “čam čēl ǧann-ak?” ygūl “ miyye čēl, ǧā-ni ḥunta.” ʔal- miyye čēl yisāwi b-al-ḥisāb il-matematīk ṯimanṭaʕaš ṭōn w-arbaʕmīt kīlow. al-miyye čēl ṯimanṭaʕaš [ʔalif] w-arbaʕmīt kīlow, yšīl-he b-al-qamyūn yāxuḏ-ha ʕa-l-midīne, ʔal-ḥunṭa ybīʕūn-he, al-ʕadas, al-ʕadas čēl-u mītēn kīlow, </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a128"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts29">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʔal-ḥunṭa čēl-he miyye w-arbaʕa w-ṯimānīn kīlow, w-aš-šiʕīr čēl-u miyye w-iṯnēna w-xamsīn kīlow, ʔaš-šiʕīr xafīf, ʔaš-šiʕīr xafīf čēl-u ṯnaʕaš dabbiyye, čēl-u miyye w-iṯnēn w-xamsīn kīlow, w-al-ʕadas ʕamann-u ṯiǧīl, čēl-u mītēn kīlow. al-ḥunṭa miyye w-arbaʕa w ṯimānīn kīlow, čēl-he. ᵊftahamit ʕalayy-e zēn? zēn? šnōn ᵊkwayyis?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a139"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts28" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa ʔiḥna nsammī-´ ngul-lu šōk. – šōk? – ʔī šōk, hāḏa yiṭlaʕ yabanǧi madde, hāḏa yiṭuššūn ilāč, al-ilāč mā yiktil-u, ᵊbgaḷb al-ʕadas mā yiṣīr, zihīd, yunṭūn-u ilāč, fazla hēna ʔal-ilāč ʕaman mā yruššūn, yuṭluʕ ba-l-kenār. ʔamma b-al-ᵊhnāk mā yiṣīr fazla. – mā yiṣīr – ʔī. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a169"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts31" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʔī yiǧi yṣīr ba-l-kenār. hāḏa, hāḏa, hāḏa ʕušub ngul-lu ʔiḥne, ʕušub, hāḏa ʔiḥna nsammī-´ šōk, hāḏa ʔaš-šōk hāḏa hnīt-u hāḏi baʕdēn ᵊtṣīr ᵊbgaḷb-u mā-dri šakle, bī-hum awwali yāklūn-he zād, amma ʔiḥna mā-nākul-he, – yāklūn-hē? – yāklūn gaḷb-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a155"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gaḷǝb hāḏe  šwayy yiṣīr guṭma hīčiḏ ḥāmḏ̣e ḥilwa  yāklūn-he, ˀiḥna mā-nākul-he halḥīn yṣīr ṭaraf al-ˁadas  ᵊb-gaḷb al-ˁadas fazla mā yṣīr ˁaman yiṭuššūn ilāč ysawwūn ilačlama  yabanǧi madde mā yṣīr.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a166" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>These are lentils; they seed them in December, or in November. They remain five months like this, four, five months, six months. Then they start to harvest them with reapers. When they are dry. Fifteen days after they have dried, they harvest them with reapers, and they put the straw aside.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a167" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The straw and the lentils are seperated. Their owners take them and sell them at the corn-exchange, at the corn-exchange. They sell them for about… the lentils, we call this (kind) green lentils, they sell them for one Lira per kilo, one Lira for one kilo lentils.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a168" ANNOTATION_REF="a25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The straw is sold for hundred Kuruş, (no) ten Kuruş – ten Kuruş – ten Kuruş which means ten kilos for one Lira, the straw. As for the lentils they take them to factories where they break them into two pieces. Then one kilo costs one million [= one Lira]; they take remove the hull, the remove the hull and then one kilo costs two million.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
