<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-01-08T19:42:34+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-012_Lentils-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:b5cd475c-e71a-43c7-9eca-dfeefaeac03d</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">183</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="4220"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="24507"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="24511"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="42596"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="42596"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="62895"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="62895"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="84934"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="84934"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="104356"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="104363"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="119774"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="119788"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="135999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="135999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="149366"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="149375"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="171431"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="171440"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="194852"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="194852"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="210540"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="210540"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="228567"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="228568"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="251934"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="251944"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="278302"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="278302"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="296000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="296013"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="312830"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="312830"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="328100"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa al-ʕadas, yizraʕūn-u onikinǧi ay, onbirinǧi ay, xamǝs tušhur yḏ̣all hīčiḏ, arbaʕ tušhur, xamǝs tušhur, sitt tušhur. baʕdēn yiǧūn yiḥaṣṣdūn-u b-al-mōṭōrāt, yōm-inn-u yības, ʕugub xamǝsṭaʕǝš yōm hīčiḏ, baʕad-ma yības b-al-mōṭōrāt yiḥaṣṣdūn-u, yuṭluʕūn at-tibin ʕayrǝ</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>tibn-u w-al-ʕadas ʕayrǝ, w-al-ʕadas ʕād yāxḏūn-u ahal-u ybīʕūn-u b-al-ʕarṣa, b-al-ʕarṣa yibīʕūn-u, al-ʕadas taqrīb-an, al-ʕadas al… hāḏa al-xaḏ̣ar ᵊngul-l-u, yeşil mercimek, ybīʕūn kīlaw-u waraqa, b-wruga, al-kīlo, al-ʕadas. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-at-tibin ybīʕūn-u imyit ǧiriš, ʕašər ᵊgrūš – ʕašr ᵊgrūš – ʕašr ᵊgrūš yaʕni al-ʕašǝr kīlawāt ᵊb-waraqa, at-tibin, w-al-ʕadas, baʕdēn-ma yāxḏūn-u ʕa-l-fabrikāt tkassr-u ysāwūn-u qišimtēn, yṣīr kīlaw-u malyūnēn, gišr-u yiṭlǝʕūn-u yiṭlǝʕūn gišr-u yṣīr al-kīlu malyūnēn</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a37"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>b-al-markēt, b-as-sūpermarkēt, b-al-baqqāl yibīʕūn-u wrugtēn w-nuṣṣ, waraqtēn w-nuṣṣ yaʕni waraqtēn zād ybīʕūn-u. taġrīban bir yūrow yaʕni yūrow avrūpa. ʕa-l-bēt iḥna nrūḥ nāxuḏ xamǝs kīlawāt, yāzī-na šahrēn ṯalāṯ. al-… an-nuṣṣ kīlo, rubuʕ kīlu ysāwi ʕēš lin-ne, nuṣṣ kīlo ysāwī-na ʕēš šōraba.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a51"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts8" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-hāḏi l-gāʕ? – al-gāʕ hāḏi siǧīy. hāḏi siǧīy. ī, hāḏa l-ʕadas hāḏa siǧīy, maʕṭīn-u mayye, yēlōn mū siǧīy mā yṣīr, al-ʕiḏīy mā yṣīr hēne. čünkü al-ʕiḏīy yibas, mā ṣār mǝṭar yibas, min hāḏa ysawwūn-u siǧīy. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a61"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā ššūf al-buwāri haḏanne yǧībūn-hin ysāwūn siǧīy yisǧūn bī-hin al-ʕadas. al-mayye… b-al-buwāri haḏanne yisḥabūn mayye, w-yisǧūn al-ʕadas, w-al-mayye hāḏi mayyt al-barāǧ hāḏi mayyit al-barāǧ hāḏi – hāḏi mayyt al-barāǧ– hāḏi mayyit al-barāč.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a67"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>tiǧi hēne yōm-in al-barāč ydaššrūn al-mayye yḥuṭṭūn ṣīfōn ᵊbgaḷǝb-ha, buwāri, ṣīfōn, halḥīn mayye māmiš, magṭūʕa, hāḏi timtali mayye yḥuṭṭūn al-būri, aṣ-ṣīfōn hēne yḥuṭṭūn, w-min hēne tgūm ᵊtkubb yisǧūn al-ʕadas bī-´.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a75"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts14" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yinṭūn-u mayye yōm-innu yaʕṭaš, yisgūn-u mayye, al-mayye taġrīban ʕal-ʕadas marra wəḥde mayye šahar ᵊtkaffīy, tāzīy. baʕd aš-šahar uxṛa yisḥabūn yaʕṭūn-u mayye ta-mā yibas </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a81"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-mayye ṣārat al-ʕadas vērm-u yṣīr zēn yaʕṭi ta-ngūl ad-dönem hemen hemen iṯnaʕaš dönem iḥna hēne nsammī-´, nsammī-´ čēl – čēl – al-gāʕ ngūl-lhe iṯnaʕaš dönüm nsammī-´ čēl, ač-čēl yaʕṭi al tizraʕ ta-ngūl čēl </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a92"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕadas ač-čēl al-ʕadas mītēn kīlow, al-mītēn kīlow yiǧi xams ᵊṭwān ʕadas. al-xams ᵊṭwān, al-kīlow yiǧi xamsa w-ʕišrīn kīlow, al-vērim maḥṣūl. yōm-in yiǧi xamsa w-ʕišrīn kīlow kwayyis yaʕni zēn hemen hemen yiǧi la-l-xams ᵊṭwān arbaʕ ᵊṭwān xams ᵊṭwān yiǧi ʕadas. ač-čēl, iṯnaʕaš dönüm</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a101"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts20" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>iḥna hēne ʕa-l-guwāʕi, ᵊtgūl [dgūl]“ašgadd ʕind-ak gāʕ?” ᵊtgūl “ʕind-i ʕašər tičāl ʕašǝr čēlāt.” al-ʕašǝr čēl miyye w-ʕišrīn dönem, miyye, ad-dönem iṯnaʕaš dönem čēl nsammī-´ b-al-ʕarab, čēl ᵊngūl.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a108"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts22" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>čēl gāʕ, čēl ḥunṭa, al-ḥunṭa čēl-he, miyye w-arbaʕa w-ṯimānīn kīlow b-al… b-ad-dibābi, ad… dabbītha aṯ-ṯimantaʕaš lītər, iṯnaʕaš dabbīt ḥunṭa li-ṯumm-ha nčīl-he nsammī-he čēl. – ā, fhimt-ak.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a117"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>iṯnaʕaš dabbīt ḥunṭa nsammī-he čēl. ᵊtgul-lu “čam čēl ǧann-ak?” ygūl “ miyye čēl, ǧā-ni ḥunta.” al- miyye čēl yisāwi b-al-ḥisāb il-matematīk ṯimanṭaʕaš ṭōn w-arbaʕmīt kīlow. al-miyye čēl ṯimanṭaʕaš [alif] w-arbaʕmīt kīlow, yšīl-he b-al-qamyūn yāxuḏ-ha ʕa-l-midīne, al-ḥunṭa ybīʕūn-he, al-ʕadas, al-ʕadas čēl-u mītēn kīlow, </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a128"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts29">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-ḥunṭa čēl-he miyye w-arbaʕa w-ṯimānīn kīlow, w-aš-šiʕīr čēl-u miyye w-iṯnēn w-xamsīn kīlow, aš-šiʕīr xafīf, aš-šiʕīr xafīf čēl-u ṯnaʕaš dabbiyye, čēl-u miyye w-iṯnēn w-xamsīn kīlow, w-al-ʕadas ʕamann-u ṯiǧīl, čēl-u mītēn kīlow. al-ḥunṭa miyye w-arbaʕa w ṯimānīn kīlow, čēl-he. ᵊftahamit ʕalay-ye zēn? zēn? šnōn ᵊkwayyis?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a139"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts28" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa iḥna nsammī-´ ngul-lu šōk. – šōk? – ī šōk, hāḏa yiṭlaʕ yabanǧi madde, hāḏa yiṭuššūn ilāč, al-ilāč mā yiktil-u, ᵊbgaḷb al-ʕadas mā yiṣīr, zihīd, yunṭūn-u ilāč, fazla hēna al-ilāč ʕaman mā yruššūn, yuṭluʕ ba-l-kenār. amma b-al-ᵊhnāk mā yiṣīr fazla. – mā yiṣīr – ī. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a169"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts31" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ī yiǧi yṣīr ba-l-kenār. hāḏa, hāḏa, hāḏa ʕušub ngul-lu iḥne, ʕušub, hāḏa iḥna nsammī-´ šōk, hāḏa aš-šōk hāḏa hnīt-u hāḏi baʕdēn ᵊtṣīr ᵊbgaḷb-u mā-dri šakle, bī-hum awwali yāklūn-he zād, amma iḥna mā-nākul-he, – yāklūn-hē? – yāklūn gaḷb-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a155"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gaḷǝb hāḏe šwayy yiṣīr guṭma hīčiḏ ḥāmḏ̣e ḥilwa yāklūn-he, iḥna mā nākul-he halḥīn. yṣīr ᵊb-ṭarf al-ʕadas ᵊbgaḷb al-ʕadas fazla mā yṣīr ʕaman yiṭuššūn ilāč, ysāwūn ilačlama yabanǧi madde mā yṣīr.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a166" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>These are lentils; they seed them in December, or in November. They remain five months like this, four, five months, six months. Then they start to harvest them with reapers. When they are dry. Fifteen days after they have dried, they harvest them with reapers, and they put the straw aside.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a167" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The straw and the lentils are seperated. Their owners take them and sell them at the corn-exchange, at the corn-exchange. They sell them for about… the lentils, we call this (kind) green lentils, they sell them for one Lira per kilo, one Lira for one kilo lentils.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a168" ANNOTATION_REF="a25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The straw is sold for hundred Kuruş, (no) ten Kuruş – ten Kuruş – ten Kuruş which means ten kilos for one Lira, the straw. As for the lentils they take them to factories where they break them into two pieces. Then one kilo costs one million [= one Lira]; they take remove the hull, the remove the hull and then one kilo costs two million.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a170" ANNOTATION_REF="a37">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>In the market, in the supermarket or in the grocery store they sell it for two and a half Lira, two and a half Lira which means for two Liras more. This corresponds roughly to one Euro, one Euro. We usually take five kilos home which is enough for two or three months. One half or a quarter of a kilo makes a meal for us. Half a kilo is good for a (lentil) soup.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a171" ANNOTATION_REF="a51">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And this field? – This field is an irrigated field. It’s an irrigated field. These lentils are being irrigated; they have put water on them. If they are not irrigated, they do not grow. Non-irrigated fields are not possible here, because they get too dry. If there’s no rain they dry. Because of this they make irrigation to the fields.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a172" ANNOTATION_REF="a61">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Don’t you see the pipes over there? They bring them to make irrigated fields, to irrigate the lentils with them. The water… These pipes provide water  and then they irrigate the lentils. This water is from the reservoir, water from the reservoir – this is water from the reservoir.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a173" ANNOTATION_REF="a67">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>It comes here when they let it (flow from the reservoir) and they install a syphon inside the pipes. Now there is no water, it’s shut off. This is filled with water, they put the pipe here and the syphon there and from here the water starts to flow out and so they irrigate the lentils with it. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a174" ANNOTATION_REF="a75">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They give water to them; when they need it  they water them. As for the lentils it is enough to irrigate them approximately once a month, that’s enough. Then, a month later, they will again water them in order that they do not dry. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a175" ANNOTATION_REF="a81">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>With the water the yield of the lentils gets good, let’s say for 1000 sqm about… 12,000 sqm is an area, we call here čēl. The field which has an expanse of 12,000 sqm is called čēl. This čēl provides – when you sow it –let’s say a čēl, a čēl of lentils</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a176" ANNOTATION_REF="a92">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Two hundred kilos of lentil seeds, two hundred kilos yield five tons, five tons. This means, one kilo becomes 25 kilos of harvest. When one kilo brings in 25 kilos then it is a good yield, then (one čēl) brings in four to five tons, five tons of lentils. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a177" ANNOTATION_REF="a101">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The čēl is 12,000 sqm. Here, with regard to the fields you say, “How large is your field?” and you say, “I have ten čēl, ten čēl.” Ten čēl are twelve hectares as 12,000 sqm are one čēl as we call it in Arabic.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a178" ANNOTATION_REF="a108">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>A čēl of land, a čēl of wheat (is different) ; one čēl corresponds to 184 kilos, measured in cans. One can has 18 litres. Twelve cans of wheat full to the brim we call one čēl – I understand you.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a179" ANNOTATION_REF="a117">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Twelve cans of wheat are called čēl. You say, “How many čēl have you got?”  And the answer will be, “Hundred čēl, I’ve got hundred čēl.” According to mathematics these hundred čēl make eighteen tons and 400 kilos. Hundred čēl are 18,400 kilos. He measures them on a truck and then brings it to Urfa where they sell the wheat; as for the lentils, one čēl of lentils is 200 kilos. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a180" ANNOTATION_REF="a128">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>As for the wheat, one čēl is 184 kilos, one čēl of barley is only 152 kilos, because barley is light, barley is light, one čēl is twelve cans and 152 kilos. Since the lentils are heavy, one čēl is 200 kilos, and the wheat 184 kilos. You understand me, right? Good? How is it? Good?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a181" ANNOTATION_REF="a139">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>This (plant) we call it thistle. – Thistle? – Yes, thistle. It grows as weed, (therefore) they spray herbicid, but the herbicide agent does not kill it. Inside of the lentil (fields), they don’t grow, only a few, (because) they spray herbicide agents on it. There are more here, because they do not spray herbicide agents, so they grow more on the edges. But there it does not grow that much now. – Not much. – Yes.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a182" ANNOTATION_REF="a169">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Yes, it grows on the edges. This, we say to it weed, we call it weed, weed. This, we call it thistle.  This thistle, there is its thing; then something grows inside of it, I do not know (its) form; there were people who (used to) eat it also. But we do not eat it. – They used to eat it? – They used to eat its interior.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a183" ANNOTATION_REF="a155">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Its interior gets a little bit like this, it is sour or sweet, and so they eat it. We do not eat it now. It grows on the edges of the lentil fields, not so much inside of them because they spray herbicide agent; they spray herbicide agent and therefore weeds do not come up.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
