<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2022-08-24T16:40:07+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-092_Sultan_Murad-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:14ffdc72-a5cc-4739-bbbe-f63805da5c0f</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">164</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="4880"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="22040"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="22050"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="41090"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="41090"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="62190"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="62205"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="84660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="84670"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="98770"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="98770"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="113920"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="113930"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="125380"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="125390"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="141750"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="141760"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="156610"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="156620"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="173630"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="173640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="193960"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="193970"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="208380"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="208390"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="226020"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="226030"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="246450"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="246460"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="259660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="259660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="280150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="280150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="300270"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="300280"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="310910"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="310920"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="325860"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts39" TIME_VALUE="325860"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts40" TIME_VALUE="342420"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts41" TIME_VALUE="342420"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts42" TIME_VALUE="360130"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts43" TIME_VALUE="360130"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts44" TIME_VALUE="377430"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts45" TIME_VALUE="377430"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts46" TIME_VALUE="390830"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts47" TIME_VALUE="390840"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts48" TIME_VALUE="409870"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts49" TIME_VALUE="409870"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts50" TIME_VALUE="419800"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts51" TIME_VALUE="419810"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts52" TIME_VALUE="442410"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts53" TIME_VALUE="442420"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts54" TIME_VALUE="453020"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts55" TIME_VALUE="453020"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts56" TIME_VALUE="471540"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts57" TIME_VALUE="471540"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts58" TIME_VALUE="488140"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts59" TIME_VALUE="488150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts60" TIME_VALUE="502950"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts61" TIME_VALUE="502960"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts62" TIME_VALUE="512140"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts63" TIME_VALUE="512140"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts64" TIME_VALUE="540427"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>as-sulṭān Murād b-zimānāt ˁala dōr al-ˁuṯmāniyye huwwa ḥākim zād belli bi… zamān  ᵊmsawwi qǝrāliyye bāše yaˁni ˁa-l-ˁuṯmāniyye.  huwwa durum, ḍurm-u ṣāyir guṭma ḏ̣æˁīf, ḏ̣aˁfān</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ḏ̣aˁfān ḍurm-u dawilt-u yaˁni min ṭaraf al-ˁaǧ… ˁaskarīt-u min ṭaraf silāḥ-u w-min ṭaraf šækl-ə ḏ̣aˁfān, yaˁni  ˁind-u xāynīn ṣāyrīn wuzārat-u wazīrīt-u wzārt-u ar-rūs, ᵊčār ar-rūs ar-rūs čāre gāyil-lu mdizz-il-lu xabar</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil-lu yā… də rūḥu gūlū-lu, mdarrb-il-lu ēlčiyye gāyil æææ…  “arīd minn-u ḥarib, sawaš, ḥarib arīd minn-u ḥarib  ta-ntiḥārab ,” w-gāyil, “tamām!”  Sulṭān Murād gāyil mesela masale ˁugub hafte ta-yḥaḏ̣ḏ̣ir ˁaskar-u  ta-niǧi ntiḥārab ˁa-l-ᵊḥdūd.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sulṭān Murād qāft-u mašġūḷa ǧaˁ- ydawwir b-al-ᵊhnīye ᵊhniyye ǧāy ᵊmxalli  as-sarāy ᵊmxalli kullši ṭāliˁ ˁa aǧ-ǧbile w ǧaˁ-ydawwir hīčiḏ  miṯl al-maǧnūn, miṯl al-mhabūl ydawwir b-aǧ-ǧbile hināk mitxaṭṭm-u rāˁi. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a20"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in šāyif ar-rāˁi, ar-rāˁi mā yˁarf-u ˀinn-u Murād. mā yˁarif inn-u l-qǝrāl. gāyil-lu “š-bī-k yāba? ǧūˁān? taˁāl āni ˁind-i xāṯir w ḥalīb w…  w ǧubun, xubuz, taˁāl w-ukul yā šāyib yā ˁammuy! ukul! ˀāni daḥḥiǧ ˁind-i xāṯir w xubuz, taˁāl! tifaḏ̣ḏ̣al ukul!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts10" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ar-rāˁi faqīr yaˁni dīwāne. mənṭī gāyim yiṭˁam-u xāṯir w ǧubun w ḥalīb w mišbiˁ-u w gāyil-lu: “[čælēt xāṯir w ᵊhni] inčād ᵊtrīd xāṯir zād anṭīk saṭəl.” gāyil axu abū-y]  ˀiš-lī bī?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a27"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mənṭī zād saṭǝl xāṯir gel gāyil hāḏa uxḏ-u li-bētak lᵊ-bēt-ak hadīye hadiyye. balči inte faqīr ašūf-ak b-ᵊhniyye b-qāft-ak čiṯīr mašġūḷa as-sulṭān māxḏ-u w-gāyil as-sulṭān zād gāyil “bāčir āni uxra arīd, bēt-ak aṣṣōbu?” gāyil “bēt-i b-al-balad hēne,” ta-ngūl</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a30"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāl “bēt-ak aṣṣōb-u?” gāyil “bēt-i b-al-midīne.” gāyil “ē,” gāyil “bāčir āni arīd aǧi ˁa-l-balad,” ar-rāˁi “bāčir āni aǧi ˁa-l-balad w ˀinčād ᵊtgūl ta-d-aǧīb-lak zād saṭəl xāṯir, aṣṣōb bēt-ak? bēt-ak aṣṣōb-u?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a34"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>waḷḷa gāyil “bēt-i āni mā tindall bēt-i bass tiǧi ˁa-l-ᵊhniyye ˁal.. – ta-ngūl – ˁa-s-sarāy āni ˀaštaġil b-as-sarāy qādi šāġūl mū mˁallim ˁala ḥāl-u, “bass ᵊtgūl min-u?” gāyil “ismak šinu?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a38"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil “ˀin saˁalit ᵊtgūl Murād ač-čibīr humma kull ḥade yaˁrif-ni qādi, ydallūn-ak ˁalayye bēt Murād ač-čibīr,” gāyil l-ar-rāˁi.  “tamām,” gāl ar-rāˁi.” waḷḷa ar-rāˁi rāyiḥ w-ǧāy ˁala s-sulṭān Murād ᵊmḥawwil ˁala bēt-u ǧāy,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a42"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE> ṯāni ᵊnhār ar-rāˁi   ᵊmsāwi saṭǝl xāṯir w-yḥuṭṭ-u b-īd-u  w gāyil “arīd arūḥ āxuḏ l-aš-šāyib haḏāk al-faqīr ᵊb-xēr-i ta-nṭ-i saṭǝl xāṯir yōm-inn-u minkatt ˁa-s-sūg ǧāy ˁa-l-balad yisˁal b-al-ˁaskar ǧāy ˁa-l-bāb ˁa…  ta-ngūl awwali š-isim-he, as-sūr</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a48"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yrīd yxušš min-as-sūr ǧawwa mā-yxallūn-u gāyil “walu!  hāḏa hēne wāḥad yištaġil  ˁid-kum ism-u Murād ač-čibīr, w āni ǧibt-il-lu saṭəl xāṯir.” “wal” gāylīn “yā xayyo hēne mā-miš Murād ač-čibīr, inte yaġnīš!  ˀiḥne mā ˁid-na Murād ač-čibīr, ˁid-na wāḥad sulṭān Murād.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a52"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“w as-sulṭān šinu šuġ… inte ǧāyb-il-lu l-s-sulṭān saṭǝl xāṯir, turūḥ ǧawwa yiḏbaḥ-ak.”  “wal” gāyil “yā ǧimāˁa ˀāni mā-li šuġul ˁid sulṭān Murād ˀāni ˀarīd Murād ač-čibīr, asˁal ˁin Murād ač-čibīr, Murād hāḏa min fōg hīčiḏ, mā-dri šnōn, lāyḥ-u, šāyf-u al-Murād</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a56"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>as-sulṭān Murād šāyif ar-rāˁi w gāyil “ xaḷḷ-u hōbhōb ṣīḥū-lu hāḏa xaḷḷ-u yiǧi ǧawwa!  iftaḥū-lu, fukkū-lu al-bāb! fukkū-lu al-bāb xaḷḷ yǧīn-i ǧawwa. fākkī-lu al-bāb “wal” gāyil “wal inte mā tˁallimn-I ya wal, ṯārīy-ak inte s-sulṭān.  ᵊtgūl āni Murād ač-čibīr, demak tiḏ̣ḥak ˁala-yye ˁalē-ma ˁallamit-ni?” ar-rāˁi ygūl ˁal-Murād ˁa-l-pādišāh.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a61"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts29" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ǧāy xāšš ǧawwa  “abū wal” gāyil “ˀinte ḥarām ˁind-ak xadādīm w ˁind-ak zulum mā tˁallim-ni wal albāriḥ āni ˀagūl aš-šāyib al-faġīr hāḏa ˁaǧal mn-aǧ-ǧbile ataltil ᵊb-saṭl al-xāṯir w-inte hēne kullši ˁind-ak mā tgūl-li?” </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a65"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts30" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts33">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil “waḷḷa, yā xayyo, hīčiḏ āni gilt ašūf  al-mille yōm-in-ha agūl-lhe kull-he tgūm ᵊtgallǧ-illi, ssawwī-li yisāwī-li yaˁni ˀäääää æææ,  yiḥibbū-ni ˁaman-ni qrāl.  inte ḥabbēt-ni ˁaman-ni fəqīr ǧibt-il-li saṭǝl xāṯir.” gāyil “ugˁud ugˁud ta-nšūf ta-ntiharraǧ āni w-inte,” as-sulṭān ygūl l-ar-rāˁi.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a70"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts32" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“gūl! yā xayyo iš-bīk?” gāl “yā yā xūye humma ǧimīˁ ǧāˁdīn waḥad-hum” gāyil “ˀāni xulg-i ḏ̣ayyiǧ  w ṭǝlaˁit ǧīt ˁa-ǧ-ǧbile, ar-rūs dawlit ar-rūs w fakkat ˁala-yye ᵊtrīd minn-i ḥarəb w-āni mā ǧaˁad atigāwan ᵊb-ˁaskar-i wālīt-i qāymaqāmīt-i, ta-ngūl ḏīč as-sāˁa ši-ˀagūl-il-hum?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a75"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā ǧāˁad atigēwan bī-hum ta-ḥārb ar-rūs axāf ar-rūs yqallib-ne yuqlub-ni, mā ǧaˁad atigēwan ᵊb-millt-i.” gāyl-lu: “ˁalē mā ttigēwan?” gāyil “waḷḷa ya ḥa… mā ndall mā ǧaˁad atigēwan.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a77"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts37" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts39">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil “ˀinte ˁaǧal ᵊmhabūl  ˁaǧal? m-ǝnte qrāl ˁalē-hum? mā ssāwī-hum mā tṭawwaḥ-ḥum  mā tdazgin-hum.”  “šnōn asāwī-hum”  hāḏa iḏ̣-ni msāˁde hafte zimān, āni adazgin-he. ˀadazgin ˁaskar-ak.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a81"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts38" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts41">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“tsss” gāyil “xayyo dazgin! ˁind-inn-ak inte tdazgin-he tā-rīd ašūf ᵊšnōn ᵊtdazgin-he.” gāyil “awwal bādye ˀinte ˁaskar-ak tinṭī-ni hafte š-mā sāwi mā ḥad, mā ttiqāraš  ᵊb-šuġl-i!” gāyil “iš-mā tsāwi inte særbæst!” gāyil l-ar-rāˁi.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a85"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts40" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts42">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ar-rāˁi gāḏ̣ib awwal mu… lāmm gāyil  “čam wilāye šī ˁa-l-uṯmāniyye?” ta-ngūl ᵊmˀit /ᵊmīt wilāye ᵊmīt wilāye, al-wilāyāt hāḏi mdarrib ˁalē-hum xabar li ṣār lissa hafte šī  ˁala ˁad ˁa r-rūs mdarrib ˁalē-hum xabar gāyil kull-kum bāčir baˁad bāčir ti-tiltammūn tiǧūn hēne b-as-sarāy, aḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur hēne arīd-kum. ˁugub ṯaliṯ ṯalaṯ ttīyām.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a89"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts43" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts45">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mdarrib ˁalē-hum ṭurrāše yaˁni ṭurrāše xabarǧi  xabarǧi kull-hum ṣāyiḥ-il-hum b-al… lāmm-hum b-al-ḥōš yōm-in  lāmm-hum gāyil kull awwali yilbasūn zibnāt ˁabāt ta-ngūl  kallīge dišdāše</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a93"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts44" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts46">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyil aḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur “daḥḥǧu!” lāmm al-ˁaskar ḥōl-ma ḥawālē-hum gāyil “daḥḥǧu! š-ma_gūl āni ti-ssawwūn?” gāylīn  īeh!” ygūl “tek tek” gāyl-li-lhum “šīlu ˁabāt-kum lē-fōg!” sarāwīl mū lābsīn “šīlu ˁabāt-kum ta-rīd adaḥḥič Aslām alli min Nuṣāra.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a96"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts47" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts49">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yaˁni bī-hum xāynīn huwwe yrīd huwwe… dawle islāmiyye al-ˁuṯmāniyye ˁalēš wgaˁat?  gāyil “šīlu!” ydaḥḥič “hāḏa ᵊmṭahhar hāḏa ygūl ṣaġlam uṭluˁ min hēne! hāḏa mū ᵊmṭahhar, hāḏa” ygūl “guṭṭu kallt-u! awwal bādye ᵊmṣaffi al-wāliyye al-qāymaqāmīye ḥəkkām-u</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a101"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts48" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts50">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ᵊmṣaffi al-miṭṭahhrīn w-al mū miṭṭahhrīn gāyil ta-ngūl ḏ̣āllīn ˁašra xamǝsṭaˁš miṭṭahhrīn ˁišrīn w-ṯimānīn mū miṭṭahhrīn demek ki kull-ha xāyne b-dawəlt-u mū m-Islām ᵊmsawwīhum wāli qaymaqām ḥākim.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a104"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts51" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts52">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>as-sulṭān Murād ydaḥḥiǧ ˁalē min ġādi yā wal gāyil šūf ar-rāˁi l-ǝmhabūl qāftu tištaġil axēr minn-i qāft ar-rāˁi tištaġil axēr minn-i āni yaˁni zād demek bōš ṣāyir pāše ṣāyir padišāh. ˁugub-mu ᵊmṣaffī-hum gāyil arīd-kum kull min ˁaskar-kum  ᵊtḥaḏ̣ḏ̣rūn ˁaskar-kum kāmil w tiǧūn ˁugub hafte ar-rūs ᵊnrīd ᵊnḥārb-u</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a109"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts53" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts55">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in lāmm ˁaskar-u w ˁaskar-u kull-hum ǧāyīn ṣaġlam. ˁaskar-hum haḏōle, intu haḏōle ḏabbaḥ-hum yōm-in ǧāyib-hum yirīd yḥārb ᵊr-rūs, al-xabar rāyiḥ ˁala Rūsye.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a111"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts54" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts57">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>wāḥad ǧāsūs min-hum minhazim, rāyiḥ ˁa-r-rūs gāyil “yā xayyo as-sulṭān Murād lāgī-lu wazīr-in ˁāǧil čiṯīr ˁāǧil  w ǧuwāsīs-ne kull-ha ḏabaḥ-ḥa, w lā tkārbū-luwwat w tarāh-u yqallib-kum  tarā yqallb-ak” ar-rūs “šnōn” gāylīn, gāl “kull ǧuwāsīs-ne guṭaˁ klāl-hum.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a115"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts56" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts58">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-wazīr aǧ-ǧidīd w al ˁind-u saġlam ˁaskar-in ṣaġlam, ha-n-nōba tara yqallbūn-ak lā tḥārb-u!  āni agul-lak lā tḥārb-u!” ar-rūs ˁād gāḏ̣ib ta-ydarrib xabar uxra ˁala Sulṭān Murāḍ gāyil “xayyo āni mā-ˁād aḥārb-ak as-sawaš mā ˁād arīd-u. sawa... al-ḥarb mā arīd minn-ak, baṭṭalit ˁin al-ḥarb.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a118"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts59" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts60">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-wāǧif yōm-in ǧāy aṭ-ṭāriš almara as-sulṭān Murād  gāyil “ᵊšnōn mā ǧāk al-xabar?” ar-rāˁi ygūl l-s-sulṭān Murād “mā ǧāk al-xabar?”  gāyil “šinu min xabar?” gāyil “mā ǧāk al-xabar mā yḥārbūn-ak __[də]____ axabar l-ak.” gāyil “ᵊšnōn?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a121"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts61" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts63">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāl āni ˁārif iḥna al-ˁaskariyye al-ordi hāḏi maḥḥad yiqlab-he b-ad-dinye. alḥaz yiǧī-k ṭāriš” w-ṣaḥīḥ ǧāy-u gāyil “mā yḥārbūn-ak gǝḏ̣at, w-salāmt-ak w-al-ˁāfiye.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a123"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts62" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts64">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ˁugub-min qādi ˁād ha-n-nōb sulṭān Murād gāyl-il-lu  gāyil la-r-rāˁi gāyil “xayyo mā ḏ̣all ˁind-i yaˁni wuzart-in mhabale [wazīrt-i mhabbil] mahbūl ḏ̣all ˁind-i ṣṣīr wazīr!” gāyil “abū-ye āni, āni šuġl-i āni rāˁi  kull-min yisāwi šuġl-u maḥ… āni šuġl-i rāˁi  arūḥ ˁala qnim-i w-inte zād šuġl-ak sulṭān ilg-il-lak wazīr-in zēn ha-n-nōba wāḥad-in ˁāǧil w-sāw dawilt-ak idāra! ᵊmsallim ˁalē-k w-ad-arūḥ.”  w-salāmt-ak w-al-ˁāfiye!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a131" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sultan Murad was, in his time, in the era of the Ottomans, a ruler. It’s known that he was a king, a pasha for the Ottomans. But his situation was a little bit weak and fragile.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a132" ANNOTATION_REF="a5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>His situation and his country were weak. Weak with regard to his soldiers, with regard to his weapons, and with regard to his inner state. That means, his ministers have become treacherous. The Russians, the Tsar of the Russians, has sent him a message,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a133" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>telling him… “Go and tell him!”—He had sent to him messangers—“I want war with you, fighting, I want war with you, let’s fight!” Sultan Murad said, “Agreed! After one week—to prepare his soldiers—let’s fight at the border!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a134" ANNOTATION_REF="a15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sultan Murad’s mind was very busy. He was looking for something, he left his palace, he left everything and went up to a mountain seeking for something like crazy, like a madman. There, a shepherd met him.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a135" ANNOTATION_REF="a20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When the shepherd saw him, he didn’t know that he was (Sultan) Murad. He did not know that he was the king. He said, “What’s wrong with you, daddy? Are you hungry? Come! I have yoghurt, milk, and cheese, and bread. Come and eat, old man, my uncle! Eat! Look, I have yoghurt and bread! Come, help yourself, eat!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a136" ANNOTATION_REF="a23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The shepherd was naïve and indigent. He gave him yoghurt, cheese and milk to eat and thus filled him. Then he said, “ You have eaten yoghurt and if you want more yoghurt I’ll give you a whole bucket.” He said, “My brother, my father what I’m doing with all that?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a137" ANNOTATION_REF="a27">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He gave him a bucket full of yoghurt and said, “Take this home as a present! Maybe you are poor and I see that your mind is very much occupied with something.” The sultan took it and then (the shepherd) said, “Tomorrow I will (bring you) more, where is your house?” He said, “My house is in the town.” Let’s say.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a138" ANNOTATION_REF="a30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “Where is your house?” He said, “My house is in the town.” He said, “Okay, tomorrow I will come to town.” The shepherd said, “Tomorrow I will come to town and if you agree, I will bring you another bucket of yoghurt. Where’s your house?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a139" ANNOTATION_REF="a34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“My house,” he said, “You don’t know my house, just come to the whatsit, to the palace. I work in the palace, I am a worker there.” He did not reveal himself. (The shepherd) said, “Just say who… what is your name?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a140" ANNOTATION_REF="a38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said to the shepherd, “When you are asked, say Murad the elder, they all know me there and will show you the wey to me, to the house of Murad the elder.” The shepherd said, “Agreed!” and (the next day) he went to Sultan Murad, he went down to his house there.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a141" ANNOTATION_REF="a42">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The next day he prepared a bucket of yoghurt, took it in his hand and said, “I want to go and take it to this old, poor man. Do a good deed and let’s give him a bucket of yoghurt!” When he came down to the market, to the town, he asked the soldiers at the gate, at the… how did they call it formerly? The city wall. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a142" ANNOTATION_REF="a48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He wanted to go inside through the city wall, but they did not let him in. He said, “Hey dude, there is one here working with you whose name is Murad the elder and have brought a bucket of yoghurt for him.” They said, “Hey brother, here is no Murad the elder, you are wrong! There is only one Murad, the sultan.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a143" ANNOTATION_REF="a52">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“The sultan has got nothing to do with you.” If you go inside and give him a bucket of yoghurt he will kill you.” He said, “ Guys, I have nothing to do with Sultan Murad, I want Murad the elder, I ask for Murad the elder, Murad!” That one, Murad—I don’t know how—saw him from above and recognized him.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a144" ANNOTATION_REF="a56">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sultan Murad saw the shepherd and said, “Get a move on! Call him and let him come inside! Open the gate! Open the gate and let him come to me!” After they had opened the gate for him he said, “Hey guy, you haven’t told me that you are apparently the sultan. You said to me, ‘I am Murad the elder,’ which means you made fun of me. Why didn’t you tell me?” said the shepherd to Murad, to the Padishah.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a145" ANNOTATION_REF="a61">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When he came in he said, “Indeed! (ḥarām is a word used in Kurdish to exclamate, for example: ḥarām inte hnī! = I see you are (still) here!).  (I see that) you have servants and other men! You didn’t tell me about this. Yesterday I thought you are a poor, old man and therefore I carried this bucket of yoghurt down from the mountain. And you have everything here. What do you say now Why don’t you tell me?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a146" ANNOTATION_REF="a65">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “By God, my brother! I see that the people just adulate me, they do me… let’s say they only like me, because I am a king. But you liked me because of my poverty and you gave me a bucket of yoghurt. Sit down and let us have a chat.” The sultan said this to the shepherd.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a147" ANNOTATION_REF="a70">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“My brother, what’s wrong with you?” He said, “My brother, they all are sitting around alone (i.e. they do not co-operate). I am in despair and so I went up to the mountain. The Russians, the State of the Russians declared war to me, but I can not trust my soldiers, deputies, and governors. What should I do now?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a148" ANNOTATION_REF="a75">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>I do not trust them to fight the Russians and I am afraid that the Russian will defeat us. They will defeat me and I do not trust my people.” He said, “Why don’t you trust them?” He said, “By God, I don’t know it, but I don’t trust them.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a149" ANNOTATION_REF="a77">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “Are you crazy? Arent’t you king over them? And you don’t put them right, don’t make them to be obedient, don’t sort them out.” He said, “How can I put them right?” He said, “Give me permission to do it,  just a for a week, and I will sort them out. I will make your soldiers obedient.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a150" ANNOTATION_REF="a81">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“Tsss,” He said, “My brother, sort them out! Whereas you will sort them out, I will look how you do this.” He said, “First of all, (regarding) your soldiers, give me one week and whatever I do, do not intervene!” He said to the shepherd, “Whatever you do, you are free.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a151" ANNOTATION_REF="a85">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>First the shepherd (wanted) to bring and gather them. He said, “How many provinces are there in the Ottoman Empire?” Let’s say there are hundred, hundred provinces. So he sent a message to these provinces that there is one week left until (the fight) with the Russians. He sent a message saying, “All of you have to come tomorrow (or) after tomorrow and gather in the palace at noon. I want to have you here after three days.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a152" ANNOTATION_REF="a89">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He sent messangers to them, heralds, to call all of them and to gather them in the courtyard. When they had gathered in the courtyard… at that time everybody wear cloak-like wraps.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a153" ANNOTATION_REF="a93">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>At noon he said, “Look!” The soldiers have had gathered around them. Then he said, “Look! You will do what I say?” They said, “Yes!” He said, “One after the other!” Then they said to them, “Lift your robes  up!” They did not wear trousers. “Lift your robes up! I want to see if you are Muslim or Christian.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a154" ANNOTATION_REF="a96">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>There were traitors among them and he wanted (to find out) why the Ottoman had become weak although they are a Muslim country. He said, “Lift up!” then he looked and said, “He is circumcised, he is allright, go away from here! He is not circumcised, cut his head off!” First of all he sorted out the governors, the rulers.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a155" ANNOTATION_REF="a101">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He sorted out those who were circumcised and those who were not circumcised. There left ten, fifteen or twenty circumcised men. Eighty were not circumcises which means they were all traitors in his country, they were not Muslim, but he had made them governors and rulers.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a156" ANNOTATION_REF="a104">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Sultan Murad looked at him from far and said, “Hey, look at this crude shepherd, his brain works better than mine. The brain of this shepherd is better than mine. I have become a Padishah and a Pasha for nothing!” After he had sorted them out he said (to his generals), “I want from you that all your soldiers are completely ready after a week; then we will fight the Russians.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a157" ANNOTATION_REF="a109">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When he had gatherd his soldiers they were all allright. As for the other soldiers, he had killed them. When he brought them to fight the Russian the news had reached the Russians.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a158" ANNOTATION_REF="a111">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>One of their spies had escaped, went to the Russians and said, “My brother, they have found a very intelligent vizier for Sultan Murad and they killed all our spies. Don’t fight them (Don’t go near them)! They will certainly defeat you.” The Russians said, “How come?” He said, “They cut the heads of all our spies.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a159" ANNOTATION_REF="a115">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The new vizier has reliable soldiers, this time they will certainly defeat you, don’t fight them! I tell you, don’t fight them!” And then the Russians sent another message to Sultan Murad saying, “My brother, I do no longer fight you, I don’t want war, I don’t want fighting, I have dismissed fighting.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a160" ANNOTATION_REF="a118">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When the messanger came to Sultan Murad the shepherd said to him, “Haven’t you got the news?” Haven’t you got it?” He said, “What kind of news?” He said, “Haven’t you got the message that they will not fight you XX (here I am telling you (already). ”  </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a162" ANNOTATION_REF="a118" PREVIOUS_ANNOTATION="a160">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[Də is also used in Kurdish to ephasize the verb, for example: ‘’də rūḥ! = Go already!’’] He said, “How come?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a163" ANNOTATION_REF="a121">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “I know, that these soldiers, this army cannot be defeated by anyone in the world. Now a messenger comes to you.” And right, he came to him and said, “They will not fight you, (war) is over, may you be safe and sound!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a164" ANNOTATION_REF="a123">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>After that Sultan Murad said to the shepherd, “My brother, no stupid viziers have remained with me, so you become my vizier!” He said, “My father, my job is to be a shepherd and everybody should do his job. My job is to be a shepherd, and so I go with my sheep. Your job is to be sultan, so find yourself a good vizier, a clever (and urgent?) one, and set your country in order! So I say good bye and go away.” 
Enjoy it!
</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
