<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2022-09-12T16:30:17+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Y:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-033_Sheikh_Nifil-Harran-2010.wav"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="../../Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-033_Sheikh_Nifil-Harran-2010.wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:79a23962-a426-4070-b4c9-db01012a6547</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">113</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="7770"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="25160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="25160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="40480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="40480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="57660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="57660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="76980"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="76990"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="86490"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="86500"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="101630"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="101630"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="117640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="117650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="130650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="130650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="144650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="144660"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="150980"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="150990"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="167130"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="167140"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="174990"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="174990"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="192480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="192480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="207640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="207640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="225670"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="225670"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="232110"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="232120"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="251630"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="251640"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="267710"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="267710"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="278230"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>nahāṛ b-al-yām ˁala ˀayyām dōr zimān ar-rasūl ˁalē aṣ-ṣalāt w-as-salām hazreti Muḥammad, rāyḥīn ˁa-l-ḥarib ˁa-l-ḥarib ḏ̣āllīn hafte, xamǝsṭaˁš yōm, ˁišrīn yōm b-al-ḥarib</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts2" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-yōm-in rāyḥīn, ḏ̣āllīn b-al-ḥarib ǧaˁ-yruddūn  min al-ḥarib ˁala byūt-hum ᵊbsāgt aṣ… ᵊbsāgt aṣ-ṣaḥābt an-nibi wāḥad zād ˀism-u Nifil Nifil ᵊbsāgt an-nibi  ˁalē aṣ-ṣalāt w-as-salām. Nifil</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a12"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>b-al-ḥarib hāḏa, mistašhid šahīd, ṣāyir šahīd, maḏbūḥ yaˁni mayyit ṣāyir šahīd w-ar-rasūl ˁalē as-salām  w hazreti ˁAli w-Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣaddīq dāmmīn-u mǝṭraḥ-in  mištahid w ǧāyīn  ˁala byūt-hum.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a19"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Nifil, yōm-in rāˁit bēt-u ḥirimt-u  ṭābi mihni ˁala galib-ha  ˀinnu zlimit-he mayyit ta-ngūl waḷḷa xāyfe ˁalē-ha xōf, wāǧfe ˁala…  aṣ-ṣaḥābe w-ar-rasūl yōm-in yiǧūn ˁala darib-hum gāṭṭit-ilhum awwal ar-rasūl qāfilt-u min ǧiddām</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ǧaˁ-tiǧi, gālat “yā ḥabīb Aḷḷa, yā rasūl Aḷḷa!  ᵊzlimt-i Nifil, wēn-u mū rāḥ b-sāgit-hum ḥarām māmiš, mū yamm-ak</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a28"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts13">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ar-rasūl ˁalē aṣ-ṣalāt w-as-salām ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ gāl “š-ilhe da-gūl al-ḥurma š-arīd agūl l-al-ḥurma hāḏi agūl-lha hniyye yaˁni ˀaxaǧil-he wēya  mā-dri šnōn agūl yaˁni aḥazin-he. ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ warā hīčiḏ</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a33"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts12" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ warā ˀin hazreti ˁAli raḏ̣iya ḷḷa ˁan-hu zād b-al-qāfilt al-ikinǧiyye al-ma… aṯ-ṯānye ǧāye qāfilt hazreti ˁAli zād saˁalatt-u zād ˁayne  gāyilt-illu “Yā ˁAli ḥarām ᵊzlimt-i rāˁi bēt-i Nifil</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a37"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts17">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>saˁalt ar-rasūl w gāl isˁali ˁAli ˀinte tˁarif aṣṣōb-u wēn ᵊb-hay qāfile?” hazreti ˁAli raḏ̣iya ḷḷāhu ˁan-hu gāl “yāw āni šnōn al-ḥurma ḏīye ˀahnī-he, ˀaxaǧil-he? </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a41"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts16" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ar-rasūl ˁalē aṣ-ṣalāt wa-salām mā ˁallam-he, w āni šnōn ˀagul-ilhe?” zād ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ warā hīčiḏ ˀin Abu Bakir, qāfilt Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq. Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq maˁnāt-u aṣ-ṣadīq ṣiddīq mā-y… alli yˁidd aṣ-ṣiddīq ṣādiq.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a46"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāl “isˁali hīčiḏ!” mādd b-uṣbuˁ-u zād lē waṛā, gāl “isˁali!  Abu Bakir, ǧa-yiǧi huwwe balči yˁarif”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a48"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ˀuxṛa tānye guṭma ǧāy Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq yōm-in ǧāy Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq gāyilt-illu  “yā ˀAbu Bakir, ᵊzlimt-i Nifil ḥarām, mū maˁā-kum mū bsāgt al-qāfile mū bsāgt aṣ-ṣaḥāba mū rāḥ ᵊbsāgit-kum, wēn-u? ˀAbu Bakir aṣ-ṣiddīq ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ gāl </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a54"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“rasūl Aḷḷa mā ˁallam-he, hazreti ˁAli mā ˁallam-he w-āni šnōn?” yōm-in ᵊmdaḥḥiǧ warā hīčiḏ  zād mā ḏ̣āll ta-ygūl, ymidd uṣbuˁ-u lē wara</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a57"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts24" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts27">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ṣāyiḥ “Aḷḷa! Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq ṣāyiḥ “Aḷḷa! yōm-in ṣāyiḥ “ˀAḷḷa!” hīčiḏ miltafit warā ˀin Nifil rāčib ᵊḥṣān-u w-ǧaˁ-yiǧi warā gāl “yā ˀumm-i hāḏa ˀinn-u  ǧaˁ yiǧi warā-yi.” gāyilt-illu “tamām, xurf Aḷḷa ˁalē-k, ǧīy</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a63"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts26" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts29">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōminn-u ǧāy Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq  damm-u b-īd-u, huwwa damm-u b-īd-u w ǧī yōm-in ṣāḥ Aḷḷa ǧī warā ǧī ˁala rasūl Aḷḷa, humma aaaa  “komutanǝm komutan-hum ḥabībo ḥabīb-hum Muḥammad! ǧī ˁala rasūl Aḷḷa, gāl “yā ˁala rasūl Aḷḷa! </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a68"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts28" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>šinhi al-ḥāl? masˀala šnōn hāḏi ṣārat? gāl “ˁalēš yā Abu Bakir?” gāl “āni ṣiḥit inte mā ˁallamit-he w ˀAli mā ˁallam-he. w-āni zād ṣiḥit Aḷḷa  waḷḷa w ˀinn-u Nifil warā-yi rāčib b-al-xēr w ǧāˁid w ǧaˁ, kidīš w ǧaˁ-yiǧi šinhi haḏi  ḥikmit-he?”gāl-lu “yā Abu Bakr  aṣ-ṣiddīq, inte ˁam-ann-ak ṣiddīq </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a74"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts30" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā tigdar ḥēš-ak, ḥēš-ak mā tigdar tikḏib  mā maddēt īd-ak inte alli trīd aṣ-ṣiddīq.” ism-u ṣiddīq</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a76"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“yōm-inn-ak ṣiḥit Aḷḷa rabb al-ˁālamīn bi-ˁizzt-u wa-ǧalāl-u, ˀAḷḷa darrab-li Ǧabrāyīl  w gāl-illi  gūl l-al-ḥabībi ta-ygūl l-Abu Bakir aṣ-ṣiddīq l-Abu Bakir, yēlōn-u ṣāyiḥ marrtēn, nōbtēn Aḷḷa  b-al-ḥarib hāḏa š-gadd-mu mustašhidīn aš-šǝhada aṣ ṣāraw  al-mayytīn, xamsmiyya wēya ˀalif wēya wala sabəˁmye</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a84"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts37">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yēlōn ṣāyiḥ nōbtēn “Aḷḷa”  kull-hum āni gawwamit-hum w darrabt-hum bsāgit  Nifil, bass sāḥ marra wəḥde miššān Nifil bass gawwamt-illu Nifil ˁam-ann-u ṣāḥ wəḥde “ˀAḷḷa” ˀāni hemen ǝnṭēt rūḥ-u raddadit rūḥit  Nifil ˁala ha… ˁala badan-u</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a91"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts36" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w ramšit ˁēn xallēt-u wara Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq ta-mā yidčiḏib kalām-u ta-yṣīr yḏ̣all dawām ṣiddīq.” winn-u waṛā ha-l-masˀala hāḏi hiyye</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a95" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>On a day, in the days and times of the prophet Muḥammad, peace and blessing be upon him, they were going to the war, to the war, they were away for a week, fifteen days, twenty days in the war</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a96" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When they went, they stayed in the war, then they started to come back from the war to their houses, someone was with the companiers of the prophet, his name was Nifil, he was with the prophet, peace and blessing be upon him. Nifil</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a97" ANNOTATION_REF="a12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>died in this war, he had become a martyr, I mean, he had been killed, dead, he had become a martyr, and the prophet, peace and blessing be upon him, ˁAli and Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣaddīq (the honest) had burried him, where he died, and were on their way home. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a98" ANNOTATION_REF="a19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Nifil, when his housekeeper, his wife, of course had fears in her heart, whether her husband was dead, let’s say, or she was afraid, she had fears on her, she stopped by the companiers and the prophet, while they were on their way, she was waiting for them. First, the prophet’s convoy was in the front,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a99" ANNOTATION_REF="a25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>she went towards it and said: “O, beloved by God, messenger of God! My husband, Nifil, where is he? didn’t he go with them, I see he is not here, he is not with you.” </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a100" ANNOTATION_REF="a28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The prophet, peace and blessing be upon him, looked around and said (to himself): “What do I want to/ What should I  tell this woman, if I tell her, I will let her down, I will disappoint her, or I don’t know how to say, I mean that I will make her sad.” He looked behind him like this</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a101" ANNOTATION_REF="a33">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>when he looked behind him, ˁAli, may God bless him, was in the second convoy, the second. ˁAli’s convoy was coming, so she asked him the same (question) She said to him: “O ˁAli, I see my man, my housekeeper, Nifil</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a102" ANNOTATION_REF="a37">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>I have asked the prophet, and he said ask ˁAli, do you know where he is, in which convoy?” ˁAli, may God bless him said (to himself): “How can I let this woman down, disappoint her?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a103" ANNOTATION_REF="a41">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>the prophet, blessings and peace be upon him hasn’t told her, and how am I supposed to tell her?” So he looked behind him like this, where he saw Abu Bakir aṣ-ṣadīq’s convoy. Abu Bakir aṣ-ṣiddīq, which means “the honest” is honest, he doesn’t... the honest must be honest.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a104" ANNOTATION_REF="a46">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said: “Ask him, like that” He pointed with his finger to behind him saying: “Ask Abu Bakir, he is coming, maybe he knows”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a105" ANNOTATION_REF="a48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Again, Abu Bakir came, when Abu Bakir aṣ-ṣiddīq had come, she said to him: “O Abu Bakir, my husband Nifil, I see he is not with you, he is not with the convoy, he is not with the companiers, didn’t he go with you? where is he?” Abu Bakir aṣ-ṣiddīq looked around and said (to himself): </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a106" ANNOTATION_REF="a54">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“God’s messenger has not told her, ˁAli has not told her, how can I?” When he looked behind him like this, no one was left, let’s say, so he would point with his finger to behind him.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a107" ANNOTATION_REF="a57">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He shouted: “God!” Abu Bakir aṣ-ṣiddīq shouted “God!” When he shouted “God!” like this turning around, (suddenly) Nifil was riding on his horse and coming behind him. He said “Ma’am, there he is coming behind me” She said to him “all good, thank you, he has come”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a108" ANNOTATION_REF="a63">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq was, his blood was in his hands (it was his responsobility), his blood was in his hands, and came, when he shouted “God”, he (Nifil) came behind him. He came to God’s messenger, they, “their leader and beloved, Muḥammad!” He came to God’s messenger, and said “O God’s messenger!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a109" ANNOTATION_REF="a68">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>What is going on? How did this matter happen?” He said “Why, Abu Bakir?” He said “I shouted that you hadn’t told her and ˁAli hadn’t told her, and I called God and suddenly Nifil was behind me riding on the horse, donkey, and coming. What is the wisdom of this?” He said to him “Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq, since you are ṣiddīq (honest)</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a110" ANNOTATION_REF="a74">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>you can not, God forbid, God forbid, you can not lie, you did not point with your hand, you only want to be honest” his name is ṣiddīq (honest)</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a111" ANNOTATION_REF="a76">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“When you called God, lord of the worlds, with his glory and majesty, God sent me Ğabrāyīl and said to me “Tell my beloved to tell Abu Bakir, Abu Bakir, if he would have shouted twice, two times, God, in this war, how many died, have become martyrs, have become dead, five hundred or one thousand or seven hundred </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a112" ANNOTATION_REF="a84">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>if he had shouted twice “God” I would have revived all of them and sent them with Nifil, but he shouted only once for Nifil, so I just revived Niffil for him. As soon as he shouted “God” once, I immediatly gave him his soul, I gave Niffil’s soul back to... to his body </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a113" ANNOTATION_REF="a91">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>and in the blink of an eye, I made him behind Abu Bakr aṣ-ṣiddīq, so he won’t be a liar, so his words will always be ṣiddīq (honest)” so as for (the fact) that he was behind him, that is how this matter is”  </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
