<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-01-11T16:58:16+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Y:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-072_Villages-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:723ec63f-0e46-4f1d-80ad-2073302eed1f</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">75</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="770"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="14600"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="14611"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="30075"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="30112"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="45098"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="45098"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="55154"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="55162"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="76381"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="76384"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="108797"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="108804"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="119282"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="119325"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="132847"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="132887"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="159387"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="159412"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="170434"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="170456"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="195150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="195173"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="208521"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="208564"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="228847"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="228847"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="247803"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="247825"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="267107"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="267173"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="283738"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="283768"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="315563"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="315588"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="331204"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="331230"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="353383"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts39" TIME_VALUE="353383"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts40" TIME_VALUE="368127"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts41" TIME_VALUE="368152"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts42" TIME_VALUE="384819"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts43" TIME_VALUE="384845"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts44" TIME_VALUE="406512"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts45" TIME_VALUE="406512"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts46" TIME_VALUE="424383"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts47" TIME_VALUE="424435"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts48" TIME_VALUE="444665"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts49" TIME_VALUE="444665"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts50" TIME_VALUE="465210"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>awwali al-mille kull ᵊbyūt-hum ᵊhnīt-hum ᵊbgaḷb aǧ-ǧarye. alḥaz al ʕind-u gāʕa gām ysawwi bgaḷǝb gāʕt-u bēt. tidāġaṭat al-mille, daḥḥiǧ hīčiḏ al-ḥagg!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a2"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>kull… kull-min gaʕad ᵊb-ǧ… ᵊb-gāʕt-u yʕammir ysawwi bēt qādi, ᵊb-ṭāpīy-u yʕammir qādi. yigūl “arīd aʕammir hēne azraʕ šiǧaṛ bēt-i ta-yṣīr zēn, abʕid ʕin aǧ-ǧarye tā mā yṣīr šakli yaʕni tidāġaṭat al-mille.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a3"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>šiǧaṛ gāmu yizraʕūn šiǧaṛ ᵊbgaḷǝb bēt-u. gām ysawwi yizraʕ warid. gām ysawwi l-ᵊškāl ysawwi sēṛa. kull šakle gām ysawwi bēt-u ha-n-nōba il ḥāl-u. awwali bgaḷb aǧ-ǧarye, mā yǝṭlǝʕ m-aǧ-ǧarye maḥḥad yʕammir b-ač-čōl.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a4"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>alḥaz kull-hum gāmu yʕammrūn b-ač-čōl yisḥab ǧērān-u b-ač-čōl. alḥaz ta-ngūl miṯl al-bēt haḏāk alḥaz. sāḥib ǧērān-u sāḥib mayyt-u hināk ziraʕ šiǧaṛ hināk bēt-u. haḏāk hīčiḏ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>kull-min gāmu ysawwūn haš-šakil hāḏe. al ʕind-u milič gām yuṭluʕ min ᵊhnīye. haḏōl mesela min haǧ-ǧarye alḥaz ʕind-u bugaṛ ḏōle, ʕind-u bgaṛa b-al-bēt miššān ḥalīb-u miššān xāṯr-u miššān ǧubn-u. al-ʕaǧāwīn al-ʕiǧyān az-zġār yuṭluʕūn yisraḥūn bī-hin, ysawwūn haš-šakil hāḏe ta-yišbaʕin al-ḥīwān haḏanne.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>awwali, al-mille akṯar-ha ʕid-he qanam. al-qanam ṣārat zihīdāt hēne. ʕaman mā ḏ̣all mǝṭraḥ yisraḥūn. al-mille gāmat tištari bugaṛ ʕādēne. al-ᵊbgaṛa daha ṣārat qōlay. yrūḥ yisraḥ wḥad-u, w waḥde b-gadd ʕadal xamasṭaʕš ᵊnʕaǧe, gām yāxuḏ ᵊbgaṛa ʕādēne miššān ḥalīb-he w miššān xāṯir-he.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>waḷḷa awwali kull-u qanam al-bēt at trūḥ bī-´ arbaʕīn xamsīn imyit dābbit qanam šī. alḥaz māmin, māmin alḥaz qanam zihīd, čiṯīr zihīd, bass b-aǧ-ǧbāl šī.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hināk b-aǧ-ǧbāl šī qanam ʕaman hināk šī, mǝṭraḥ-in yiṭlaʕ yisraḥ bī-hin. amma hēne māmin, mǝṭraḥ al bī-he mayye alḥaz haḏanne mā ḏ̣all bī-he qanam, kull-u b-aǧ-ǧbāl haḏāk, bāʕaw ʕala ahal aǧ-ǧbile.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>awwali al-qanam, yōmin yḥalbūn-ha, ʕugub-ma yḥalbūn-ha al-ḥurma, ač-čibīre, al b-al-bēt. hiyya ᵊtʕarif ḥurmit ač-čibīra al-uṃṃa haḏīč tāxḏ al-ḥalīb w ʕa-n-nār ᵊtfawwr-u awwal fāl ʕugub-ma tfawwr-u txallī-´ tsawwi dinlenme ta-yubrud guṭma.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hā yōm-inn-u yubrud ʕādēne ᵊǧǧīb ᵊssawwi inčādin inčān ᵊtrīd ᵊssawwi xāṯir, ᵊtxaṯṯr-u wi-tqaṭṭī-´. ᵊtḥuṭṭ-u muṭraḥ-in hawwiy hināk yṣīr ǧubun ʕādēne. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a11"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hā ʕugub-ma yṣīr ǧubun ʕādēne ši- ssawwi? šī šukwa ngūl lilhe iḥne awwali, aš-šukwa, min ǧilid al-ᵊhnīye yuṭluʕ [yuṭluḥ], al-ǧadi. – al-ǧadi – aǧ-ǧadi. awwali yuṭluʕūn yiḏbaḥūn aǧ-ǧadi mā yigšumūn ǧild-u yuṭluʕūn-u mir_rās-u kull-u tek parča hāw yinaḏ̣ḏ̣fūn-u w zēn yqasslūn-u b-al-miliḥ b-al-ᵊhnīye.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a12"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w yisawwūn-u šukwa, aš-šukwa ʕādēne šnōn-he? lilhe ṯalaṯ riǧlēn xašab ṯalaṯ riǧlēn. w-aš-šukwa ḏiyye lilhe xšibe yurbuṭūn-ha l-īdēn w riǧlēn aǧ-ǧadi ǧild aǧ-ǧadi. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a13"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w zalʕūm aǧ-ǧadi yṣīr miṯl al-musluq. ᵊtkubb al-xāṯir qādi al-ḥurma, w-ᵊtkubb ʕalē-´ mayye w-ᵊššidd-u w tgūm ᵊtxuḏ̣ḏ̣-u w-iḥna ngūl, ᵊtxuḏ̣ḏ̣ al-xāṯir. ᵊtxuḏ̣ḏ̣-u zēn ᵊtxuḏ̣ḏ̣-u, ʕugub-ma txuḏ̣ḏ̣-u zēn, ᵊtkubb-u b-aǧ-ǧidrīye, az-zubda ʕādēne aǧ-ǧišde, as-samin ᵊngūl yuṭluʕ lē fōg. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-ḥurma ʕādēne tāxḏ as-samin min fōg, w tḥaṭṭ ᵊtḥuṭṭ-u, aa w tlumm haš-šakil ḏe ᵊtlumm as-samin. ʕugub-ma yṣīr čiṯīr ᵊtmawwʕ-u ʕugub-ma tmawwʕ-u šī ǧild-in nōba. šukwa, iḥna ši-ngul-l-he ši-ngūl Ismāʕīl haḏīč?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts29" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ǧild-in nōba šī yḥuṭṭūn-u as-samin ᵊbgaḷəb-ha, al-ᵊkwāṛa ši-ngul-l-he? al-ᵊkwāṛa ngul-il-he. zād al-ᵊkwāṛa min ǧild-ha, zād al-ᵊhnīye,  al…al-ǧadi zād yṣīr al-xārūf zād yṣīr, ē.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a16"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts31" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yḥuṭṭūn as-samin qādi hināk mā yxarab al-ʕukka – ysammūn-ha ʕukka – ʕukka. yḥuṭṭūn as-samin qādi, al-ḥurma tḥuṭṭ as-samin kull-u qādi, kull-hum yāklūn m-as-samin haḏāk. b-aš-štē b-al-gēḏ̣ kull-hum m-as-samin haḏāk ysawwūn ačil, ysawwūn kull šakle min as-samin hāḏe.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a17"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā yxarab bī-he. – mā yxarab bī-he. – aǧ-ǧild al yḥuṭṭūn bī-´ as-samin ysammūn-u ʕukka, al-ʕukka as-samin mā yxarab bī-he. [gap 4:53 - 5.08] ī yḥuṭṭūn ʕalē-he dibis al-fallōṭi yxalṭūn ta-ymawwʕ[ūn]-u ṣṣīr layyne. yaʕni yḥuṭṭūn ʕalē-he dibis fallōṭi. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a18"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w baʕdēn zād yḥuṭṭ ykassrūn ar-rummān ᵊbsāgit ḏāk, yaʕni yiṭḥanūn-u gišr ar-rummān. yiṭḥanūn-u miṯil aṭ-ṭaḥīn, ᵊbsāgt al-fallōṭi yḥuṭṭūn-u fōg-ha tā mā txaṛab, ta-ḏ̣ḏ̣all saġlam yaʕni ʕumur-ha yiṭwal. ysawwūn ačil, b-as-samin haḏāk ysawwūn ačil.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a19"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts37" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yḥuṭṭ al-xubuz hīčiḏ ysawwi ʕa-ṣ-ṣāč, awwali b-aǧ-ǧarye b-al-gaṛāye, kull ṣubḥ ᵊyxabzūn, kull ṣubuḥ, kull bēt kull ṣubuḥ, al-yōm ᵊšgadd iḥtiyāǧ-u ta-ngūl, iḥtiyāǧ-u ʕišrīn xubuz, ʕišrīn ᵊrqēf. al-ʕišrīn ᵊrqēf al-ḥurma ṣubḥ ᵊtgūm m-aš-šufaq ṭalʕit aš-šamis, ᵊtgūm, šnōn-ma tgūm ᵊtqassil bēt-he w-ᵊtnaḏ̣ḏ̣if ḥawālē-he. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a20"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts39" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts40">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕugub-ma tnaḏ̣ḏ̣if tuṭluʕ aṭ-ṭaḥīn w-ᵊssawwi ʕaǧīn. tʕaǧin-u w ssawwi ʕaǧīn w ǧǧīb aṣ-ṣāǧ w tirmī-´ w-tiǧʕid ḥabāyb al-bēt yugʕudin yugūmin yixabzin, al-yōm ᵊšgadd yāzī-ne? al-yōm ʕišrīn ᵊrqēf yāzī-ne. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts41" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts42">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yxabbzin ʕišrīn rqēf yṣaffṭinn-u w yirminn-u iḥtiyāǧ kun__nahāṛ hāḏa ysawwinnu. kun__nahāṛ hāḏa l-iḥtiyāǧ hāḏe ysawwinn-u. hā al-… ʕādēnīye ʕādēne alḥaz alḥaz gāmaw ysawwūn b-aš-šahaṛ, alḥaz b-aš-šahaṛ gāmin, ᵊtyabbis al-xubuz ᵊtxallī́ šahaṛ. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a22"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts43" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts44">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>amma awwali kull ṣubuḥ, al-bēt, ahl al-bēt yugʕudūn mn-aṣ-ṣubuḥ, min ṭalʕit aš-šamis al-mille kull-he tugʕud. hēne aǧ-ǧarye, al-gaṛāye kull-he min ṭalʕit aš-šamis yugʕudūn, xall šuqul šī xallu mā-min yugʕudūn aṣ-ṣubuḥ. ʕugub ṣalāt aṣ-ṣubuḥ al-mille tugʕud tufṭur w tsawwi xubuz w al luwwa šuqul yisawwi šuġl-u l-aḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur yištaġlūn. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts45" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts46">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>aḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur ʕādēne, ʕugub ṣalāt aḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur al-mille kull-he tnām. ʕaǧīyān ᵊngūl – al-mille kull-he tnām? – ᵊtnām, čibīr w zġīr saʕtēn yǧayylūn iḥna ngūl. alḥaz ᵊššūf b-at-talafizyōn meksika ygulū-l-he fiesta, fiesta – siesta. – hī hēne! </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a24"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts47" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yǧayyil al-ḥurma w-az-zlime kull-min ʕugb aḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur sāʕtēn talāṯ, kull-min ᵊb-bēt-u aǧ-ǧarye tiǧī-he mā-min ḥade, kull-he nāyme, kull-he nāyme yǧayylūn. hā ʕugum… ǧirīb l-al-ʕaṣǝr ʕādēne ṣalāt al-ʕaṣǝr, al-mille tgūm [dgūm] ᵊtgūm ᵊtgūm ʕādēne tgūm ʕala šqāḷ-ha.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts49" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts50">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-ᵊssawwi šqāḷ-ha tgūm ᵊssawwi šqāḷ-ha ʕādēne ha-š-šakil hāḏe, w ddāwim ᵊhnīye l-al-lēl. hā b-al-lēl ʕādēne aǧ ǧāʕdīn ǧāʕdīn ᵊb-bēt-u w ar  rāyiḥ mitharriǧ yrūḥ ʕala mitharriǧ ʕala mǝṭraḥ, haš-šakil hāḏe al-maʕīše ddāwim yaʕni.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a51" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>In former times the houses and the stuff of the people were all inside of the village. Now, the one who owns land has begun to make a house on his estate. The people have dispersed. Look! That’s the truth!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a52" ANNOTATION_REF="a2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Everyone who lives in the… builds a house over there on his field. He let it build over there on land which is registered for him in the cadastre. He says, “Here I want to erect a house and I want to plant trees that it becomes beautiful. I want to be far from the village that nothing happens. Thus the people have dispersed.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a53" ANNOTATION_REF="a3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Trees; they started to plant trees inside their courtyards. They  started to plant flowers. They made this and that and erected greenhouses. At once they started to make everything for themselves. In fomer times everything was inside the village, nobody left the village, nobody built a house on the open land.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a54" ANNOTATION_REF="a4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Now they all have started to build houses outside (the village) and they even bring electricity out to the open land. Now it is like that house over there. (His owner) has brought electricity there, he has brought water there, he has planted trees. There is his house, so is it.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a55" ANNOTATION_REF="a5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Everybody started to do it like this. The one who has his own property left. Those, for example, are from this village. Now they have cows, they have cows at home for the milk, for the yoghurt, for the cheese. The small children go out and pasture them, they make it like this in order that these animals get enough to eat.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a56" ANNOTATION_REF="a6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>In former times most people had sheep. (But now) sheep have become few here. Because there is no space to graze them. So the people started to buy cows. The cows are easier (to handle). They to and graze alone and one is worth as much as fifteen ewes. So they have begun to buy cows because of their milk and their yoghurt. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a57" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>By God, formerly there were all sheep. Whatever house you entered there were 40, 50, 100 head of sheep. Now there aren’t. There aren’t. Now there are few, very few sheep, only in the mountains are there sheep.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a58" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Over there in the mountains, there are sheep, because there is enough place to graze them. But here aren’t any. At places where there is water, there no sheep now remain. All of them are in those mountains. They have sold (them) to the mountain people.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a59" ANNOTATION_REF="a9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>In former times, when they milked them, after they have milked them… the old woman (did it), the one who was at home, she knew it. The old woman, the “mother” is the one who takes the milk and first brings it to the boil on the fire. After she has brought it to the boil she lets it rest so it cools down a little.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a60" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When it has cooled down she brings… and makes, if she wants to make yoghurt she let it curdle and covers it. She puts it at a cool place and there it becomes cheese. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a61" ANNOTATION_REF="a11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And what does she do after it has become cheese? There is something called šukwa. In former times there was the šukwa made of skin, the skin of a young billy goat. In former times, when they slaughtered a young billy goat, they did not dissect its skin, the left it all in one piece from the head down. They cleaned it and tossed it  well in salt.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a62" ANNOTATION_REF="a12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And then they made a rack called šukwa out of it. What is a šukwa? It has three feet made of wood, three feet. And this šukwa has a piece of wood to which they bind the hands and the feet of the billy goat, the skin of the young billy goat. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a63" ANNOTATION_REF="a13">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And the throat of the billy goat is like a water tap. And the the woman pours the yoghurt inside, then she pours water in it, ties it up and starts to rock it. We say, she is rocking the yoghurt. She rocks it very well, and after she has rocked it she pours it in a pot. And then the butter, the cream, the fat comes up.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a64" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Then the woman takes the fat from upside and puts it, collects it like this. She collects the fat. When she has collected a lot she melts it and after she has melted it she puts it in another skin. It is called šukwa, how do we call it, Ismail?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a65" ANNOTATION_REF="a15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They put it inside another skin, kwāṛa, do we call it like this? We call it kwāṛa.  The kwāṛa is also from skin, it is also from the skin of a young billy goat or of a lamb. Yes.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a66" ANNOTATION_REF="a16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They put the ghee inside it and there it does not get rotten; it’s called ʕukka – they call it ʕukka. – Hose pipe. They put the ghee inside, the woman puts all the ghee inside it and they all (the whole family) eats from this ghee. Winter and summer they make their food with this ghee; they make everything with this ghee.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a67" ANNOTATION_REF="a17">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And it does not get rotten in it. – It does not spoil. – The skin in which they put the ghee is called ʕukka. In the hose pipe the ghee does not spoil. They put grape jelly on it (the skin) and rub it inside in order that it becomes soft. That means they put grape jelly on it.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a68" ANNOTATION_REF="a18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And then they they cut pommegranates and put them together with it (the jelly) on it, that means they grind the skin of (dried) pommegrantes, they grind it like flour. And together with the grape jelly they put it on the goat’s skin in order that it does not get rotten, that it remains good and that it persists for a long time. With this ghee they make food.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a69" ANNOTATION_REF="a19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They make the bread on an iron plate. In former times they used to bake bread in the villages every morning. Every family did it every morning. They said, “How much is today’s needs? – The needs is twenty loaves, twenty loaves.” The woman got up at dusk, at sunrise. As soon as she had got up she washed up her house and cleaned its surroundings.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a70" ANNOTATION_REF="a20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>After the cleaning she took the flour and made the dough. She kneaded the dough and brought the iron plat, put it on the ground and woke up the women of the house. They all sat down and started to bake bread. (They said to each other), “How much is enough for us today? – Today twenty loaves are enough for us.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a71" ANNOTATION_REF="a21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>So they baked twenty loaves, stacked them and put them (at a place). So they filled the needs of every day. Every day the made as much bread as was needed. Ha, but nowadays the do it once in a month, only once in a month the bake and then they dry the bread and leave it for a month.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a72" ANNOTATION_REF="a22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>But in former times they did it every morning. The (female) members of the family gathered  early in the morning, at sunrise the all the people gathered. Here in the village, in the villages, they used to gather at sunrise. Regardless of whether there was work or not they gathered in the morning. After the morning prayer the people were sitting together and had breakfast, they baked bread and the one who had work did his work: They worked until noon. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a73" ANNOTATION_REF="a23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>At noon, after the midday prayer all the people sleep. The children, let’s say – All the people sleep? – Yes, they do. The young and the old have an afternoon nap for two hours. Now you can see it on television that the Mexicans call this fiesta, fiesta – siesta – Yes, like this!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a74" ANNOTATION_REF="a24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Women and men alike have a nap of two or three hours after noon. Everybody who is in the house. When you come (at that time) to a village you won’t find anybody, because they are all sleeping. They all have an afternoon nap. Towards late afternoon, we have the afternoon prayer the people stand up again and start doing their work.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a75" ANNOTATION_REF="a25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They do their jobs, they start doing their jobs and in this way they continue until the evening. As for the evening there are those who stay at home and those who go out, they go out to another place to have a chat. And like this life continues again and again.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
