<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2022-08-23T17:45:41+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Q:/shawi-data/122_elan/Urfa-012_Lentils-Harran-2010.wav"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="./Urfa-012_Lentils-Harran-2010.wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:b5cd475c-e71a-43c7-9eca-dfeefaeac03d</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">168</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="4220"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="24507"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="24511"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="42596"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="42596"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="62895"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="62895"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="84934"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="84934"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="104356"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="104363"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="119774"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="119788"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="135999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="135999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="149366"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="149375"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="171431"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="171440"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="194852"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="194852"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="210540"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="210540"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="228567"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="228568"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="251934"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="251944"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="278302"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="278302"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="312816"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="312816"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="328100"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa al-ˁadas, yizraˁūn-u ˀonikinǧi ˀay ˀonbirinǧi ay xamǝs tušhur yḏ̣all hīčiḏ arbaˁ tušhur, xamǝs tušhur sitt tušhur baˁdēn yiǧūn yiḥaṣṣdūnu  b-al-mōtōrāt yōm-innu yības ˁugub xamǝsṭaˁǝš yōm hīčiḏ , baˁad-ma yības b-al-mōtōrāt yiḥaṣṣdūn-u yuṭluˁūn at-tibin ˁayrǝ</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>tibnu w-al-ˁadas ˁayrǝ , w-al-ˁadas ˁād  yāxḏūn-u ˀahal-u ybīˁūn-u  b-al-ˁarṣa b-al-ˁarṣa yibīˁūn-u, al-ˁadas taqrīban al-ˁadas al… hāḏa  al-xaḏ̣ar ᵊngūl-l-u, yeşil mercimek ybīˁūn kīlawu waraqa wruga, al-kīlo, al-ˁadas</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-at-tibin ybīˁūn-u  ˀímy(it) ǧiriš ˁašar ᵊgrūš  – ˁašr ᵊgrūš  – ˁašr ᵊgrūš yaˁni  al-ˁašǝr kīlawāt waraqa at-tibin w-al-ˁadas, baˁdēn-ma yāxḏūn-u ˁa-l-fabrikāt tkassr-u  ysawwūn-u qišimtēn yṣīr kīlawu (b-)malyūnēn gišr-u yiṭlǝˁūn-u yiṭlǝˁūn gišr-u  yṣīr al-kīlu (b-)malyūnēn</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a37"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>b-al-markēt, b-as-sūpermarkēt b-al-baqqāl yibīˁūn-u  b-wrugtēn w-nuṣṣ,  waraqtēn w-nuṣṣ yaˁni waraqtēn zād ybīˁūn-u taqġrīban bir yūrow  yaˁni yūrow avrūpa ˁa-l-bēt  iḥna nrūḥ nāxuḏ xamǝs  kīlawāt, yāzī-na šahrēn ṯalāṯ al-… an-nuṣṣ kīlo rubuˁ kīlu ysawwi ˁēš li-n-na nuṣṣ kīlo  ysawwī-na ˁēš šōraba</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a51"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts8" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-hāḏi l-gāˁ?  al-gāˁ hāḏi siǧīy. hāḏi siǧīy ˀī, hāḏa l-ˁadas hāḏa siǧīy maˁṭīn-u mayye yēlōn mū siǧīy mā yṣīr al-ˁiḏīy mā yṣīr hēne čünkü al-ˁiḏīy yibas mā ṣār mǝṭar  yibas min hāḏa ysawwūn-u siǧīy</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a61"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā ššūf al-buwāri haḏanne yǧībūn-hin  ysawwūn siǧīy yisǧūn bī-hin al-ˁadas al-mayye… b-al-buwāri haḏanne yisḥabūn mayye w-yisǧūn al-ˁadas w-al-mayye hāḏi mayyt al-barāǧ hāḏi mayyit al-barāǧ hāḏi – hāḏi mayyt al-barāǧ - – hāḏi mayyit al-barāč.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a67"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>tiǧi hēne  yōm-in al-barāč ydaššrūn al-mayye yḥuṭṭūn ṣīfōn ᵊb-gaḷǝb-ha buwāri, ṣīfōn halḥīn mayye mā-miš, magṭūˁa hāḏi timtali l-mayye  yḥuṭṭūn al-būri, aṣ-ṣīfōn hēne yḥuṭṭūn, w-min hēne tgūm ᵊtkubb yisǧūn al-ˁadas bī</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a75"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts14" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yinṭūn-u mayye  yōm-innu yaˁṭaš yisgūnu mayye al-mayye taġrīban  ˁal-ˁadas marra waḥde mayye  šahar ᵊtkaffīy, tāzīy baˁda šahar uxṛa yisḥabūn yinṭūn-u mayye ta-mā yības</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a81"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-mayye ṣārat al-ˁadas vērmu yṣīr zēn  yaˁṭi ta-ngūl ad-dönem  hemen hemen  aṯnaˁaš dönem  ʾiḥna hēne nsammī nsammī čēl – čēl – al-gāˁ  ngūl-lhe  aṯnaˁaš dönüm nsammī čēl ač-čēl yaˁṭi  al tizraˁ-u ta-ngūl čēl</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a92"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ˁadas ač-čēl al-ˁadas imyitēn (mītēn) kīlōw al-mītēn kīlōw yiǧi  xams ᵊṭwān ˁadas al-xams ᵊṭwān, al-kīlōw yiǧi xamsa w-ˁišrīn kīlo al-vērim maḥṣūl Yōm-in yiǧi xamsa w-ˁišrīn kīlōw kwayyis yaˁni zēn hemen hemen yiǧi la-l-xams ᵊṭwān arbaˁ ᵊṭwān  xams ᵊṭwān yiǧi l-ˁadas ˀač-čēl, ˀaṯnaˁaš dönüm</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a101"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts20" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>iḥna hēne ˁa-l-guwāˁi ᵊtgūl [dgūl]“ˀašgadd ˁind-ak gāˁ?” ᵊtgūl “ˁind-i  ˁašəar tičāl  ˁašǝr čēlāt al-ˁašǝr čēl mīye w-ˁišrīn dönem mīye, ad-dönem iṯnaˁaš dönem čēl nsammī b-al-ˁarab, čēl ᵊngūl</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a108"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts22" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>čēl gāˁ, čēl ḥunṭa al-ḥunṭa čēl-he mīye  w-arbaˁa w-ṯimānīn kīlōw  b-al… b-ad-dibābi ad… dabbītha aṯ-ṯamantaˁaš līṯər ˀiṯnaˁaš dabbīt ḥunṭa li-ṯummha nčīl-he nsammīhe čēl ˀā, fhimt-ak</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a117"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ˀiṯnaˁaš dabbīt ḥunṭa  nsammī-he čēl ᵊtgul-lu “čam čēl ǧann-ak?” ygūl “mīye čēl ǧā-ni ḥunta ˀal-mīye čēl yisawwi b-al-ḥisāb  il-matematīk  imanṭaˁaš ṭōn w-arbaˁmīt kīlow , al-mīye čēl ṯimanṭaˁaš [ˀalif] w-arbaˁmīt kīlow ᵊtšīl-he b-al-kamyūn yāxuḏ-ha ˁa-l-midīne ˀal-ḥunṭa ybīˁūn-he, al-ˁadas, al-ˁadas čēl-u mītēn kīlow</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a128"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts29">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ˀal-ḥunṭa čēl-he mīye  -arbaˁa w-ṯimānīn kīlow w-aš-šiˁīr  čēl-u mīye w-iṯnēna w-xamsīn kīlow ˀaš-šiˁīr xafīf ˀaš-šiˁīr xafīf čēlu ṯnaˁaš dabbīye čēlu mīye w-iṯnēna w-xamsīn kīlow w-al-ˁadas ˁamanu ṯiǧīl, čēlu mītēn kīlow al-ḥunṭa mīye w-arbaˁa w ṯiamānīn kīlow čēl-he. Zēn? Kwayyis? ,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a139"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts28" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa ˀiḥna nsammī  ngūl lu šōk. Šōk?  Ēh šōk, hāḏa yiṭlaʕ yabanǧı madda hāḏa yiṭuššūn lāzim mā yiqtil-u  -galb ʕadas ma yiṣīr zihīd  ... yiṭlaʕ bə-l-kanār  amma hnāk ma yiṣīr fazla  yiṣīr ba-l-kanār ..... hāḏa ʕušub ngūl lu iḥna ʕušub hāḏa  hāḏa ˀiḥna nsammī šōk , hāḏa ˀaš-šōk hāḏa hnīt-u hāḏi baˁdēn  ᵊtṣīr ᵊb-gaḷb-u mā-dri šakl-e  bī-hum awwali yāklūn-he zād amma ˀiḥna mā-nākul-he yāklūn galb-u</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a155"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts30" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gaḷǝb hāḏe  šwayy yiṣīr guṭma hīčiḏ ḥāmḏ̣e ḥilwa  yāklūn-he, ˀiḥna mā-nākul-he halḥīn yṣīr ṭaraf al-ˁadas  ᵊb-gaḷb al-ˁadas fazla mā yṣīr ˁaman yiṭuššūn ilāč ysawwūn ilačlama  yabanǧi madde mā yṣīr.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a166" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>These are lentils; they seed them in December, or in November. They remain five months like this, four, five months, six months. Then they start to harvest them with reapers. When they are dry. Fifteen days after they have dried, they harvest them with reapers, and they put the straw aside.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a167" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The straw and the lentils are seperated. Their owners take them and sell them at the corn-exchange, at the corn-exchange. They sell them for about… the lentils, we call this (kind) green lentils, they sell them for one Lira per kilo, one Lira for one kilo lentils.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a168" ANNOTATION_REF="a25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The straw is sold for hundred Kuruş, (no) ten Kuruş – ten Kuruş – ten Kuruş which means ten kilos for one Lira, the straw. As for the lentils they take them to factories where they break them into two pieces. Then one kilo costs one million [= one Lira]; they take remove the hull, the remove the hull and then one kilo costs two million.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
