<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2022-08-25T17:10:30+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Y:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa/2010-Mai-10-12/Urfa-098_Young_Woman-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:479c2c2c-212e-41eb-9f2a-011d6f563766</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">26</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="44830"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="76165"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="76178"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="115000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="115000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="139542"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="139542"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="180000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="180000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="207526"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="207526"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="229894"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāl hiyye šaṛṛābit titin yā xū-ye w nahāṛ  ᵊmxallṣa titin mā ˁid-he čigāṛa w ǧāˁde b-al-lēl w mǝštamma rīḥt ad-duxxān, rīḥt ad-duxxān. ˁa-l-buˁud mǝštammit-he.  w ˁa-r-rīḥa rāyḥe, al-maṛa yōm-in-he rāyḥe ˁa-r-rīḥe w lāǧīt-hum ᵊzlimtēn ǧāˁdīn: salām!  ˁalē-kum as-salām! </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyle “ˀaxūye axū-y! āni ǧīt arīd lī siqāṛa. sikāre” (gāḏ̣be) gāḏ̣ib w mǝnṭī-ha siqāṛa.  w huwwa ˁadu abū-ha, ˁadu ˁamm-he. – düšmān ˁamm-he – ē, ˁadu ˁamm-he b-al-ˁarab.  ˁašgān-he ḥābbitt-u w ḥābb h-al-bint.  gāḏ̣be ǧāye ˁa-l-bēt yōm-in-he ǧāye ˁa-l-bēt, ˀugḏ̣ubi w qabbi l-ᵊghawa! </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w qabbi at-titin w qabbi ač-čāy. ᵊmqabbīthin qabbīt-hin mā-miš ǧāyīn xuṭṭār ˁala ˁamm-he. ē, al-xuṭṭār yirīdūn al-ᵊghawa w-al-ˁarab awwali balāy b-lēy l-ᵊghawat al-muṛṛa mā-ṣṣīr, alli ghawt-in murra, alli ghawt-in murra. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a13"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“wali yā bint-i” gāyil “ᵊghawa mā-min?” gāyilt-illu “mā-min titin mā-min” gāyle, “alli ᵊb-šarṭ  tinṭī-ni lil [lal?] az-zlimt al aṭǝlb-u āni!” gāyil: “gūli! ṭalabt-ič ǝnṭēt-ič, ṭalabt-ič marra ṯānye ˀǝnṭēt-ič  ṭalabt-ič ṯālṯe inṭēt-ič. w-iḥna l-ˁarab gōlit ǝnṭētič xalāṣ! mingāḷ “ˀǝnṭēt, tamām!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a17"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts8" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“mā-yḏ̣all warā-ha suwālif, yēlōn al-qamīṣ”.  gāyle “yā ˁamm yā Waṭbān”, hū ˀism-u Waṭbān ˁamm-he.  “šaffi ᵊxlāfi, šaffi xalaf minwit al-gōm al-miǧāfi Xalaf Xalaf b-al-gēḏ̣ nafnūf w b-aš-šitē dāfi. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts10" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE/>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a22" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>It is said that (there was a young woman) who was a heavy smoker. One day she stopped smoking and did not have cigarettes. At night she was sitting when she smelled the smell of smoke, the smell of smoke. From far away she smelled it. She went to the direction of the smell and found two men sitting. “Hello!” – “Hello to you!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23" ANNOTATION_REF="a6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>She said, “My brother! I came because I want a cigarette.” He took a cigarette and gave it to her. But he was the enemy of her father, the enemy of her uncle. – The foe of her uncle. – Yes, her uncle’s enemy as we say in Arabic. He fell in love with her. She loved him and he loved the girl. When she came back home. Take the coffee and hide it!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a24" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And hide the tobacco and hide the tea. She hid all this and so it was not available. Then guests came to her uncle. Yes, and the guests wanted to have coffee. In former times, among the Arabs, nothing happened without bitter coffee, without bitter coffee.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25" ANNOTATION_REF="a13">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “My daughter. is there no coffee?” She said to him, “There is none, and there is no tobacco too.” Then she said, “Except on condition of giving me to the man whom I want (to marry)!” He said, “Listen, they asked for your hand and I gave you to them, they asked a second time and I gave you to them, and they asked a third time and I gave you to them. And when we Arabs say, ‘I have given you to them’, then it’s finished. After it has been said ‘I have given’ it’s over.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a26" ANNOTATION_REF="a17">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>After that no talking around remains, as clear as the color of the shirt?” She said, “O my uncle, o Waṭbān!” The name of her uncle was Waṭbān. “My lips do not lie /solve my matter or make my matter easier; my lips aim is Xalaf _consider Xalaf from the tribe al-Miǧāfī? Xalaf, Xalaf who smells good in summer and who is warm in winter.” </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
