<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-01-16T13:05:52+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-024_Vegetabels_and_Seasonal_Work-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:93dbad3e-d982-4235-a7ff-d5de8c64944c</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">216</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="69183"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="93060"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="93060"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="105672"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="105683"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="119020"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="119030"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="134591"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="134601"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="151805"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="151815"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="167152"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="167162"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="178662"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="178663"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="206743"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="206754"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="215121"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="215131"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="236111"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="236121"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="253989"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="253989"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="267070"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="267080"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="282887"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="282897"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="302499"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="302510"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="316121"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="316122"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="330714"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="330714"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="348979"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="348979"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="362989"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="362999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="383203"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts39" TIME_VALUE="383203"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts40" TIME_VALUE="408203"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts41" TIME_VALUE="408203"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts42" TIME_VALUE="430560"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts43" TIME_VALUE="430570"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts44" TIME_VALUE="446652"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts45" TIME_VALUE="446653"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts46" TIME_VALUE="467173"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts47" TIME_VALUE="467173"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts48" TIME_VALUE="481030"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hēne ʕid-na b-dīrit Ḥarrān, b-al-gaṛāye al mā ʕind-u gāʕ, al-gāʕ mā ʕind-u gāʕ milič ta-ngūl arāḏ̣i, mā ʕind-u yimkin ba… mū kull-he ʕid-he bī-hum mā ʕid-hum. al mā ʕind-u gāʕ yirkabūn b-al-ato.. b-al-qamyūnāt yrūḥūn ʕal Anqaṛa yištaġlūn b-al-panǧar yiduggūn qazma, qazma qara qazması nsammī-ha qazma.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a32"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts2" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yiduggūn al-… yihawwūn al… al-panǧaṛ yirūḥūn b-al-qamyōnāt b-al-qamyōnāt yōm-in yirūḥūn ʕa-ṭ-ṭarīg yisawwūn qaza, al-qamyūn yōm-in yinǧilib yimūtūn ṯalāṯīn arbaʕīn wāḥad. huṃṃa w ʕaǧāwīn-hum.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a37"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-ʕaskarīye, aǧ-ǧandarma mā txallī-hum yirūḥūn b-al-qamyūnāt ᵊtgul-lhum “rūḥu b-al-atabōsāt!” b-al-otobīs b-al-bāṣ as-Sūrīyīn ysammūn bāṣ iḥna ngūl atabōs. yirūḥūn b-al-atabōs, al-atabōs daha güvenliy, daha emniyetliy.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a43"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>awwal aǧ-ǧandarma mwaqqif-hum ʕa-d-darib w-ǧaʕ-ynazzil ummāʕīn-hum m-al-qamyūn ygūl-lhum “rūḥu b-al-atabōs!” al yrūḥūn ʕa-l-panǧaṛ il ʕēlit-u xamsa sitte ʕašṛa yištaġlūn. ʕumr-u m-al-ʕašṛa fōg iṯnaʕaš ṯilaṭaʕaš sine, bnayyāt wala wēlād mā yufrug.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a50"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yduggūn qazma yāxḏūn yōmiyye ʕišrīn ṯalāṯīn malyūn, lēṛa, al-wāḥad al-ʕēle čam wāḥad yištaġlūn ʕašṛa yōmīt-hum mītēn waraga mītēn w-xamsīn ʕala mǝṭraḥ aš-šuġul, aš-šuġul yōm-in šuġul kaṯīr w-māmiš ḥade al-yōmiyye qālye.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a57"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in šuġul māmiš w-mille čiṯīr al-yōmiyye tigaʕ [tigaḥ], tinzil. bēn al-ʕišrīn wa-ṯalāṯīn tilʕab (al-)yōmīt ar-rās al-ādami, al-farid. ᵊmn-aṣ-ṣubuḥ l-al-maġrib, iḏ̣a min tuṭluʕ aš-šamis lummun-ma tġīb aš-šamis yḏ̣all ydugg qazme.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a64"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕa-ḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur yākul akil sāʕa zimān mōḷa baʕdēn uxra ydugg qazme, yduggūn yištaġlūn arbaʕ tušhur xamis tušhur yaʕni yōm olaraq mīye w-ʕišrīn mīye w-xamsīn yōm yištaġlūn.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a69"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-bēt an-normāl al-bēt al ʕind-u xamis ʕāylāt [frād] sitte sabʕe b-bṭāl aš-šuġul yiǧībūn ʕašaṛa ᵊṯnaʕaš xamǝstaʕaš alif lēṛa turki. yiǧībūn yqazniǧūn mǝṣāri. bidūn maṣraf-hum bidūn akil-hum bidūn kullši. Yōm-in yiǧūn hēne kull bēt xamǝstaʕaš alif ʕišrīn alif yiǧīb mǝṣāri il ʕēlt-u, al ʕind-u walad-in lāḥiǧ yǧawwz-u b-al-flūs haḏannīč.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a80"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al mā ʕind-u walad… – w yirǧaʕūn baʕda l-bēt? – yiǧūn ʕala bēt-hum haḏōl, yiǧūn ʕugub, baʕad xamǝs tušhur miyye w-xamsīn yōm yirǧaʕūn ʕala byūt-hum. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a84"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>baʕad-ma yirǧaʕūn ʕala byūt-hum hēne ʕād ydaššin šunhu ydaššin ʕād b-Urfa b-Ḥarrān? ydaššin ḥōš [ḥawš] al-guṭun, ygūmūn yḥūšūn guṭun ʕād haḏōle yōm-in yirǧaʕūn. yḥūšūn al-guṭun al-kīlow ǟǟǟ b-ʕišrīn ǧiriš – b-ʕišrīn ǧiriš – ē, al-xamǝs kīlawāt b-lēṛa. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a91"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>rās al-ādami – ǧilīl – ē, rās al-ādami l-al-maġrib yiḥūš miyyit kīlo guṭun in ṣār ḥābūb yištaġil ḥābūb yaʕni ḥābūb tʕarif ḥābūb? çalışkan yaʕni. l-al-maġrib yimli bandač guṭun taġrīban imyit kīlow iḥna ngūl, ʕišrīn lēṛa yōmīt-u [yōwmītu]. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a98"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts22" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕa-l-ʕēle ʕād, amma hēne mǝṣraf mā-l-hum čünkü bēt-u ġādi w-yiǧi hēne ḥōš guṭun imyitēn mitr ʕan bēt-u, lā yinṭi ḥagg darib lā yinṭi ḥagg atabōs lā yinṭi ḥagg ačil. ᵊb-ǧarīt-u yištáġil zād šahrēn yḥūšūn guṭun. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a103"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-bēt al-ḥabūb al yištaġil yiḥūš ʕišrīn ṯalāṯīn ṭōn guṭun. zād yṣīr-lu xamǝs sitt ālāf līra. baʕad-ma yāxḏūn ᵊflūs-hum al-mǝṣāri al yḥūš al-guṭun yāxḏūn ḏaxīrit-hum. ḥunṭa yāxḏūn ʕa-l-bēt xams ᵊmīt kīlow. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a109"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yāxḏūn samin, arbaʕ xamǝs dibābi tanak ṯimanṭaʕaš litar, ayčiček yaġi iḥna nsammī-´ w-yāxḏūn sukkar čāy miyyit kīlow, w-yāxḏūn čāy ʕašǝr kīlawāt, yāxḏūn xamǝs ṭōrbāt sitt ʕalāyiǧ mīt kīlo burġul ʕēš, mīt kīlo burġul čīga nsammī-´ čīy köfte ysawwūn. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a117"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts29" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ḏaxǝrt-u b-al-bēt b-aš-štē, al yākul-he kull-he b-aǧ-ǧumle yāxuḏ-hum, ᵊb-nōba wəḥde, kull-he yḥuṭṭ-ha b-al-bēt. alif lēṛa, alfēn lēṛa yḥuṭṭ ḏaxre. baʕdēn-ma yḥuṭṭ ḏaxǝrt-u ʕād mā yištaġlūn yugǝʕdūn b-aš-štē, b-aš-štē ʕād yugǝʕdūn hēne. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a123"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts31" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts33">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al ʕind-u sayyāra ṭaqṣi w-yigdar yʕarif ysūg yāxḏ-illu ṭ-ṭaqṣi ygūm yrūḥ ʕal Aqčaqala. yiǧīb banzīn ybīʕ yǧīb čāy ybīʕ ysawwi tiǧāra, yōm kull yōm yrūḥ ʕala Sūriyye yḏ̣all-lu xamsīn waraga sittīn waraga miyyit waraga </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a129"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts32" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts35">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>min banzīn al yiǧīb-u, yiǧīb imyit litre banzīn malyūn hēne ybīʕ-u b-malyūnēn. miyyit lēṛa qārow, yqaznič, yǧīb čāy w yǧīb sukkar-u, yǧīb arzāq b-Sūriyye kullši raxīṣ – kullši raxīṣ – kullši raxīṣ, iḥna kullši ʕid-na qāli, iḥna ʕid-na hēne šī qāli. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a135"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts34" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ā šift al-banzīn al-māzōt iḥna b-Urfa b-al-petrōl nāxḏ-u b-ṯaliṯ lēṛāt, šift ᵊb-Tall Abyaḏ̣ ʕamann-u māzōt Sūrīye xaḏēna b-lēṛa w-ṯalāṯīn ǧiriš, yaʕni sabʕīn mīt alif hemen hemen belki lēṛa, arxaṣ min Urfa. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a141"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts37" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts39">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕalēš? ʕamann-u ǧaʕ-yiǧi min Sūriyya. al-banzīn al-liter ᵊb-lērtēn – ᵊb-lērtēn – ᵊb-lērtēn bi-Tall Abyaḏ̣, b-al-petrōl b-Urfa b-ṯalāṯa w-nuṣṣ, lēṛa w-nuṣṣ yufrug farig čiṯīr, ē ʕaman hāḏa ʕaman nāxuḏ al-petrōl min hēne min Tall Abyaḏ̣ yōm-in nāxḏ-u raxīṣ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a149"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts38" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts41">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>as-sayyārāt hāḏi ngūm nākul min al-xubuz. yaʕni nākul xubuz. in xaḏēna qāli mā yxallī-na xubuz, yaʕni xaḏēna al-gāz, al-māzōt ᵊb-ṯalāṯe, ṯalāṯe w-mītēn ta-ngūl ṯalāṯe w-ʕišrīn ǧiriš ṯaliṯ lērāt. mǝṣārī-ne iḥna Turkiyya iḥna lissaʕ ᵊlsān-ne mitʕallim ʕal malyūn ṯalit malāyīn ᵊngūl ḥatta lissaʕ malyūn, mā ngūl lēṛa ʕallamō-ne awwali ʕal malāyīn.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a159"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts40" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts42">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in ᵊngūl ṯalaṯ malāyīn w-mītēn nāxḏ al-māzōt, mā nqaznič mǝṣāri xōǧa. para mā nqaznič, qār mā yḏ̣all. in xaḏēna l-māzōt raxīṣ yḏ̣all-inna xubuz. iḥna zād Turkiyye ḥāliyla, ᵊtḥuṭṭ vērgi. al-ʕarab ygūlūn ḏ̣arība, iḥna ngūl vērgi. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a169"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts43" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts44">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yḥuṭṭūn vērgi ʕa-l-māzōt, al-vērgi yāxḏūn-u zād uxṛa yraddidūn-u zād ʕalē-na aṣlan zād ḥaggliyye. ysawwūn xizme ṣaġlǝq ysawwūn makātib, madāris, ᵊdrūb, ad-dawle mnēn tiǧīb? tinṭi min ǧēb-he? ti-tāxuḏ minn-i ta-tinṭī-ni, ad-dawle waẓīfit-he māmūr-i.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a176"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts45" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts47">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏi maʕnat ad-dawle gōlt ad-dawle, wa-l-ḥamdilla uxṛa rās… ᵊhnīye as-salāma, aš-šukur iḥna l-ḥamdilla nuškur, nuškur Aḷḷa ngūl zihīd wēya čiṯīr ᵊngūl aš-šukur mā yxalaṣ nḥamad-u nistaḥamad-u ʕala kull ḥāl rabb al-ʕālamīn iš-ma yaʕṭī-ni agūl al-ḥamdu li-llā.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a184"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts46" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-baṭin hāḏiy, al-baṭin al-ādami in ḥaṭṭēt bī-he laḥam zād (ᵊtgūl) mā tgul-lak ʕāfiye. w in ḥaṭṭēt bī-he xubuz mā tgūl ʕāfiye w in ḥaṭṭēt bī-he bēḏinǧān mā tgul-lak iš-ma tḥuṭṭ bī-he tākul, hahaha. šlōn xōǧam?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a193" ANNOTATION_REF="a23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Here with us, in the Plain of Harran, in the villages, (it is like that): The one who does not have land, who has no land, no property, no estates, he cannot… not all of them, but there are people who don’t have it. Those who have no land get on the bus, they get on a truck and go to (the province of) Ankara to work on the turnip fields. They work with a hoe, we call it “black hoe” (in Turkish).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a194" ANNOTATION_REF="a32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They dig up (the soil with a hue) to aerate the turnips; they go there on trucks and when they have an accident on the way, when the truck turns, over thirty or fourty of them die, they (all) together with their children.  </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a195" ANNOTATION_REF="a37">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The army, the police  no longer let them go on trucks, they tell them, “Go with buses!” By bus, bāṣ they say in Syria, but we say atabōs. So, they go on the bus, the bus is more reliable, safer (than the truck).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a196" ANNOTATION_REF="a43">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>First the police started to stop them on the road and let them unload their belongings from the truck telling them, “Go by bus!” As for those who go to work on the turnip fields they are five, six, (up to) ten per family. Above the age of ten, twelve or thirteen they are working, girls and boys alike.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a197" ANNOTATION_REF="a50">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When they work with the hoe their daily wage is ten to thirty million Lira; for one person; a family, according to how many there are working, they (earn) 200 Lira when they are ten. Or 250, it depends on the working place. And if there is a lot of work and no people then the daily wage is high.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a198" ANNOTATION_REF="a57">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>But when there is no work and many people, the daily wage goes down. The daily wage per head fluctuates between twenty and thirty for one person. (They work) from the morning to the sunset. From the time the sun rises until the time the sun goes down they work with the hoe..</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a199" ANNOTATION_REF="a64">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>At noon they eat, there is one hour break then they work again with the hoe. They are working for four or five months, that means in days they work 120 to 150 days.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a200" ANNOTATION_REF="a69">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>A normal family that consists of five, six or seven members take home 10-, 12-, 15,000 Turkish Lira at the end of the season. They earn (this amount of) money except their costs, except their food, except everything. When they come back here, every family brings 15 to 20,000 Lira to their extended family. The one who has an adolescent son will (now) marry him off with that money. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a201" ANNOTATION_REF="a80">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The one who has no son… – Do they return home? – Yes, they return home, after five, six months they return, after hundred or 150 days they come back home.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a202" ANNOTATION_REF="a84">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>After they have come home, what begins here in Urfa and Harran again? The picking of the cotton begins. So they start to pick cotton when they have come back. They pick cotton and they get 20 Kuruş for one kilo. – 20 Kuruş – Yes, that means 1 Lira for five kilos.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a203" ANNOTATION_REF="a91">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Each person – This is little. – Yes. Until sunset they pick hundred kilos of cotton per head. If one is diligent, if one works a lot. You know the word ḥābūb, don’t you? It means çalışkan (in Turkish). Until the sunset each person fills one large sack of cotton, let’s say approximately hundred kilos and he gets 20 Lira as his daily wage.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a204" ANNOTATION_REF="a98">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>For the family is… but here they do not have expenses, because his house is over there and he comes here for picking the cotton, just two hundred meters from his house. He does not have to pay for the journey, nor does he have to pay for the bus, nor for the food. Another two months he picks cotton in his village.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a205" ANNOTATION_REF="a103">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>A hardworking family picks twenty to thirty tons of cotton. So they get five to six thousand Lira. After they have got their money, those who have picked cotton take their winter stock. They bring five hundred kilos of wheat home.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a206" ANNOTATION_REF="a109">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They take ghee, four or five canisters, eighteen litres of sunflower oil as we say. They also take hundred kilo sugar for tea, ten kilo tea, and five or six sacks, that is hundred kilo, of coarse bulgur and hundred kilo of fine bulgur to make çiğ köfte.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a207" ANNOTATION_REF="a117">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>So they have stock at home for the winter. They buy everything that they eat (in winter) all at once and put it in the house. They spend 1,000 or 2,000 Lira for the winter stock. After they have laid in the winter stock they do not work any more, they just stay here for the whole winter.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a208" ANNOTATION_REF="a123">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The one who owns a car, a motor, the one who knows to drive, he takes a car and goes to Akçakale. He brings petrol to sell it and he brings tea to sell it that means he works in trading. Every day he goes to Syria and every day fifty, sixty or hundred Lira remain for him;</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a209" ANNOTATION_REF="a129">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>From the petrol he brings (from Syria). When he brings hundred litres (which he has bought) for one million he sells it here for two millions. This makes hundred Lira profit. He brings tea, he brings sugar, he brings foodstuff because in Syria everything is cheap – Everything is cheap – everything is cheap there but here with us it is expensive.  No matter what here it is expensive. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a210" ANNOTATION_REF="a135">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>You saw that we bought the petrol, the diesel from the filling station for three Lira. And you saw that in Tall Abyaḏ̣  we bought it for one Lira and 30 Kuruş, because it is diesel from Syria. That means it is 70,000 (old Liras) or even one (new) Lira cheaper than in Urfa. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a211" ANNOTATION_REF="a141">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Why? Because it comes from Syria. One litre petrol is two Lira – two Lira – two Lira in Tall Abyaḏ̣ but at the filling station in Urfa it cost three and a half. One and a half Lira makes a big difference. Yes, and therefore we bought the petrol from here, from Tall Abyaḏ̣, as it is cheap.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a212" ANNOTATION_REF="a149">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>These cars, we start to eat bread of them, we eat bread. If we buy (the petrol) expensive no bread is left for us. This means, if we buy the petrol and the diesel for 3.20, let’s say three Lira and 20 Kuruş. We are still used to count our Turkish money in millions, we still say three millions, or we say one million instead of one Lira because we have got used to it from former times.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a213" ANNOTATION_REF="a159">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When we pay 3 million and 200 for the diesel we don’t earn money and there remains no profit. If we buy the diesel for a cheap price then some bread remains for us. Moreover, here in Turkey (the government) imposes a tax. The Arabs say ḏ̣arība but we say vērgi for tax.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a214" ANNOTATION_REF="a169">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They impose a tax on the diesel. They take a tax but on the other hand they also give it back to us, so it is fair (that they take taxes). They install public health services, they erect schools and roads. From where else should the government bring this? Should it give all that from its pockets? They take it from me to give it to me, this is the government’s duty, (it is) my civil servant.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a215" ANNOTATION_REF="a176">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>This is the meaning of government, the sense (of the word) government. Thank God there is also safeness; we thank God a lot for this. We thank God for it, may it be little or may it be much, we express our thanks to God, we do not stop praising the Lord of the Worlds. Whatever he gives me I say thanks to God.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a216" ANNOTATION_REF="a184">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>This stomach here, the stomach of a human; if you put more meat in it, it does not say thanks. And if you put bread in it, it does not say thanks, and if you put aubergines in it either. Whatever you put in it, it just eats it, hahaha.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
