<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-01-16T13:26:55+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa/2010/2010-Mai-08-09/Urfa-077_Jinn-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:bf4faf39-b494-4880-b1ff-09fea84a8d3e</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">12</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="238564"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="238564"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="261111"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="261111"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="261138"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="261138"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="285115"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="285115"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="285138"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="285138"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="308650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="308650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="308650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="308650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="326347"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="326347"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="326371"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="326371"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="346883"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="346883"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="346930"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="346930"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="360511"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="360511"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>alḥaz iḥne ʕiǧyān ᵊzġār kull ʕaǧi-n ziġīr nḥuṭṭ-ill-u gāma, gāma, āyat al-kursi ngūl, musqa, ᵊnḥuṭṭ-ha mā nxāf hīč, al-ǧinn minn as-saʕālwa mā yitigallaṭan ʕalē-k. āni, inte sōlif, āni ǧan-ni hēne b-al-bēt hēne – b-al-bēt hēne? – b-al-bēt hēne šu-ygūlū-l-u haḏāk aaa… – sukun? – lā mū as-sukun.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a2"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>abu al-lubēd? – abu lubēd, ism-u huwwa – karabasan – karabasan b-at-turuk yigūlūn karabasan. yōm-in ᵊtnām ylabbit fōg-ak b-al-ʕarabiyye abu lubēd hā abu lubēd ṣǝʕlu yōm-in al-wāḥad nāyim, āni nōbtēn ṣār ʕalay-ye. ḥatta ṯalāṯe, ṯalaṯ nōbāt ṣār ʕalay-ye, āni nāyim hēne b-ad-dār haḏiyye nāyim, </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a3"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w b-al-lēl w čān yiǧi w yubruk fōg-i, gǝḏ̣ab-ni kull wuǧūd-i kull wuǧūd-i haš-šakil hāḏa gǝḏ̣ab-ni. mā agdar agūl mā agdar asōlif, ᵊb-nōba! arīd aṣīḥ mā agdar gāḏ̣ib ᵊlsān-i w gāḏ̣ib-ni haš-šakil mā agdar altabǝṭ. hā w gimit ʕādēne b… b-rās ᵊlsān-i gimit agṛa āyat al-kursi. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a4"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>grēt āyat al-kursi gǝḏ̣at āyat al-kursi w huwwa čān yrūḥ ʕin-ni nōbtēn haḏanne hēne ṣāru ʕalay-ye w nōba zād ᵊb-qēr mǝṭraḥ. yiǧi haš-šakil hāḏe ā hīčiḏ yugḏ̣ub-ak, ᵊtfukk ʕēn-ak, mā ššūf-u. amma inte magḏ̣ūb lā tgūl hīčiḏ lā tigdar ᵊtgūl hīčiḏ. lā tigdar ᵊssōlif lā tigdar ᵊtfukk ʕēn-ak – ḥiss-ak mā yuṭluʕ. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>lā tigdar … ᵊb-nōba. hīčiḏ hīčiḏ ǧimad-ak – bass mā šift-u? – mā ššūf, mā ššūf-u,  huwwa yčalliṭ ʕalē-k yčalliṭ ʕalē-k abu lubēd, iḥna nsammī-´ abu lubēd. yaʕni ḥiss-ak ᵊtḥasib ḥāl-ak ǧaʕad ᵊṣṣīḥ amma ḥiss-ak māmiš mā yrūḥ. aṣīḥ mā yuṭluʕ ḥiss māmin. ba-t-tāli yōm-in ydaššr-ak ʕād yrūḥ ʕād ḥiss-ak inte tizgaḥ ḥiss-ak ʕād yuṭluʕ, al yamm-ak ʕād yismaʕ-ak ygūm ygūl ᵊš-bī-k?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>āni ṯalaṯ nōbāt ṣār ʕalay-ye, ṯalaṯ nōbāt, ā hēne b-al-bēt gǝḏ̣ab-ni haš-šakil hāḏa mā_gdar atimalmal ᵊb-nōba, arīd asōlif mā_gdar. arīd ᵊhniyye gāḏ̣ib-ni min iṯmu-y min ᵊlsān-i min wuǧūd-i haš-šakil hāḏe. –</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts2" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Now, when we have small children, we put an amulet on every small child; an amulet, let’s say (with) the Verse of the Throne, an amulett, we stick it in order that we are not afraid, (because) the demons or whatever,  the saʕālwa do not approach you. As for me, you may talk,  they came to me. Here into the house. – Into this house here? – Into this house here, how do they call them… sukun? – No, not sukun.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Abū al-Lubēd? – Abū Lubēd is his name. – karabasan – In Turkish they say karabasan (=nightmare). He rides on you when you are sleeping. In Arabic it is called Abū Lubēd , which is also a demon that comes when you are sleeping. He came over me twice, in fact even three times, while I was sleeping in the house, in this house. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts10" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He came and sat on me at night. He grabbed all of me, my whole body. He grabbed my body like this. I could not speak or talk at all! I wanted to scream, but I couldn’t, because he was holding my tongue and my body so I could not move. Then I started to recite the Verse of the Throne with the tip of my tongue.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts14" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>I recited the Verse of the Throne, and by the time I finished the recitation, he (the demon) went away. It happened to me twice here and once in another place. He comes like that and grabs you. When you open your eyes, you do not see him. You are held by him, so you cannot say anything. You can not talk or open your eyes ¬¬– your voice does not come out.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a11"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts18" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>You cannot... not at all. He freezes you like that. – But you don’t see him? – You don’t see, you not see him. Abu Lubēd locks you; we call him Abū Lubēd. I mean your voice; you think that you are screaming, but your voice does not come out. You scream, but no sound comes out. Eventually, when he leaves you; when he goes away, you shout and then your voice comes out. So the person next to you hears you and asks you, “What’s wrong with you?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a12"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts22" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>As for me he came over me thrice, three times. Here in the house he grabbed me like this. I could not budge at all and when I wanted to speak I couldn’t. I wanted to speak but he kept shut my mouth, he grabbed my tongue and my body like this.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
