<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2023-09-08T15:22:38+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa/2010/2010-Mai-08-09/Urfa-077_Jinn-Harran-2010.wav"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="../../../Recordings/Urfa/2010/2010-Mai-08-09/Urfa-077_Jinn-Harran-2010.wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:d7146ab8-9aec-4080-b7ae-f58bae2ee1dd</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">34</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="558083"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="558083"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="587857"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="587857"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="587867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="587867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="602792"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="602792"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="602810"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="602810"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="619150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="619150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="619150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="619150"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="636419"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="636419"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="636419"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="636419"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="660263"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="660263"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="660263"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="660263"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="674508"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="674508"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="674527"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="674527"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="690961"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="690961"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="690962"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="690962"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="714452"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="714452"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="714471"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="714471"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="740184"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="740184"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="740225"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="740225"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts39" TIME_VALUE="759867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts40" TIME_VALUE="759867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts41" TIME_VALUE="759867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts42" TIME_VALUE="759867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts43" TIME_VALUE="777093"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts44" TIME_VALUE="777093"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts45" TIME_VALUE="777093"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts46" TIME_VALUE="777093"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts47" TIME_VALUE="797074"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts48" TIME_VALUE="797074"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts49" TIME_VALUE="797093"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts50" TIME_VALUE="797093"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts51" TIME_VALUE="811188"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts52" TIME_VALUE="811188"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts53" TIME_VALUE="811188"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts54" TIME_VALUE="811188"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts55" TIME_VALUE="826867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts56" TIME_VALUE="826867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts57" TIME_VALUE="826867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts58" TIME_VALUE="826867"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts59" TIME_VALUE="846131"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts60" TIME_VALUE="846131"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts61" TIME_VALUE="846131"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts62" TIME_VALUE="846131"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts63" TIME_VALUE="861169"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts64" TIME_VALUE="861169"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts65" TIME_VALUE="861202"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts66" TIME_VALUE="861202"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts67" TIME_VALUE="894843"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts68" TIME_VALUE="894843"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>wāḥad min gaṛāyib-ne ᵊngul-l-u as-sǝʕlu, – min gadd-ma s-saʕālwa yuṭluʕin-ill-u [ʕalē-´]. – insān min gadd-ma yšūf saʕālwa – sammō-´ s-sǝʕlu – as-sǝʕlu huwwa ḏābiḥ wāḥad ᵊmn-as-saʕālwa, kātil… mindamī-l-hum, w šāmiṭ as-s… ᵊtfungt-u ḏ̣ārib-u w mayyit, as-sǝʕlu mayyit. a… ʕu… ʕugub-ma māt ygūl ha-n-nōb gāmaw yquččūn-ni – dāwamlǝ yquččūn-u – ygūl āni b-al-bēt arīd aṭluʕ ba… b-ač-čōl yigūl ašūf-hum b-ač-čōl wāǧfīn ašūf-hum yigūl bass huwwa yšūf-hum.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a2"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ygūl ᵊbsāgt-i min yḥuṭṭūn-i bēnāt-hum, ygūl amši bēnāt-hum min xōf-i ytikāwanūn kōn. ygūl ḏ̣allēt ṯalāṯ arbaʕ ᵊsnīn hīčiḏ. āni w-huṃṃa devām kōn min nuṭluʕ al-xāli hīčiḏ awwali māmin tuwāle. yuṭluʕ ʕa-l-xāli hīčiḏ ʕa-l-gāʕa yirūḥ ʕa-č-čōl, ʕa-t-tuwāle. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a3"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yigūl min aṭluʕ hīčiḏ ygūl yuguṭʕū-l-i ygūl yṣīr nfāʕiš b-al-ʕaṣīy b-al-ᵊhniyye ygūl al-milli tdaḥḥǧ-ill-i āni ǧaʕad afaʕʕiš ḥade maḥḥad yšūf-hum haḏōlak mā yšūfūn-hum – ī – lumminn-u-ma rāḥ rāḥ ʕa-l-ḥiǧǧ rāḥ ʕala dǝxal an-nabi ʕala gabr ar-rasūl, ʕala gabr ar-rasūl ǝxlǝṣ</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a4"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>alḥaz yšūfūn-u yinhazmūn ʕinn-u. gāḷ yā rasūl Aḷḷa daxīl-ak min-hum xalliṣ-ni aw min ḥaǧǧ-u dǝxal ʕa-r-rasūl ʕalēt aṣ-ṣalāt w-as-salām mā ʕād yiǧūn-u, ᵊtrikō-´. ḥaǧǧ yaʕni [ma] – as-saʕālwa hēne čiṯīr ᵊbyūt al b-al-midīne b-lᵊbyūt yšūfūn hniyye, </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>amma mū kull ʕala ḥade yaʕni. mū kull ʕala ḥade yšūfūn baʕaḏ̣ nās yiǧūn-hum. yiǧi b-šakil insān ᵊb-šakil ḥīwān, ī, b-šakil al-ḥīwān yiǧi, b-šakil al-insān yiǧi. – iḥna ʕād Ibrāhīm ysōlif yōm-in nuṭluʕ b-ač-čōl b-al-lēl ta-ngūl ᵊnrīd nuṭluʕ baṛṛa, nfukk al-bāb yōm-in ᵊnmidd xuṭwuṭ-ne nsammi bismilla. yōm-in ᵊnsammi bismilla mā itigallaṭūn</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yibʕidūn yaʕni baʕaḏ̣-hum ʕalēš, yigūl, al-misǧane yōm-in tiǧī-he w-tdūs-he hīčiḏ ᵊb-qēr-ma tsammi. ḏīč as-sāʕa tdūs-hum humma fōg al-misǧane yilʕabūn. alḥaz humma ʕala iḥna inanǧ-na islāmiyye. aslam b-ad-dinye ḏiyye#</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts27">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>as-saʕālwa iḥna mā nšūf-hum. humma yšūfūn-na hāḏa maktūb b-al-qurʔān b-al-āxir iḥna nšūf-hum humma mā yšūfūn-na. rabb al-ʕālamīn yirīd ysāwī-´ b-at-ters. hā hēne ʕalē-ne alḥaz kull mǝṭraḥ šī ᵊǧnūn hēne alḥaz ʕid-ne šīy. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts29" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ygūl rabb al-ʕālamīn kull insān, inte zād āni zād kull insān luwwa min ǧiddām-u mḥāfaḏ̣e malak yigūl al-malak yigūl yōm-inn-u al-insān inte alḥaz yōm-inn-ak timši al-malak ǧiddām-ak ygūl yfukk-ill-ak darib ʕin-hum tā ma tiḏ̣rub-hum hā inte ʕādēne miṯil-ma gāḷ Ismāʕīl b-aslāmiyye kull xuṭwa tsammi bismilla. axāf inn-ak ᵊtdūs ʕaǧiyy-u</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts35">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>axāf inn-ak ᵊtdūs-u ygūl samm bismilla mā-yṣīr šī – mā tdūs-u. mā tidḥam-u –  amma in dəst-u ha-n-nōb yinšab-ill-ak –  mā ydaššr-ak – hā al-qayrimüslüm mā yigbal, iḥna islamiyye nigbal haḏiyye, haḏiyye čünkü yaqīn alḥaz as-saʕālwa šī ᵊǧnūn šīy. wa… yʕarfūn ašqāl al-māḏ̣iyyāt al-awwali ṣāyir aǧ-ǧinn yʕarif w yʕallim al-insān </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts37" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts40">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>amma al-miǧbil mā yʕarif, yʕarif bass ʕa aṣ-ṣāyir, alḥaz šī baʕaḏ̣ xawāǧi ysōlfūn aǧ-ǧnūn, ygūlūn ḏ̣āyʕ-il-ne ḏahab ilg-u! ilg-u! ygūl aṣ-ṣǝʕlu yʕallm-u. ygūl b-ᵊflān mǝṭraḥ b-ᵊflān mǝgṭaʕ. ygūl āni arīd al-xōǧe, aṣṣōb al-xōǧe? </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a11"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts41" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts44">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>āni ǧirēt ʕala rās-i āni šifit saʕalit xōǧe gilit ʕind Yāsīn al-Aḥmad, ē gilt-ill-u wald ʕamm-i āni b-Avrūpa aṣṣōb-u ʕallim-ni! midām-in yʕarif al-ǧinn hāḏa as-saʕālwa w-čān yisʕal-u w-ygūl b-al-Almānye. gilit lā wald ʕamm-i b-Holanda šnōn Almānya? </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a12"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts45" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts47">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ṯāni nahār saʕalit axū-´ win ygūl ṣār-l-u xamǝs tiyyām b-Almānye. ṣihīḥ, yaʕni iḥna nisʕal ʕin ibin ʕamm-ne. ygūl Ibrāhīm isʕal aǧ-ǧinn ʕind-inn-u yʕarif ibin ʕamm-i aṣṣōb-u. gāyil w… win ygūl ibn ʕamm-ak b-Avrupa yaʕni iḥna ginnā-l-u (~gulnā-lu) b-Avrupa yištaġil gāḷ b-hay ᵊb-ha-iš dawla yištaġil, gāḷ ibin ʕamm-ak halḥīn b-Almānye,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a13"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts49" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts51">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>b-Almānye. iḥna ibin ʕamm-ne b-Hōlanda ṣār-l-u xamsa w ʕišrīn sine b-Hōlanda Ibrāhīm gāḷ, lā inte mā tʕarif yaġnīš yāw gāḷ: lā ibn ʕamm-ak b-Almānya. Ibrāhīm ʕād ṯāni nahāṛ gāyil Muṣṭafa al hēne mū al b-Hōlanda. gāyl-l-u yāw albāriḥ saʕalit xōǧe.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts53" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts55">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>saʕal aǧ-ǧnūn kalām-hum, w saʕalit ʕin Yāsīn, yaʕni al qādi zād ism-u Yāsīn, Yāsīn, saʕalt-u gult b-Hōlanda? huwwa ygūl-l-i lā b-Almānye gāyil ī waḷḷa Yāsīn ṣāyir luwwa xamǝs tiyyām ʕid xawāl-u. xāl-u b-Almānya w-ǧāy yzūr xawāl-u. ṣār-l-u xaməs tiyyām b-Almānya.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts57" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts59">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yaʕni yigūl b-Almānya w hāḏa ygūl lā hāḏa mā yʕarif. demek ṣaḥīḥ b-Almānya. – alḥaz as-saʕālwa yʕarfun yuṭluʕun škāl ᵊškāl b-šakil čaḥaš, b-šakil faras b-šakil qanam. b-šakil ʕaniz b-šakil čalib, –mā yiǧi b-sīmt insān baʕaḏ̣ nōbāt – šakil šakil yṣīr, hāḏe mawǧūd.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a16"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts61" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts63">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>amma iḥna mā nʕarif alḥaz yuṭluḥ yitxattam-ne b-al-lēl kidīš ᵊngūl čaḥaš ᵊngūl hāḏa čaḥaš, halbuki belč-inn-u sǝʕlu sǝʕlūwa mā nʕarif. aǧ-ǧinn yaʕni iḥna nsammī-´ sǝʕlu, sǝʕluwwa, as-saʕālwa šakl-in šī, as-saʕālwa</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a17"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts65" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts67">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>šī islām w šīy mūhum islām, raḥmāni var, islām islām müsülman miṯil-na. islām w ši mū islām, qayri islām – raḥmani bir de şeytani var – raḥmāni wa šayṭāni. – alḥaz al islām zāten miṯil-ne mā yiḏ̣irrūn ḥade, – e, zarar olmaz – mā yiǧūn ʕala darib ḥade, mā yxawwfūn ḥade, w-aš-šayṭāni haḏāk yxawwif ᵊbsāgt aš-šayṭān haḏāk – šiyāṭīn – šiyāṭīn, Iblīs ᵊbsāgt Iblīs naʕlatulla ʕalē-´ bsāgt-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a18"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts2" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>One of our relatives, we call him “the demon” because the demons came to him that often. – A man who sees the demons very often… – they call him a demon himself. – The demon (the same guy) is one who has killed one of the demons, a murder… This means he has a blood feud with them. He produced a weapon, he drew his gun and shot at him. So he died, the demon died. “After he has died,” he said, “They start to persue me.” – They always persued him. – He said, “I’m at home, but I want to go outside (of the village) to see them. They are standing outside and he sees them. But only he sees them.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a19"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He says, “They are with me. When they put me among them, I walk with them out of fear and they fight each other.” He says, “I stayed like this for three or four years and there was always fighting. We went to the privy, because formerly there was no toilet. He went out to the privy, just out to the fields, outside to the toilet.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a20"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts10" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He says, “The moment I go out they cut my way and the fight with sticks or whatever starts. The people watch me how I am fighting one of them but no one can see them. Theye don’t see them.” Yes. When he went on pilgrimage, he went to the Prophet’s shrine – to the Prophet’s tomb – to the tomb the Prophet and then he was relieved.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts14" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Now if they see him, they run away from him. –He said: “O prophet of God, I take refuge to you, rid me from them” After his pilgrimage to prophet’s shrine; blessings and peace be upon him; they stopped to come to him. They left him. I mean he went on pilgrimage. – There are a lot of demons here. They also appear in the houses in the city, </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a22"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts18" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>but not to everyone. They do not appear to everyone. They come to some people. The demon comes in human and animal form. Yes, they come in animal and human form. We; while Ibrāhīm is speaking (again polite expression by interrupting); when we go to the outside at night; let’s say when we want to go out; we open the door, and say bismilla when we take our steps to the outside. When we say bismilla, they don’t come close,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts22" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>they go away. I mean, that is why some people say, when you go to the misǧane (restroom?) and step in without saying bismilla; you step on them (the demons) in that moment, they are playing on the misǧane. Since our belief is islamic; according to Islam; In this world </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a24"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts26" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>we don’t see the demons in this life, but they see us. This is written in the Qoran. However, in the afterlife we see them, but they don’t see us. God wants to do it backwards. So here around us; there are demons everywhere; right now for instance they are here with us. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts30" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>God says that every human, even you, even me, every human has in front of him a guardian angel. He says that the human, now for instance you, when you walk, the angel is in front of you opens your path from them, so you don’t hit them. So therefore; as Ismāʕīl said; according to Islam; you should say bismilla with every step you take. I am afraid you will step on his (demon’s) children.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a26"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts34" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>I am afraid you will step on him and so say, “In the name of God” and nothing happens. You don’t step on him. You don’t crush him, but if you step on him, he will come after you and won’t let up on you.” Those, who are not Muslims don’t believe that. But we are Muslims and we believe it because it is true that the saʕālwa and other demons exist. They know the things that have already happened. The demons know them and can tell them to the humans.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a27"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts38" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts39">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>However they don’t know the future, they only know what has happened. For instance, there are some sage men who can talk to the demons. They say to them, “We have lost some gold, find it!” It is said that the demon will tell him saying, “It is in this and that place, at that spot.” One says, “I want (to see) the sage. Where is the sage?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a28"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts42" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts43">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>It happened to me. I saw it. I asked a sage called Yāsīn al-Aḥmad and said to him, “My cousin is in Europe. Where exactly is he, let me know!” As he knows the demons, the saʕālwa, he asked and then he said, “He is in Germany.” I said, “No, my cousin is in Holland, how can he be in Germany?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a29"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts46" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The next day I asked his brother (my cousin’s brother) and he said that he had been in Germany for five days. It was correct! That means we asked about our cousin. Ibrāhīm says, “Ask the demon there, if he knows where our cousin is!” He (the sage) said, “Your cousin is in Europe...” I mean we told him that he was in Europe and that he was working there. He (Ibrāhīm) asked, “In which country does he work?” He answered, “Your cousin is currently in Germany”.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a30"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts50" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts52">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>In Germany, but our cousin works in Holland. He has been in Holland for twenty five years. So, Ibrāhīm said to him, “No, you know nothing. You are wrong.” He said, “No, your cousin is in Germany”. So the next day Ibrāhīm asked Muṣṭafa, the one, who is here, not the one in Holland. He says to him: “Dude, yesterday I asked a sage,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a31"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts54" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts56">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>who asked the demons and talked to them, about Yāsīn.” The one who is there is also called Yāsīn. “I asked him if Yāsīn is in Holland. He said to me no and that he was in Germany.” He (Muṣṭafa) said, “True, actually Yāsīn has been in Germany for five days at his uncles’ place. His uncle is in Germany and he went there to visit his uncles so he has been in Germany for five days.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a32"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts58" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts60">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>That means, he said that he is in Germany and this (Ibrāhīm) said, “No, he does not know”. However, he really was in Germany. The demons – they know – appear in different forms: in the shape of a donkey, a horse, a sheep, a goat, – a dog... Sometimes he doesn’t come in human shape – It appears in different forms, so it is.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a33"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts62" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts64">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>But we don’t know it. For instance, if we come across a beast of burden at night, we would say that is a donkey, but maybe it is a demon. We don’t know. The demons, we call them səʕlu and səʕluwwa (the female); there are two types of saʕālwa: </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a34"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts66" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts68">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Muslim and non-Muslim – there is a blessed type – Muslims, Muslims like us. A Muslim and a non-Muslim – a blessed (from God) one and a cursed one (from Satan) – So the Muslim ones are actually like us. They do not harm anyone. They don’t come in anyone’s path. They don’t scare anyone, but the one from Satan (the evil one), that is the one, who is scary. He is together with the Satan. They are demons. They are with the Devil; may God’s curse be upon him. They are with him. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
