<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-01-17T15:00:20+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-011_Cemetry-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:9521bbf3-2e1e-489c-8294-8f676ade67ac</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">64</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="20"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="1140"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="1140"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="21759"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="21759"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="30999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="30999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="42986"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="42986"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="64000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="64026"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="90972"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="90972"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="114998"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="115013"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="140000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="140000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="177999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="178000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="198986"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="198986"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="260013"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="260013"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="325013"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="325039"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="345999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="345999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="421000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="421000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="440999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="440999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="459039"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="459039"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="483000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="483000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="581999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="581999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="605999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts39" TIME_VALUE="605999"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts40" TIME_VALUE="626986"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts41" TIME_VALUE="626986"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts42" TIME_VALUE="642012"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE/>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a2"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa l-ᵊgbūr, al-miǧanne, al-gabǝr, wāḥad ymūt yidfunūn-u hēne, yidfunūn-u yqasslūn-u ʕala ʕurf islām, ʕala ʕādāt uṣūl Islām, yqassl-u, al-xōǧe yqassl-u, w-yǧībūn-u hēne yčaffnūn-u yḥuṭṭūn-u b-al-kefen, čafan – kefen –čafan, ydummūn-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a3"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-gabǝr baʕdēn, ʕugub sabʕ ᵊsnīn yigdarūn yḥuṭṭūn qēr wāḥad bī-´. in mā ṣār sabʕ ᵊsnīn qēr wāḥad mā yḥuṭṭūn. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a4"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ta-ngūl hāḏa, mayyit luwwa sine, al-gabǝr hāḏa mā yiftaḥūn-u – mā yiftaḥūn-u – baʕad sabʕ ᵊsnīn yiftaḥūn-u yigdarūn in māt ḥade in ṣār mayyit uxṛa l-al-ʕēle, kull-min… ta-ngūl alḥaz iḥna … </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>alḥaz qādi nrūḥ gabǝr ǧidd-i, gabǝr ḥabbābt-i ʕamm-i ṯalāṯe mawǧūdīn bi-gabǝr wāḥad, bēnāt-hum sabʕ ᵊsnīn, sabʕ ᵊsnīn yiftaḥūn al-gabǝr, gabl as-sabʕ ᵊsnīn mā yiftaḥūn-u, xaṭiyye yaʕni ygūlūn al-mayyit sabʕ ᵊsnīn mū tāxx hā!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[…] bi-sabʕ ᵊsnīn yidfunūn bī. nahāṛ az-zyārāt iḥna ʕa-l-ᵊgbūr hal-miǧanne akṯar an-nōbāt b-al-ʕīd niǧi b-ʕīd ar-ramaḏ̣ān. w b-ʕīd aḏ̣-ḏ̣aḥiyye fazla maḥḥad yiǧi zihīd. ta-nrūḥ iḥna ʕala miǧannit-na min qādi xōǧam, ʕala miǧannit…gabǝr ǧidd-i ḥabbābt-i, b-al-ʕīd ar-ramaḏ̣ān yiǧūn hēne yigrūn al-yāsīn, yigrūn al…al-fātiḥa.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>bī-hum al-mayyit ǧidīd gabr-u ta-ngūl ḏa… gāl al-mayyit al-ǧidīd, al-ḥabāyib baʕḏ̣-an al-maṛāt yaʕni yibčin, yibčin ʕalē-´ baʕaḏ̣-hin ǧidīd ʕaman walad-he mayyit axū-ha mayyit ygūmin yibčin  ta-ngūl al-bači (b-)al-miǧanne aṣlǝnda ḥarām. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[…] b-arḏ̣-in tibči igir āya, igir duʕa, yibkūn al yibkūn baʕaḏ̣-hum al-yōm walad-u mayyit yibči amma bī ygūl b-arḏ̣-in tibči igir-lu al-ḥamdilla igir-lu l-fātiḥa, igir-ill-u yāsīn, inte w b-xēr-u šaqle, aḥsan m-al-bači, al-bači xaṭiyye hā! </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa, hāḏa gabǝr qāyin bābāt-i āni, abu rāʕit bēt-i, abū-ha. hāḏa māt gabǝḷ… yirmi beš on iki bin altı – arbaʕ ᵊsnīn – ē, arbaʕ ᵊsnīn yimkin ṯalāṯ arbaʕ ᵊsnīn, ē, Aḷḷa yirḥam-u, gāḷ huwwa gabǝr ǧidd wēlād-i, ǧidd banāt-i, ǧidd-hin, hināk gabǝr āni ǧidd-i āni ǧidd-i āni. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hal-kāsāt la-šū? – al-kāsāt haḏanne, ad-dann hāḏa gabǝr Šēx Ibrāhīm, šēx zāt yaʕni, hēne yḥuṭṭūn mayye, yimlūn bī-´ mayye, alḥaz fāḏ̣i  mā bī-´, yiǧūn baʕaḏ̣-hum hēne al-mayye hāḏi b-al-gēḏ̣ yišrabūn min-he ʕala ḥurmit aš-šēx – miššān al-baraka – ē, miššān al-baraka, miššān al… </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a11"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>bī wāḥad waǧʕān yṣīr ʕaǧiyy-in ziġīr mū ʕadil, yiǧūn w-yisgūn-u min gabǝr Šēx Ibrāhīm, min gabr-u hēne. al-miǧanne āni gerče yōm-inn-i xaššēt mā grēt, nigra al-fātiḥa ʕalē-hin, ᵊngūl ṯalǝṯ marrāt ᵊngūl [sūrat al-Ixlāṣ and sūrat al-Fātiḥa] </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a12"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gōlit ṯalǝṯ nōbāt qul huwa aḷḷāhu aḥad al-gabǝr yōm-in tiǧi fōg al-gabǝr xōǧam ta-ngūl fōg al-gabǝr alḥaz, ta-nrūḥ yamm gabǝr ǧidd-i ta-afahhm-ak ṣaġlam. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a13"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>maʕnāt ṯalǝṯ nōbāt qul Aḷḷāhu aḥad ygūlūn al-xawāǧi ygūlūn, baʕdēn tigra l-fātḥe yōm-in ᵊtgūl hīčiḏ, rāʕi l-gabǝr yišūf-ak b-iḏn Aḷḷa, min ǧawwa yšūf-ak b-iḏn Aḷḷa, iḥna yaʕni ngūl yōm-in tigra ṯalǝṯ nōbāt qul Aḷḷāhu aḥad, inte tgūl hadīt-in wāṣla rūḥ al-marḥūm hāḏa, al-fātiḥa, ygūlūn al b-al-gabǝr yišūf-ak.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yišūf yigūl hāḏa Ismāʕīl ǧāʕid yigra ʕala gabr-i al-fātḥe, yigūl yiǧi ʕala…ʕala wuǧūd-u ʕala rūḥ-u, ᵊhniyye serinlik ṯuwāb yaʕni yiǧi ʕala xēr-u, ṯuwāb. […]</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts29" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w ʕugub ḥabbābt-i b-sitt ᵊsnīn, xamǝs sitt sabʕ ᵊsnīn zād, ibin ʕamm abū-yi zād dammō-´ hēne, ibin ʕamm abū-yi, ʕamǧa oġlu babamǝn ʕamǧası oġlu zād dammō-´ hēne, aʕarif-hum āni hēne ṯalāṯa mawǧūdīn: ʕamm-i w ḥabbābt-i w-ibin ʕamm abū-yi – w bēnāt-hum sabʕ ᵊsnīn? –   ē, sabʕ ᵊsnīn, ē sabʕa akṯar … </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a16"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts31" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gabǝḷ as-sabʕ ᵊsnīn al-gabǝr mā yiftaḥ, mā yiftaḥūn-u xōǧam, čünkü ʕalēš yigūlūn lissaʕ al-mayyit al-badan ṣaġlam. amma baʕad sabʕ ᵊsnīn mā yḏ̣all ṣaġlam yiftaḥūn-u yḥuṭṭūn-u l-ᵊʕḏ̣ām b-al-kōše min qādi ʕidd riǧlēn-u, ar-rās min hēne yḥuṭṭūn al-mayyit, rās-u hēne w riǧlēn-u min hināk.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a17"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yiǧabblūn-u hīčiḏ yṣaffḥūn-u, waǧh-u ʕa-ǧ-ǧible yṣaffḥūn-u waǧh-u ʕa-ǧ-ǧible. baʕad sabʕ ᵊsnīn yōm-in tiǧi ḥāliyle al-ḥašarāt tākul-hum al-bani ādam. min yḏ̣all sine ytixx al-badan. az-zēn hāy hū, az-zēn al-ᵊʕmāl, ʕamal, yaʕni al-ādami alḥaz hāḏa l-badan hāḏa trāb, kunna trāb ǧīna m-at-trāb ᵊnrīd ᵊnṣīr at-trāb. amma az-zēna šinhi? az-zēna l-ʕamal.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a18"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>aṣ-ṣāliḥ, al-ḥasanāt al-ʕamal, haḏāk rabb al-ʕālamīn yḥuṭṭ-u b-al-ǧanne. iḥna kunna šuġul-na miššān aǧ-ǧanne, ad-dinya hāḏi bōš, iḥna xuṭṭār – ad-dinya fāniya – fāniya d-dinya, iḥna bī-he xuṭṭār. [...]</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a19"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts37" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hēne ište iḥna ʕadǝn… iḥna l-ʕarab ʕarab Harrān ta-ngūl, akṯar-ha b-al-miyye sittīn sabʕīn ydummūn b-al-hēne  b-aš-Šēx Ḥayā ngūl hēne ngūl-he miǧannit aš-Šēx Yaḥya, aš-Šēx Ḥayāt ibin Qays, Yaḥya, Ḥayā ngūl-lu Ḥayā, Šēx Yaḥya ḥayy – yaʕni hal-makān mubārak – ē, mubārak, huwwa mubārak.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a20"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts39" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts40">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yaʕni niǧi hēne daha, yēlōn yimūt b-Istanbūl yiwaṣṣi yigūl “āni dummū-ni [b-Ḥarrān!]”, iḥna ta-ngūl ᵊʕrubi yēlōn yirūḥ ʕala Stanbūl ta-ngūl marīḏ̣, yirūḥ ysāwi ʕamaliyye ʕa-š-šife xastaxāne yēlōn yimūt b-al-xastaxāne yirtaḥam, yiwaṣṣi ahál-u ygūl “dummū-ni b-aš-Šēx Yaḥya, lā tdummū-ni b-Istanbūl, uxḏū-ni ʕala ahál-i, hēne!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts41" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts42">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā yiqbal ta-ydummūn-u b-Istanbūl, b-Ādane hep ʕaynǝ alla yrīd ʕa-š-Šēx Ḥayā, yiḥutṭūn-u b-al-… b-al… ha-l-atobīs b-at-tābūt yǧībūn-u ī hēne ydummūn-u, ila ʕa-š-Šēx Ḥayā. mā yiqbal ta-yrūḥ ta-ngūl ᵊb-qēr mǝṭraḥ. [...] </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a44" ANNOTATION_REF="a2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>These graves, the graveyard, the grave, when somebody dies, they bury him here, they bury him, they wash him according to the Islamic tradition, according to the tradition of the fundamental rules of Islam; he washes him, the sheikh washes him, then they bring him here, wrap him into the shroud, they put him into the shroud, the shroud, and then they bury him.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a63" ANNOTATION_REF="a3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>After that, seven years later they can again put somebody else into it. If seven years have not passed, they do not put anybody else (into the grave). </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a62" ANNOTATION_REF="a4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Let’s say, if it is only one year ago that one has died, then they do not open it – they do not open it – but after seven years they can if somebody dies, when there is another dead in the family. Everybody…. let’s say, now we…</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a61" ANNOTATION_REF="a5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Now we are going over there, to the grave of my grandfather, to the grave of my grandmother and my uncle. All three are in one grave, but between their (departure) were seven years. (After) seven years they can open the grave, before seven years they don’t open it, it’s a sin, because, so they say, the deceased has not yet rotten before seven years (have passed).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a64" ANNOTATION_REF="a6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>After seven years they (can) bury him in it. Days of the visit to the graves, to the graveyard are during feasts, particularly at the feast at the end of Ramadan. At the Feast of Sacrifice not so much, only a few come. Let’s go over there, my teacher, to our graveyard, to the graveyard, to the grave of my grandfather and grandmother. At the feast at the end of Ramadan people come here and recite the sura Yāsīn, they recite the sura al-Fātiḥa.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a60" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>There are some, when somebody died recently, let’s say he died a short while ago , the women, some of the women are crying over him. Some of them, when somebody died recently, because (for instance) her son or her brother has died (then) they come and cry. But in principle crying on the cemetery is a forbidden (according to religion).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a57" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Instead of crying recite a verse (from the Koran) or say a prayer! There are some who cry when today their son died, but there are those who say, “Instead of crying say for him ‘Praise to God’ or recite the Fātiḥa for him or recite the sura Yāsīn for him. It’s better for you and for him, better than crying, because crying is a sin.” </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a58" ANNOTATION_REF="a9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>This, this is the grave of my father-in-law, the father of my wife, her father. He died on 20 May 2006 – four years – yes, four years ago, maybe three to four years, may God have mercy with him. So this is the grave of my sons’ and my daughters’ grandfather, their grandfather. Over there is the grave of my own grandfather, my grandfather.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a59" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>For what are these cups? – These cups, this jar, belongs to the grave of Sheikh Ibrāhīm, a real sheikh; they put water inside, they (usually) fill it with water, but now it’s empty, there is no water. Some people come here in summer and drink form this water to bestow honour to the sheikh – Because of the blessing? – Yes, because of the blessing, because of the…</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a54" ANNOTATION_REF="a11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>If there is somebody ill, if a small child is not well, then they come and give him to drink (from the water) of Sheikh Ibrahim’s grave, from his grave here. (When entering) a graveyard, actually when I entered, I didn’t do it, we use to recite the Fātiḥa upon them (i.e. the deceased), we pray three times, we say [it follows the recitation of sūrat al-Ixlāṣ and sūrat al-Fātiḥa].</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a56" ANNOTATION_REF="a12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Saying thrice, “Say, God is one!” when you come to the grave, my teacher, let’s say (standing) like now over a grave… let’s go to the grave of my grandfather, there I will explain it to you in detail. [Some prayers follow.]</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a55" ANNOTATION_REF="a13">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The reason for reciting thrice, “Say, God is one!” followed by the Fātiḥa is, so the religious teachers say, that when you do like this, the “owner of the grave” can see you from below. With God’s permission. We say, when you recite three times, “Say, God is one!” then you say this as a kind of present (together with) the Fātiḥa, which reaches the soul of the deceased. They say that the one who is in the grave can see you.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a52" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He looks and says, “This is Ismail he is reciting a Fātiḥa at my grave. It’s said, it (the saying of the prayer) reaches his existence, his soul, and brings coolness and reward, it comes for his deeds, his reward.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a53" ANNOTATION_REF="a15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Five, six, seven years after my grandmother they buried also the cousin of my father here, the cousin of my father, the son of my father’s uncle was buried here. I know of three who are buried here. My uncle, my grandmother, and my father’s cousin. – And between (their departures) are seven years? – Yes, seven years, seven or more…</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a51" ANNOTATION_REF="a16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Earlier than seven years the grave is not opened, they do not open it, my teacher. Why? Because they say, that until then the deceased’s body is still sound. But after seven years it is not intact anymore and then they can open it and they put the bones in one corner next to his feet. They put the head of the deceased from here, his head here and his feet there.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a50" ANNOTATION_REF="a17">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The put him into the direction of Mecca, they put him on one side his face in the direction of Mecca. They put him on one side facing Mecca. After seven years, when you come (and open the grave) the insects have eaten the human body. After a year the body gets rotten. The good thing is the deeds. A human’s body is only dust, we are all dust. We are made of dust, and we will become dust. But what is good? The deeds are good. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a48" ANNOTATION_REF="a18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The sincere (who does) good deeds is the one whom God will bring to Paradise. All our doings are because of the Paradise; this world is empty, and we are only guests. – This world is fading. – Yes, the world is fading, and we are only guests on it.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a49" ANNOTATION_REF="a19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Here, we Arabs, the Arabs of Ḥarrān, most of them, sixty, seventy per cent of them are buried here next to Sheikh Hayat. We say, we call it cemetery of Sheikh Yahya, Sheikh Hayat ibin Qays, Yahya. We call him Ḥayā “life”, because Sheikh Yahya is still alive. – This means, this place is blessed. – Yes, blessed, it is blessed.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a47" ANNOTATION_REF="a20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>We come back here. Even if someone dies in Istanbul he devises, “Bury me in Harran!” Every Arab, when he goes to Istanbul because of an illness, when he goes there to a hospital to have an operation: If he dies, if he passes away in the hospital, he will have instructed his family by will saying, “Bury me at Sheikh Yahya, don’t bury me in Istabul, take me here to my people!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a46" ANNOTATION_REF="a21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He does not accept it to be buried in Istanbul or in Adana. It’s always the same; he wants (to be buried) at Sheikh Hayat. They put him in a bus, inside the coffin, bring him here and bury him here, only at Sheikh Hayat’s place. He will not accept to be taken to another place. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
