<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2023-12-18T18:24:10+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-110_Salim_az-Zir-Harran-2010.wav"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="../../../Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-110_Salim_az-Zir-Harran-2010.wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:15c319b7-8514-464d-8134-29543f85cff6</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">24</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="6933"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="70800"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="70866"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="132199"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="132265"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="157465"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="157466"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="194333"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="194333"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="223400"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="223466"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="242066"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="242066"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="294266"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="294333"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="315932"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="315933"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="355132"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="355133"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="398000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="398133"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="434733"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="434799"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="480190"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>az-Zīr ḏibaḥ ʕiyāl ʕamm-u kull-u ḥarb w maṛt-u, uxt ᵊKlēb an-nōba ahal-he mā ḏ̣all-il-hum gūč ʕalē-´. gāḷō-l-he: ṣīri waǧʕāne ṣīri xasta waǧʕāne w gūli: “al-xōǧe gāḷ-l-i ḥalīb as… as-sabʕa, ḥalīb as-sabiʕ ysāwi šife.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a2"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w maǧbūr yrūḥ ʕala məṭraḥ as-sbāʕ, balči as-sabiʕ yuguḏ̣b-u w yākl-u. ᵊrčib ᵊčḥaš-u w rāḥ ʕala məṭraḥ as-sbāʕ. an-nōb yōm-inn-u rāḥ hināk as-sbāʕ ᵊhǧimin ʕalē-´. hū gəḏ̣ab as-sabiʕ, ḥilab as-sabiʕ w mila ǧ-ǧūd. darrab al-ḥalīb an-nōba. ᵊčḥaš-u čalinn-u as-sabiʕ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a3"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gām yuguḏ̣b-u min as-sbāʕ w yčattif, yuguḏ̣b-u min as-sbāʕ w yčattif. hināk ᵊḏbaḥu axū. ǧā al-xabar, “yā wayli” gāḷ. inte hēne w-ᵊhnāk gāmat aǧ-ǧāme axū-k. yā wayli gāḷ. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a4"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ǝfṭan l-as-sbāʕ hāḏi, āni kull-he čattafit-he w ǧaʕad aḏbaḥ-he miššān ač-čaḥaš. šnōn yiḏbaḥūn axū-y? yā wayli, gāḷ, waḷḷa yiḏbaḥūn. hināk ᵊḏbah-ō-´ yōm-inn-u ǧīy an-nōba axū-´ gāyil: lē ǧīy axū-ye xall-u yḏ̣all yigaf ʕind… gabr-i ygul-l-i tamām alle mū tamām?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ᵊdfin-u b-al-gabər. šgadd-ma yiḏbaḥ min ḏōlak hīčiḏ yiǧi ʕind al-gabər. ygūl: yāzi alle mā yāzi? – ygūl mā yāzi! huwwa ygūl ʕala ḥāl-u: yā wal gāḷ wāḥad min a… aš-šiyāb tā nḥuṭṭ-u b-al-gabər tā hā yingāḷ yāzi alle mā? tā ygūl yāzi, kāfi!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa yōm-inn-u gām yiḏbaḥ, ǧī ʕala l-gabər hāḏa ḥāṭṭīn-u bgaḷb al-gabər. xū-yi, gāḷ: yāzi alle mā yāzi? gāḷ yā wayl yāzi yāzi! ʕǧizne. yā wal, inte ṭayyib? fakk al-gabər hīčiḏ inn-u zād w yiḏbaḥ-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>an-nōb gāḷaw: mā nigdir ᵊntaḥayyal ʕalē-´. ʕalē intīy, ᵊb-šaʕir rās-ič tirbuṭīn [īdē-h], šaʕr ar-rās hāḏa mitīn. guṭṭi šaʕir rās-ič sawwi ḥabil w šiddi īdē-h balčinn-u itičattaf tā niḏbaḥ-u. hiyye čattafatt-u b-al-ᵊmrisi gaʕad gāḷat: tā_šūf ḥēl-ak šnōn-u. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>čattafatt-u b-al-ᵊmrisi mingāḷ hīčiḏ giṭaʕ ʕa-l-ᵊmrisi. čattafatt-u b-at-tēl al-ḥadīd mingāḷ hīčiḏ šnōn-ma čattafatt-u, ᵊṭlaʕat al-ḥabil hāḏa gāḷat tā_šūf hāḏi zād.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>luwatt-u ʕalē-´ luwatt-u ʕalē-´ lummin-ma gāḷat hāy hāḏa šnōn? šnōn-ma gāḷ hīčiḏ, gāḷ hīčiḏ, gāḷ hīčiḏ, laʕ! gāḷat rawwiḥū-l-u huwwa mčattaf. ʕād ǧāw tallafō-´ talāf ᵊb-nōba. tallafō-´ talāf ᵊb-nōba w ǧābaw ṣandūg. ḥaṭṭō-´ b-aṣ-ṣandūg w zattō-´ b-al-baḥar. zattō-´ b-al-baḥar w rāḥ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>haḏōl ad-denizǧiyye yḥūšūn bāliq yṣīdūn bāliq miṯil Isṭambōl yaʕni. hāḏa n-nōba zatt al-ᵊhniyye inn-u ṯiǧīl, yōm-in yisḥab-u hīčiḏ winn-u ṣandūg. sḥab-u aṣ-ṣandūg hināk ᵊṭlaʕō-´ yōm-in ᵊṭlaʕō-´, inn-u hū zlime. ᵊb-tāli yrūḥ! fakkaw aṣ-ṣandūg inn-u flān ǧābō-´ ʕa-l-bēt gāmaw ydāwūn-u. čiṯīr ǧilīl ᵊflān ṭāb. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a11"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>bāšt al-balad ydawwir sāyis l-al-xēl. gāylīn hēne ᵊzlime. čiṯīr ᵊzlimt-in zēn yṣīr sāyis. gāḷ: xall-u yiǧi! ǧābō-´ luwwa w-ṣār sāyis-in l-al-xēl. gām yāxuḏ al-xēl ʕala ǧāl al-baḥar hīčiḏ. yāxuḏ al-xēl ʕala ǧāl al-baḥar w min al-baḥar yuṭluʕ ᵊḥṣān, erkek, al-faras zād ʕāṭi yšabbi l-faras minn-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a12"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>l-al-ḥōl ṣāyir muhra minn-u gāyim yrabbī-he dāyir sine uxṛa yrūḥ hināk uxṛa l-ᵊḥṣān ṭilaʕ uxṛa al-faras šabbā-ha. ǧābat ᵊḥṣān an-nōb. w-rabbā-hin haḏanne lummun-ma ṣār ʕa-l-kēf. ᵊrčib ʕād w naḥar ʕala Klēb w Ǧassās b-ḏ̣ahar al-faras az-zēna hāḏi. taḥārabaw ʕād ḏibaḥ-hum. baʕad hāḏa ḏibaḥ-hum ʕād. mū hēk? </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a13" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>az-Zīr killed the family of his father-in-law, it was all fighting, his wife, the sister of Klēb…one day her family (saw that) they would not have enough strength (to fight) him. So they said to her, “Fall ill, fall sick and ill and say to him, ‘The doctor told me that the milk of a lioness, lion’s milk will make me heal.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14" ANNOTATION_REF="a2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>So he was obliged to go to the place where the lions are. Maybe the lion will grab and eat him (his enemies thought). He mounted his donkey and rode to the place of the lions. As soon as he went there the lions attacked him. He took the lion, milked the lion and filled the vessel. And he sent the milk immediately (to the woman). As for his donkey the lions ate him.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15" ANNOTATION_REF="a3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>So he grasped one of the lions and tied him, he took one of the lions and tied him. (At the same time) there they killed his brother. When the news reached him, he said, “Woe!” You are here and there your brother is in big troubles. “Woe!” he said.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a16" ANNOTATION_REF="a4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Remember that I have tied all those lions and I will kill them because of the donkey. (Asking a passer-by) he said, “How did they kill my brother?” He said, “Look, they really did kill him.” They killed his brother there when he came along and (before dying) he brother said, “When my brother comes he should stay at my grave and ask me, ‘Is it okay or is it not okay?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a17" ANNOTATION_REF="a5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He buried him in the grave. Whenever (lit. as many as) he killed one of them, he came to the grave and said, “Is it enough or is it not enough?” – He responded, “It’s not enough!” So he [viz. Jassas who is the leader of the family who killed Zir’s brother] said to himself, “Let’s put one of the old men into the grave that, when it will be asked again, ‘Is it enough or not?’ he should say, “It’s enough, enough!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a18" ANNOTATION_REF="a6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>So, when he (Zir) killed another one and came to the grave, they had put him (the old man) into it. He said, “My brother, is it enough or not?” He said, “It’s enough, it’s enough! We have our fill’s of it!” Zir said, “Hey, are you alive?” He opened the grave and killed him too.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a19" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Now they said, “We cannot outfox him.” [So they said to one of the women], “Bind him with your hair, your hair is very strong. Cut your hair and make a rope out of it and then tie his hands, maybe, when he is bound, we can kill him.” She tied him with the rope and said, “Let’s see how strong you are!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a20" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>She tied him with the rope (but) he broke the rope like this. So she tied him with an iron wire. As soon as she had tied him, she put the rope on him and said to him, “Let’s see what you can do now!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21" ANNOTATION_REF="a9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>She bound it around him again and again, then she said, “How is this?” As he said, “So!”, he said, “So!” [I can open it]”, but, “No!” [he couldn’t]. She said, “Come here, he is bound.” They came and lambasted him completely. They lambasted him, brought a box, put him inside and threw him into the sea. They put him into the sea and he disappeared.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a22" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Those sailors were catching fish, they were catching fish, like those in Istanbul. This one, he threw this whatnot (i.e. the fishing rod)…it was heavy! When he had pulled it out (he saw) that it was a box. They pulled the box out and when they had hauled it out it turned out to be a man who was about to die. They opened the box, brought him to their homes and started to cure him. Soon he recovered.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23" ANNOTATION_REF="a11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The pasha of that country was looking for a groom for the horses. They said, “Here is a man, a very good man who can become a groom.” He said, “He should come!” They brought him to him and he became a groom for the horses. He took the horses to the shore of the sea; and out of the sea came a stallion, a male horse, the mare wanted to get gravid and so he (Zir) mated the mare with it. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a24" ANNOTATION_REF="a12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>One year later a foal was born and he trained it. After a year he went there again, and the stallion came out again and he mated the mare with it. It bore another foal and he trained them until they have become as he liked it. Finally he mounted it and declaimed against Kleb and Jassas on the back of this good mare. He fought them and killed them. After that he killed them all. Isn’t it like that? </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
