<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2023-08-16T15:28:44+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Y:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-077_Jinn-Harran-2010.wav"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="../../../../Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-077_Jinn-Harran-2010.wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:846e7d1b-a258-4cc1-bd85-8b4637ec6f3e</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">266</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="3710"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="21290"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="21290"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="49485"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="49490"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="68670"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="68670"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="90500"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="90500"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="110470"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="110480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="123270"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="123280"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="138560"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hēne šī, iḥna ngūl as-saʕālwa, as-saʕālwa, yuṭluʕin – suʕluwwa, suʕluwwa ǧǧī-na. b-al-ʕarab ᵊngūl as-suʕluwwa. – as-suʕluwwa hēne. mǝṭāriḥ šī, hināk b-al-lēl riḥit alle tuṭluʕ ʕalē-k. muḥaqqaq tuṭluʕ ʕalē-k ᵊššūf-ak ᵊtxawwf-ak.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yā tinhabil yā tmūt, yā yuktulūn-ak, kesin hāḏi alle yiṣīr, ē – ᵊtgabbib gaḷb-ak, tgabbib gaḷb-ak –  yaʕni amis mesela hēne, čān ʕid-na wāḥad, rabīʕi. huwwa, maṛt-u, ᵊṣṣīr ḥāmil ᵊtḥabil. yōm-in ᵊtḥabil wlēd, ᵊtwaǧǧiʕ ʕa-l-wlēd. yōm-in ᵊtḥabil ʕa-l-wlēd ᵊtwaǧǧʕ-u.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>huwwa mā yṣīr-l-u wlēd. kull-ma tḥabil maṛt-u yṣīr wlēd – baṭin-he ygūmin yiǧin-he b-al-lēl, as-saʕālwa. win ygul-l-i, ǧā-ni win ygul- l-i “hīčiḏ iš-šī ᵊšnōn ᵊnrīd ᵊnsāwi?” han-nōba at-tixātra mā yilgū-lu čāṛa. tugʕud twaǧǧiʕ alle twaǧǧiʕ ṯalāṯ arbaʕ marrāt ᵊtwaǧǧiʕ al-wlēd.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a20"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕāmalawwal ʕādēne uxṛa ḥablāne l-ḥurma win yigūl uxṛa wlēd hāḏe: belli, gāḷ gāman yiǧin-he yiǧin ʕa-l-ḥurma. huwwa zād yabanǧi, yaʕni mū m-al-midīne mūhu Urfalli. gilt-ill-u “ta-rrūḥ ʕala xōǧa, šēx!“ čān, nuṭluʕ ᵊrrūḥ ʕala šēx, āni w huwwa.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts8" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ᵊrrūḥ ᵊnfahhim l-aš-šēx, win ygūl hāḏe “āni aktib-il-kum w lā txāfūn!” gām w čān yiktib-in-na wruga. w ysāwī-n-na wruga, min āyat al-qurʔān, w kitab-he win ygūl “haḏanne tḥuṭṭ-ha ʕind-he!” w kitab-in-na wruga zād, gāl “ḥuṭṭū-ha b-al-mayye w kun__nahāṛ tišṛab mayye m-al-ᵊhnīye!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a31"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>lummun ᵊtxalaṣ uxṛa asāwi, ‌lā txāfūn!“ gāḷ, “hāḏa l-ᵊwlēd hāḏa alle yiṣīr.” čān nāxuḏ al-wruga ḏīč. ḥaṭṭēnā-ha inṭēnā-ha ʕala l-ḥurma, min ḥaṭṭēnā-ha ʕa-l-ḥurma w-šālat-he ʕid-he, haḏannīč mā yiǧin-he b-al-ḥilim.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a36"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>awwali yiǧin-he b-al-ḥilim, yōm-in ᵊtnām yiǧin-he b-al-lēl. hiyye nāyme w ygūmin yiǧin-he. hā w-alḥaz ṣār-l-u wl-ēd. ṣār-l-u al-wlēd ṣār-l-u šahaṛ šhaṛēn ṣār- l-u. kayyāf! awwali kull-ma yṣīr-l-u wl¬ēd ᵊtwaǧǧiʕ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a220" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>There is what we call the demon, the demon comes out – The demon called suˁluwwa comes to us, in Arabic we say suˁluwwa. – Yes the suˁluwwa demon is here. There are places, if you go there by night she will come over you; she will certainly come over you, she will see you and frighten you.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a221" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>You will either get mad or you will die or they will beat you. This will surely happen, yes. – Your heart stands still, your heart stands still. – Recently we had one here, a friend of mine. His wife got pregnant, she became pregnant. (But) when she conceived a child, she always lost the child. When she got pregnant with a child she lost him or her.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a223" ANNOTATION_REF="a15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>So he did not get children. Always when his wife conveived a child they started to come into her belly at night. The demons. Look! He said to me, he came to me and… Look! He said, “It’s like that, what we can do?” And again the doctors did not find a cure for him. She kept on losing the child, three or four times she miscarried.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a224" ANNOTATION_REF="a20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Last year this woman became pregnant again. Look! He said it was again a boy. He said, “They come again to her, they come to the woman.” He is also a stranger, this means he is not from the town, he is not from Urfa. I said to him, “Let’s go to a sage, to a sheikh!” So we went to a sheikh, he and I.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a225" ANNOTATION_REF="a25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>We went there and explained the issue to the sheikh. He said, “I will write something for you, don’t worry!” He stood up and wrote and amulet for us. He made an amulet for us from verses of the Koran. He wrote it and then he said, “Put these all on her!” And he wrote for us another amulet and said, “Put this into water and then she should drink from this water every day!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a226" ANNOTATION_REF="a31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When it is finished I will maken you another one, don’t worry!” Then he said, “This child will surely be born.” We took the amulet and put it on her; we gave it to the woman. After we had put it on her and she was carrying it with her, those (demons) did no longer come to her dreams.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a227" ANNOTATION_REF="a36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Before they came to her dreams, the came to her during night when she was sleeping. When she was sleeping the started to come to her. Hey, but now he has got the child. He has got a boy one or two months ago. He is very glad because formerly (his wife) always miscarried. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
