<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2022-09-01T16:40:35+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-105_Life_in_Former_Times-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:b0807e0d-766a-4ad7-a04d-40544cc32f9a</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">74</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="10"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="71485"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="71485"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="115512"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="115512"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="167080"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="167080"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="204770"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="204782"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="243215"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="254323"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="298904"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="298904"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="362648"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="362648"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="402526"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="402526"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="418499"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="418499"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="462763"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="462763"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="486769"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="486771"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="516078"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="516092"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="541045"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="541068"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="588240"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gabǝḷ-ma tiǧi ˀal-mayye činna nizraˁ ˁala l-fiddān ˁa-l-bǝgaṛ, ˁa-l-bǝgaṛ ᵊnšidd ᵊbgaṛtēn b-an-nīr al-xašab w-al-ˁidde xašab, ᵊnḥuṭṭ bī-ha ḥadīde hīčiḏ tišxaṭ al-gāˁ ˀal-maˁāš zifit, ᵊnšidd ᵊmn-aš-šufāg al-awwali  nāxuḏ ṯumnītēn ḥunṭa, nizraˁ ᵊṯnēne fiddānēn ᵊnsūg wāḥad yizraˁ  mn-aš-šufāg l-al-maġrib, ˀaṯ-ṯumnītēn   ᵊnšidd aṭ-ṭabbān, zād ᵊnsawwi aṭ-ṭabbān.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts2" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ˀā, niǧi tibin čān tibin. ᵊnḥuṭṭ at-tibin  mišān al-bǝgaṛ yākl-u al-bǝgaṛ yišbaˁ, ᵊnnām, nnām sāˁtēn gūm saḥḥǝr al-bǝgaṛ nsaḥḥǝr al-bǝgaṛ w mn-aš-šufāg uxṛa nšidd. šuqulne maˁāš-ne hāḏa hū čān. awwali  aṭ-ṭāḥūn aṭ-ṭaḥīn  fōg b-aǧ-Ǧillāb hīčiḏ ᵊb-ˀĀḏane Dōdāš filān. ašidd al-biˁīr min hēn</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts4" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ˁa-l-biˁīr ˁa-ǧ-ǧamal ˁa-ǧ-ǧaḥaš “rūḥ ˁa-ṭ-ṭāḥūna ˁa-l-mayye tiṭḥan.”  sǝra yox  arbaˁ tiyyām xamǝs tiyyām dört gün beş gün ekmek yox, ač kimse yox, sǝra yox,  ˀarbaˁ tiyyām xamǝs tiyyām nitna tā tiṭḥan aṭ-ṭāḥīn al-bēt hēn mayyit mn-aǧ-ǧūˁ, mā-min xubuz. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ˁala-ma niǧi ˁa-l-bēt inn-u mn-aǧ-ǧīrān nāxuḏ ṭaḥīn aǧ-ǧīrān kullu ta-nxabiz. niǧi  wǝḥde mn-al-ᵊfrād ᵊtrūḥ l-al-gurḏ̣a  [Turkish 2.57-3.11]  [Turkish  wāḥad ᵊmn-al-ᵊfrād yḏ̣all, farde, hā ˁašǝr tiyyām ᵊtxalaṣ ˀuxṛa nšidd rrūḥ ˁala… hāḏa maˁāš-ne ṃayy mā-min.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a26"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>b-al-fiddān taˁab ᵊmn-aṣ-ṣubuḥ ˁa-l-maġrib ssūg w timši ᵊmn-aṣ-ṣubuḥ ᵊnšidd l-al-maġrib yēlōn arīd amši ˁala riǧl-ayya aṭubb Āḏane Āḏane ˀaṭubb-ha hā!  mn-aš-šufāg al-xalāṭ aḏ̣-ḏ̣alām māši ˁala riǧl-ayye, yēlōn-i amši hīčiḏ aṭubb Āḏane min Ḥarrān aṭubb Āḏane, hā hīčiḏ maˁāš-ne čān</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a31"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-ḥurma tilbas ṯōb wāḥad, awwali az-zlime lū ṯōb wāḥad alḥaz az-zlime lū ˁišrīn ṯōb, al-ḥurma la-ha ˁišrīn ṯōb kull-ha nāylōn gāmin yšiddin rrūshin min waṛa miṯl ad-deve ysawwin miṯl al-biˁīr.  salām al-biˁīr yā! ṣār xarāb čān awwali nāmūs ḥayā šī. az-zilime lē rād yufūt al-ḥurma tigaf xamsīn mītraw. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a36"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>tigaf w tilimm ṯōb-ha hīčiḏ. miṯil yasīr al-yasīr miṯil al-ˀær ˁind al-yüzbāši.  lum-min-ma az-zlime yfūt tā hī tfūt. čān ṣudug, awwali čān nāmūs.  wāḥad lē tiḏ̣āyag al-ˁašīre kull-he tgūm ᵊb-sāgt-u.  nāmūs ḥayā qayriyye, ˀē  ha-s-sāˁa hāḏiy hāḏī ˀal-axx umud-u  b-ax-ū ˁalag ᵊb-an-nāṛ nāmūs mā ḏ̣all, ḥayā mā ḏ̣all. al-ḥurma gāmat ᵊtdūs fōg gaḷb az-zilime hīčiḏ ᵊtfūt. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a57"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-ᵊkbāṛ ġābat  yeni moda çıktı naylōn naylōn. awwali čān ǧūx yirmi sine aǧ-ǧūx tilbas hū yḏ̣all ǧidīd. ˀalḥaz naylōn šahar yˁallig yrūḥ awwali činna ˁala l-xēl  nirkab al-xēl nifzaˁ b-at-tfungāt. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a48"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ᵊnḥāmi waṭan-ne. al-lēl w-an-nahāṛ ᵊnḥāmi l-waṭan  lā yiǧīna dišmān min Sūrīye. yiǧi yāxuḏ qanam-ne yāxuḏ baˁar-ne yāxuḏ halāl-ne </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a49"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts18" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>at-tfunge b-īd-ak b-al-lēl b-an-nahāṛ miṯl al-ˁaskariyye. ᵊtnām haḏāk yiǧi yāxuḏ ḥalāl-ak yiḏbaḥ-ak. hā hīčiḏ čān. alḥaz ṣār as-sayyārāt nāmūs mā ḏ̣all ṣār guṭun ṣār mǝṣāri ṣār mǝṣāri xērsiz. awwali činna b-wurəgət pangalōt rrūḥ ˁa-l-madīne tta-rrah-a </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a54"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts20" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w niǧi. alḥaz b-al-malyār ᵊtrūḥ l-al-madīne tiǧi bōš. xērsiz bereketsiz, ˀē al-ḥamdilla ˁala d-dawle  ˀal-ḥamdilla ˁala ḥukūmit-ne, ˀal-ḥamdilla ˁala Turkīt-ne.Aḷḷa ygawwi al-bērag al-ḥamar </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a58"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>wa-ḥne ǧawwā. Aḷḷa lā yqārbinna yqarbin-na w-yirazzil-na miṭl al-qēr. inšaḷḷa l-bērag al-ḥamar hāḏe yiḏ̣aḷḷ ˁalēne hīčiḏ. ayyıldız. iḥna ˁāyšīn kēf alḥaz ǧawwā. inšaḷḷa dāyme yḏ̣all hīčiḏ fōg-ne. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a59"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Aḷḷa yˁammir at-Turkiyye. awwali čānu ˁArab Ḥarrān yrūḥūn ˁala Sūriyye miššān mišān kīlow čāy yā amma  kīlow ghawa. alḥaz yuḏ̣urbūn-u ˁa-l-ᵊḥdūd zād ymūt. alḥaz kull-ši b-Turkīye šīy šī, Aḷḷa berekettir Aḷḷa yhannī-ne maˁāšne āmīn.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a60"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ˁiš hū ᵊb-duwal al-aǧnabiyye kull-u ˁindi-na b-Turkiyye, hā hīčiḏ w-inšaḷḷa dāyme hīčiḏ, Aḷḷa yistir-ne, min gaḏ̣ab aḏ̣-ḏ̣ulum w-ač-čiḏib. ˀē mū hīčiḏ yā wald axū? – naˁam naˁam!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a61" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Before the water came we used to cultivate the fields with animals, with cows, with cows. We used to tie two cows to the wooden yoke; the plough was also made of wood and we put a ploughshare of iron onto it. Like this it ploughed the soil. The earnings were misarable.  Formerly we used to work from dusk and took only two ṯumnīye of wheat. We cultivated the earth with two animals but the one who worked on the soil from dusk to dawn took only two ṯumnīye. We cultivated 2 acres (Fiddan= 4,200 m2). One would had to work on the soil from dusk to dawn for two ṯumnīye (sacks?) of wheat.  We also pulled the ṭabbān, we did the work with the ṭabbān (which is used to cover the seeds).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a62" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Yes, we also came for the straw, there was the straw. We took the straw for the cows to eat, in order that the cows get full. We slept two hours but then “Get up and feed the cows!” We fed the cows and worked on the soil again from dusk onwards. This was our work and our income. And the mill for the flour was up there in aǧ-Ǧillāb, in Āḏane, in Dōdaš, and so on. I went from here</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a63" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>with the camels. On the back of the camels and the donkeys. “Go to the water mill to grind the crop!” There was a long queue; four, five days, four five days no bread, hunger, nobody; and a long queue. We waited for four or five days until we could mill the flour while the family here was dying of hunger, because there was no bread.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a64" ANNOTATION_REF="a21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Until we came home they (lit. we) took the neighbours’ flour to bake bread. One female member of the family went to borrow something. One of the the family members used to do this, one female member. Well, and after ten days it (the flour) was finished and we went again. This was our life, there was no water. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a65" ANNOTATION_REF="a26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>With draught animals; come and plough from morning to evening! It is tiring to work from the morning to evening on the field! We ploughed from morning to evening and if I had walked (the same distance in one direction) I had reached Adana I would have reached Adana? , yes I had reached Adana! From dusk to nightfall I was walking and if I had walked (straight) I had reached Adana, from Harran I had reached Adana. Like this was our life.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a66" ANNOTATION_REF="a31">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The woman used to wear one single garment and the man had one single garment in former times. Now the man has twenty garments and the woman has also twenty garments, which are all made of nylon. They have begun to bind their hair in ponytail style (lit. camel) like a camel’s tail. Like a camel! Everything has become spoiled; in former times their was honour and shame. When a man liked to pass by the woman stood behind fifty metres.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a67" ANNOTATION_REF="a36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>She stopped and tightened her garment like this. Like a prisoner, like a private in front of a lieutenant. When the man had passed she also passed then she was allowed to pass. There was honesty; there was honour in former times. When one had problems the whole tribe was on his side. There was honour, shame, and helpfulness. But nowadays the brother hopes that his brother burns in fire. But nowadays a brother’s hope in his brother has got cought in fire (has been burned/ It does not exist anymore). Neither honour nor shames has remained. The woman has begun to step on the man’s heart, like this she goes on.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a74" ANNOTATION_REF="a57">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The politeness is gone. There is a new fashion out, namely, the nylon. It was the braodcloth in the former times. If you would wear broadcloth for twenty years, it would stay new, but nowadays the nylon (clothes that are made out of nylon) would be worn out in a month. Formerly, we used to ride on horses and stand to protect/guard our homeland with rifles. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a68" ANNOTATION_REF="a48">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>To protect our country. We were protecting the country day and night, in case an enemy would come from Syria, who would come and take our sheep, he would take our camels, he would take what is rightfully ours</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a69" ANNOTATION_REF="a49">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The rifle must remain in your hand day and night like in the military. If you fall asleep, he (the enemy) will come and take what is (rightfully) yours and kill you. It was like that. Nowadays there are cars (instead of horses). There is no honor anymore. There is cotton and therefore, more money, bad money.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a70" ANNOTATION_REF="a54">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>In the former times we used to go to the city and come back with one pangal (a former currency?), but nowadays with 1.000 Turkish Lira (formerly 1.000.000.000 Turkish pounds) you go to the city and come back empty-handed. It is bad money nowadays, with no blessing. Thank God for the state, our government and our Turkey.May God strengthen the red banner</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a71" ANNOTATION_REF="a58">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>as we are inside the country (under its shadow). May God does not make us flee and suffer like the others. God willing this red banner will stay upon us like this. ‘’The moon and the star’’ we live happily now in this country. May it always remain like this upon us.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a72" ANNOTATION_REF="a59">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>May God let Turkey prosper. In the former times, the Arabs of Harran used to go to Syria for a kilo of tee or coffee, but nowadys if anyone gets close to the borders, he would be shot and dead. Nowadays there is everything in Turkey. God has blessed it. May God make us satisfied with our income. Amen.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a73" ANNOTATION_REF="a60">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>What is in the foreign countries, we have it all here in Turkey. Yes, it is like that, and God willing it will always be like that. May God save us from the wrath of injustice and lies. Isn’t like that, son? Yes, definitely. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
