<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-03-29T10:12:06+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-155_Childhood-Harran-2014.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:07e68073-848f-4470-abeb-6df77e1a38aa</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">46</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="2830"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="14030"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="14040"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="27270"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="27282"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="39666"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="39666"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="52000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="52033"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="60016"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="60032"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="67399"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="67415"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="77415"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="77416"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="86449"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="86482"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="92332"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="92349"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="100400"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="100400"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="106883"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="106891"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="123358"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="123382"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="136032"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="136033"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="148083"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="148132"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="159516"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="159516"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="167433"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="167449"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="180016"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="180032"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="193349"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="193366"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="205416"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts39" TIME_VALUE="205432"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts40" TIME_VALUE="216032"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts41" TIME_VALUE="216032"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts42" TIME_VALUE="229432"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts43" TIME_VALUE="229432"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts44" TIME_VALUE="238249"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts45" TIME_VALUE="238265"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts46" TIME_VALUE="250724"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>āni awwali, awwali wakt-inn-i ziqīre āni činit čiṯīr ᵊrḥamt abū-yi yištahī-ni, ʕamann-i āni hem ǧilqa hem zādēne mū... al-ʕiǧyān ṣāyrīn ʕugb-i erkek çocukları ta-ngūl</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a2"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ište hēne yaʕni mā yihnī-ni āni, mā yizʕil-ni; han-nōb uxt-i akbar minn-i isim-he Miryam, tss, axū-ye ṣāyir ᵊzġayyir ṣāyir ǧidīd w-umm-i mā tirḏ̣aʕ-u, rrūḥ ᵊtrūḥ ᵊǧǧīb-ill-u m-aǧ-ǧarye ǧǧīb-ill-u ḥalīb.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a3"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ta-ngūl aǧ-ǧarye čam kilāwmitir? ʕin… ʕin Aqčaqale? xamaṣtaʕaš kilāwmitir? – hāy hī? –  min Aqčaqale ʕa-l-ʕIlle –lā, lē kilāwēn mitir – hā – alle iki bin metre – ī, ᵊnrūḥ ᵊnǧīb, ī nrūḥ ᵊnǧīb,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a4"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>han-nōba wāḥad ʕaǧiy yisraḥ, ʕind-u… rāčib ač-čaḥaš, w yisraḥ ʕind-u duwāb, yisraḥ bī-hin. hāḏa hā min yšūf Miryam šāyle l-ḥalīb yiǧi yuktil-he w ykubb ḥalīb-he. tss!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>kunn_nahāṛ yikubb ḥalīb-he, tiǧi tī-tgūl l-umm-i tgūl umm-i hemen faqīre mā ssōlif ši-trīd ᵊssāwi. ᵊnqəṣaf ʕumr-u! ᵊtgūl ᵊtxaḷḷī-´.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>min yšūf-he, ḥāṭṭ ᵊhnīt-u qanǧīt-u win yšūf-he ǧaʕad tiǧi min... yisāwi ǧalāq ʕala kull al yfūtūn al-ʕiǧyān az-zqār min qādi. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w nahāṛ ʕayne Miryam ʕād win ᵊtgūl, iḥne b-al-məktab w-āni yā-ha, b-al-məktab iḥne, gilt-il-he ǧaʕad yiǧi al-ʕaǧi min qādi hū zād yigri b-al-məktab ᵊbsāgit-ne.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gilit “daḥḥǧi hāḏa al-ʕaǧi hāḏa, wali!” ism-u wald Ṣāfye, hiyye Ṣāfye, ism al-ḥurma, umm-u, hāḏa wald Ṣāfye al kunn_nahāṛ ykubb ḥalīb-ič?” gāḷat “ī waḷḷa hāḏiyān-u!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hinne bēt ahal-i darbēn luwwa, wāḥad ana ǧādde, wāḥad zād min waṛa daṛbt-in ḏ̣ayyǧe.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>čān agūm w gilt-il-he: “hā-č čantit-i!” čān agaḏ̣ḏ̣ib-he čantit-i, Miryam mənṭī-he. hā, agḏ̣ub-ill-i min hal-ᵊḥǧarāt ummahāt būz. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a11"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>aǧi w-aṭluʕ-ill-u hīčid aguṭṭ-ill-u m-al-kōš w-aṭluʕ-ill-u ᵊgbāḷ hū dāy… hū kallt-u hīčiḏ aswad,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a12"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yihizz ᵊb-kallt-u ǧaʕ-yiǧi min qādi, w-agḏ̣ub-ill-i al-ᵊḥǧara aḏ̣rib-u, hihihihi, ʕala guṣṣt-u, win miṯil ᵊtgūlīn hnīt – muṣluq – muṣluq – ᵊtgūlīn ᵊhnīt ba… ygūlūn miṯil ᵊhnīt al-ᵊbrīǧ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a13"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w gām ad-damm, gām ad-damm yiṭannib mir_rās-u, qassal waǧh-u ad-damm w rāḥ ʕala umm-u mištaki l-umm-u, umm-u rabīʕt umm-i w-abū-ye wakt-in-hum ᵊzqār awwali, rabīʕit-hum köy arqadāši yaʕni, awwali ᵊb-zimānāt.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts28">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>win-he ǧāye umm-u āni čān agūm anhazim w-arūḥ axušš ᵊbgaḷb al-gunn. ʕid-ne gunn, gunn ad-diǧāǧ čān axušš ᵊbgaḷb-u, an-nōba mtilat zādēn al-gamḷa. w-aḥukk min hal-gamḷa w xāṭle bgaḷb al-gunn.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts29" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w yiǧi win-he ǧāye hiyye “yā wali ḥaǧǧiyye! yā wali ʕAwwāš yā wali daḥḥǧi ši-msāwye bint-ič! daḥḥǧi yā wali ḏ̣ārbe yā wali… txanxin hiyye burnu biraz hiyye wakt-in ᵊssōlif.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a16"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts31" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>xāle daḥḥǧi ši-msāwye b-wlid-i, yā wali mqasslitt-u b-ad-damm yā wali!” han-nōb ᵊrḥamt abū-ye, yindall bī-ye yaʕni āni bgaḷb al-gunn, </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a17"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>alḥaz tiǧi alḥaz hīčiḏ asāwi, alḥaz hīčiḏ asāwi, maqṣūft al-ʕumur, ᵊšnōn tuktil yāw wlid-ič yāw ᵊšnōn tuktil-u?!” w-āni asmaʕ ḥiss-u, hū zād yindall bī-ye āni b-al-gunn mā y... mā, mā ysōlif-ni, al-marḥūm.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a18"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ahā w ʕugub ʕādēne wakt-in ṭilaʕit gāḷ-l-i “zēn sāwēti bī-´ xall-u! kunn_nahār ykubb ḥalīb uxt-ič?!” hāw ᵊhnā yaʕni mā, mā izʕil ʕalay-ye, w-āni kafš-i hal-gadd-u gəḏ̣a m-al-gaməḷ, min gaməḷ ad-diǧāǧ. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a19"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts37" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ḏāk al-wakit awwali šī dedete, ad-dedete ad-dedete al yhuṭṭūn-he ʕa-n-nimmāl. čān tiǧi min qādi uxt-i w tgūl gāḷat umm-i: daḥḥǧi yā wali hāḏi šnōn gəḏ̣a kafiš-he, min ad-dedete min ᵊhniyye m-al-gaməḷ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a20"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts39" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts40">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w čān ᵊǧǧīb-ill-i guṭmit dedete w tḥuṭṭ ʕala rās-i. w gāmin yḥuṭṭin hal-gadd gəḏ̣a kafš-i m-al-gaməḷ w ḥaṭṭan ʕalē-´ ad-dedete, manṯūr w…</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts41" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts42">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>han-nōba ʕid-ne hniyye al-gunn uxṛa, aṣ-ṣuwāṣi ḥāṭṭīn aṣ-ṣuwāṣi bgaḷb al-gunn w yiǧi al-biss w-āni maǧḏ̣ūʕa fōg, ad-dinye gēḏ̣ w ǧāʕde ʕa-ṣ-ṣōmye w kafš-i manṯūr.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a22"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts43" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts44">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w gāḷat umm-i “daḥḥǧi yā wali šūfi šūfi māl ač-čalib hāḏa al-biss hāḏa, nāšb-in-ne čala kull haṣ-ṣuwāṣiyyāt.” umm-i.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts45" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts46">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w šnōn ṣaḥīḥ zād ᵊmnāwiǧ l-al… l-al-gunn, w čān yiǧi yxaṭif wāḥad w yinhazim w-ᵊyrūḥ, w čān w-āni kafš-i manṯūr w-arkuḏ̣ b-aṯar-u, hahahaha!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a24" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>In former times, when I was young, my late father loved me very much because I was playful. And, let’s say, also because the children before me were all male kids. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25" ANNOTATION_REF="a2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>So, I mean, he was never angry with me. Once it happened that my elder sister, her name is Miryam, tss… My younger brother was just born and my mother could not breastfeed him and so she (my sister) went to bring milk for him from the village.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a26" ANNOTATION_REF="a3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Let’s say, how many kilometres is the village away from Akçakale? Fifteen kilometres? – Which one? – From Akçakale to al-ʕIlle. – No, it is just two kilometres. – Yeah! – It is just two thousand metres. – Yes, we used to go (there) and brought (milk).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a27" ANNOTATION_REF="a4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>There was a kid there, he was herding (animals) and he had… he was riding a donkey, he had sheep and he was grazing them. Whenever he saw Miryam carrying the milk, he would come, hit her and spill her milk. Tss!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a28" ANNOTATION_REF="a5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He spilled her milk every day and when she came home she said to my mother, “XXX.” Since my mother was naïve she did not say anything. What else should she do? She just said, “May his life be short,” and let him do. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a29" ANNOTATION_REF="a6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Whenever he saw her, he took his thingy, his cane and as he saw her he came. He played nasty tricks on all the small children who passed by from there.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a30" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>One day, the same thing happened again. Miryam said – we were at school, me and her, we were at school. I told her that the boy was coming from there; he also was studying with us at the same school.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a31" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>I said, “Look at that one, that boy, look!” His name was Ṣāfye’s son; the name of the woman, his mother, was Ṣāfye. “Is it Ṣāfye’s son who spills your milk every day?” She said, “Yes, that’s him!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a32" ANNOTATION_REF="a9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>My parents’ house bordered on two streets; one of them was a main street, and the other one was in the back, a narrow street. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a33" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>I got up and said to her, “Take my bag!” I passed her my bag and Miryam took it. Then I grabbed a few stones with pointed edges. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a34" ANNOTATION_REF="a11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>I came and went out to him; I cut his way at the corner and turned up in front of him. His head was black like that.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a35" ANNOTATION_REF="a12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He was shaking his head and coming from there. I grabed the stone and hit ihm, hahaha, on his forehead. Lo and behold, there was something like a bump – a tap – a tap, something (that looked) like the thing of a jug.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a36" ANNOTATION_REF="a13">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The blood gushed out; the blood gushed out and ran down his head. His face was washed in blood. He went to his mother and complained to his mother. His mother was my mother’s and my father’s friend. When they were young, she was their friend. They were village kids back then.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a37" ANNOTATION_REF="a14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>His mother came straight over. So, I ran away and entered the coop. We had a coop, a chicken coop; I went into it and it was full of lice; I was scratching myself because of the lice when I was hiding inside the coop.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a38" ANNOTATION_REF="a15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He and she came and she said, “Hey hajji! Hey ʕAwwāš!  Look what your daughter has done! Look how she has hit... hey!” When she spoke, she always twanged a little.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a39" ANNOTATION_REF="a16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“My dear, look what she has done to my son! She has washed him with blood!” Of course, my late father knew that I was in the coop.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a40" ANNOTATION_REF="a17">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “She will come now and I will do like this to her. May God shorten her life, how could she hit your son so badly? How could she hit him?!” I was hearing his voice and he actually knew that I was in the coop. He would not say anything to me, (my) deceased (father). </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a41" ANNOTATION_REF="a18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Ha, and after I had come out he said to me, “Good job you did to him, let it be! He spills your sister’s milk everyday?!” He was not at all angry with me. And my hair was completely gone because of the lice, the lice of the chicken.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a42" ANNOTATION_REF="a19">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>At that time there was something called DDT. They used to put DDT on the ants. My sister was coming from there and said that my mother had said, “Look how destroyed her hair is because of the DDT, the thingy, the lice.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a43" ANNOTATION_REF="a20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>She brought me some DDT and put it on my head, so destroyed was my hair due to the lice. They put the DDT on it; scattered…</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a44" ANNOTATION_REF="a21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Then we had a thing, another coop for the chicks. We had put the chicks inside that coop and then a cat came. I lay down upstairs. It was summer and I was sitting on the bed with my hair down.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a45" ANNOTATION_REF="a22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>My mother said, “Hey, look! Look at it, this cat is like a dog. It has nested at our place and has eaten all the chicks.” My mother.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a46" ANNOTATION_REF="a23">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>How carefully it observed the coop. It was hiding and when someone came it went away. And I with my hair down was running behind her, hahahaha!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
