<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-01-15T11:08:19+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Y:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-112_Tall_Nasir-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:58003e09-d755-42b7-a4c9-5392a07244a9</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">33</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="0"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="28589"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="28600"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="74440"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="74480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="108560"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="108560"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="145720"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="145720"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="184720"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="184720"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="237840"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="237840"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="264360"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="264400"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="313160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="313160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="349160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="349160"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="373480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="373480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="402280"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Tall Xarma – isim awwali Tall Xarma? – Tall Qarma, zimān al-ʕUsmalli, ā, baʕdēn ǧidd-ina hēn nāzil. huwwa w rayyis al-ʕašāyir as-Sūriyye ṣār ḥarb. ma-bēn ʕašāyir-na w-Sūriyye ṣār ḥarb čiṯīr.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a2"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>rayyis al-ʕašāyir haḏāk gāyil l-aš-šāʕir, šāʕr ē, tʕarif šāʕir? – ē! – gāḷ: rūḥ! ʕa-rayyis ʕašāyir Ǧēs w lē ṣār b-al-ᵊghawa al-maǧlis ṣār tamām. inte b-aṛ-ṛǝbāb, gūl:
mǝn fōg diǧil-ha, mǝn fōg diǧil-ha
kull al-ʕaǧādīy yassarat
wa-Čill ḥabbal-ha.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a3"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yaʕni huwwa erqeq hāḏi kull-ha qadǝn. sen böyle söyle: mǝn fōg diǧil-ha, mǝn fōg diǧil-ha, kull al-ʕaǧādīy yassarat, wa-Čill ḥabbal-ha. gūl hīčiḏ w āni anṭī-k čiṯīr məṣāri. hāḏi zād xarǧiliq hāḏa albīs w rūḥ!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a4"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hā, ǧī ʕala ǧidd-ina hēne ḏāk az-zimān qara čādir, byūt al-ʕarab. gaṛāye flān māmin, kull-u qara čādir, bēt-in aswad, bēt šaʕir. āā, hāḏa zād ǧīy rāčib ʕa-ǧ-ǧaḥaš, ḥawwal w fāt w gaʕad w flān w qahwa w kēf ifil.
</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ʕugub gāḷ-l-u: yā… yā ḏ̣ēf-na halla ʕind-ak ṛubāba, halla sawwī-n-na teselli! giḏ̣ab aṛ-ṛubāba, gāḷ nōbtēn ṯalāṯ šarqī, qēr šarqī, gāḷ hak-kilma hāḏi zād, gāḷ mǝn fōg diǧil-ha, mǝn fōg diǧil-ha, kull al-ʕaǧādīy yassarat, wa-Čill ḥabbal-ha.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>maḥḥad ᵊmtabbʕ-il-he hāḏi amma aš-šēx, xaššat qāft-u, neyse hāḏi ǧat al-ᵊqnīm ʕa-l-ḥalīb aḏ̣-ḏ̣uhur kull-man rāḥ ʕala bēt-u ḏ̣aḷḷ ar-rayyis hēne š-šēx, w-aš-šāʕir. gāḷ-ḷ-u: yā šāʕir! gāḷ: hā! gāḷ-ḷ-u: imiš tā nirga fōg at-tall hāḏa w daḥḥiǧ ʕala ʕurbān Ǧēs! šgadd ʕurbān šīy? šgadd qanam šīy? šgadd baʕar šīy? šgadd ḥarīm šīy? šgadd yaʕni xēl? šūf al-ᵊblād! hāt zād ṛubābt-ak ᵊbsāgt-ak! </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hāḏa zād ᵊstadār ʕala ʕiyāl-u al-qilīč, ᵊlbis al-ʕabā fōg-u w-rǝga ʕa-t-tall. at-tall hāḏa min fōg min qādi ʕāli. min hēne hīčiḏ, ā, hīčiḏ ᵊngūl, min qād ʕāli, min al-wurč aš-šimāli.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gaʕadu hināk. gāḷ: daḥḥiǧ! gözü doldur – imil ʕēn-ak! ši-tšūf? gāḷ: ašūf ᵊbyūt, čiṯīr. uxṛa ši-tšūf? gāḷ: ašūf ᵊqnīm. uxṛa? gāḷ: baʕar čiṯīr. uxṛa? gāḷ: awādim čiṯīr, xēl čiṯīr, aḷḷa yhannī-k bī-hum! aḷḷa yhannī-k bī-hum!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāḷ: zēn šifit? zēn daḥḥiǧ-ha! gāḷ: zēn, milēt ʕēn-i, yūūūūū… gāḷ: tisḥab-in-ne ṛ-ṛubāba wannis-ne ta-ššūf! saḥab aṛ-ṛubāba, gāḷ-l-u gaṣīdtēn ṯalāṯ. gāḷ: mū hāḏi! al gulit-he aḏ̣-ḏ̣aḥa. gāḷ qēr-he, gāḷ: mū hāḏi, alli gulit-ha b-al-ᵊghawa. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā ʕād yʕarif ši-yrīd yigūl. mā ḏ̣allat firṣa yōx alle tgūl-he. gāḷ: yōm-inn-u maǧbūr alle_gūl. yōm-inn-u gāḷ-ha lissaʕ mā gāḷ tamām, hāḏa b-as-sēf gāḷ bī-´ hīčiḏ wa-ṛās-u yidriǧ w ytammim as-sālfe.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a11"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ism-u Nāṣir, aš-šāʕir ism-u Nāṣir. awwali čān at-tall hāḏa Tall Xarma, b-zimān al-ʕUsmalli, w min ᵊnḏibaḥ bī-´ az-zlime hāḏa ṣār Tall Nāṣir, ᵊnḏibaḥ bī-´ w-ᵊndifan fōg-u. hā hīčiḏ ǧidd- ina ḏbuḥ-u, wa-Čill darrab-u min Sūriyye hīčiḏ.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Tell Xarma – [SP] Its former name was Tell Xarma? – Tall Qarma, in the era of the Ottomans. Then our grandfather settled down here. A war broke out between him and the chief of the Syrian tribes. Between our tribes and the Syrians there was a lot of war.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a24" ANNOTATION_REF="a2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The chief of those tribes said to a certain poet, a poet, yes, you know what a poet is? – Yes! – He said, “Go to the chief of the tribes of Qays! And when he is sitting in the coffee house, in the majlis, then it is the right (moment) to recite (to him) by playing the rebab: He beat (?) them from above (the camel) All men were taken captives And Čill made pregnant all (women).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25" ANNOTATION_REF="a3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>That means, he was a real man and those others were all (like) women. Say this: He beat them from above (the camel) All men were taken captives And Čill made pregnant all (women). Say like this and I’ll give you a lot of money. Here you have also some allowance! Here you have clothes and (now) go!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a26" ANNOTATION_REF="a4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Hey, he came here to our grandfather and in that time there still were black tents, the tents of the Arabs, there were no villages here, only the black tent, the tent made of hair. This one came riding on a donkey. He got off, came in and sat down. There was coffee and good mood.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a27" ANNOTATION_REF="a5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Afterwards he said to him, “O our guest, since you have a rebab with you, please, comfort us!” He took the rebab and played two or three songs, other songs (than the one he was told in Syria), but then he also said these words: 
He beat (?) them from above (the camel) All men were taken captives And Čill made pregnant all (women).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a28" ANNOTATION_REF="a6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Nobody did follow along, but the sheikh caught on to it.  When the sheep came for the noon’s milking everybody went home, only the chief stayed. The sheikh and the poet. He said to him, “O poet!” He said, “Yes!” He said, “Come on, let’s climb this hill and have a look at the Arabs of Qays! How many Arabs are there? How many sheep? How many camels? How many women and how many horses? Have a look at this country and take your rebab with you! </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a29" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He (the sheikh) returned to his family too. He put on his sword, got the aba onto it and climbed the hill. This hill is steep from the other side, from this side here it is like this, but from the other side it is steep, from the northern slope.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a30" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They sat down there and he said, “Look! Delight your eyes! What do you see?” He said, “I see tents, many indeed.” “What else do you see?” He said, “I see sheep.” “What else?” He said, “Many camels.” “What else?” He said, “Many men, many horses, may God make you happy by them!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a31" ANNOTATION_REF="a9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He said, “Did you look well (at them)? Take a hard look at them!” He said, “I have delighted my eyes, yoo-hoo!” He said, “Take the rebab and exhilarate me!” He took the rebab and recited two or three poems for him. He said, “Not this one, the one you played before noon!” He played (again) another one, so he said, “Not this one, the one you played in the coffeehouse!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a32" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He (the poet) did not know any longer what he should play. (The sheikh) said, “There is no chance left but to play it.” He said, “If it is really necessary I’ll play it.” He played it again but before he could complete it [the sheikh] said, the sword (in his hand), “It’s like that”, and so he finished the poem while his head was rolling down (the hill). </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a33" ANNOTATION_REF="a11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>His name was Nāṣir, the poet’s name was Nāṣir. Before that the tell’s name was Tall Xarma, in the time of the Ottomans. But when this man was slaughtered there, it became Tall Nāṣir. He was slaughtered and buried on it. Our grandfather killed him like this; and Čill had sent him from Syria.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
