<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2023-02-22T11:40:29+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Y:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-057_Story_of_Magician-Harran-2010.wav"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="../../../Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-057_Story_of_Magician-Harran-2010.wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:c22d2840-faa5-4090-b59b-2de4f9f47808</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">97</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="4730"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="31280"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="31280"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="52330"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="52330"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="84650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="84650"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="108810"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="108820"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="121880"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="121890"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="137990"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="138000"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="153570"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="153570"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="170240"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="170250"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="180460"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="180470"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="198047"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>hiyye hiyye abū-ha hēne bāše b-al-balad yaʕni wāli b-al-balad abū-ha b-Urfa hāḏi ṣāyre hēne abū-ha wāli. ʕugub huwwa zangīl čiṯīr, ʕugub-ma mayyit abūha – ḏ̣āllit-illu bnayye – hī w-umm-ha yōm-in ḏ̣āll al-ᵊbnayye yiǧī-ha al-māmūr yiǧī-ha l-ḥākim, yiǧī-ha yxaṭbūn-ha mā trīd. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a16"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>mā trīd kull ḥade yxaṭbūn-ha al-ukbāṛ w-az-zanāgīl w-mā trīd. nahāṛ ǧāy-he dāgg al-bāb šāyib yōm-in dāgg al-bāb fākkit-illu al-bāb umm-ha yōm-in xašš gāyil: āni ǧīt arīd bint-ič. Yōm-innu gāl arīd bint-ič (aš-šāyib). yā bnayyt-i gāyitt-il-he hāḏa šāyib w-inti bint-i ab.. abū-č masmī maʕrūf, yixaṭb-ič al-ḥākim al-qāymaqām al-ihnīye w-mā trīdīn-(hum) w-trīdīn aš-šāyib hāḏa?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a26"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>gāyla arīd-u, aš-šāyib saḥḥār, siḥirbāz. gāyil yōm-in māxiḏ-he šāyle hdūm-ha umm-ha zād gāyle arīd arūḥ ǝb-sāgtu ta-ndall bēt-he. ǧaʕad yimšin yrūḥin ba-ǧbalit bi-ǧbilt Uṛfa. muqār šī yōm-in rāyḥāt ʕa-l-muġur ad-dinye ṣāyre maqrib hiyye w-umm-ha w-šāyib ǧāʕdīn aš-šāyib ygūt al-ᵊbnayye min īd-ha w-yāxuḏ-he ǧawwa. gāyil yirīd ytiǧawwaz-ha. Yōm-in tismaʕ ḏ̣abaḥt al-ᵊbnayye āāā al-… umm-ha. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a41"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts6" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ǧāʕde šuḥḥ. sāʕa zimān miṯil ᵊgʕadit-ne ḏiyye gāyil ǧāy ʕal umm-ha gāyil: rawwḥi ʕāwnī-ni! Yōm-in ǧāye inn-a l-ᵊbnayye mayyte(n). ᵊmšallxa hīčiḏ zātt-ha al-ḥayye al-ḥayye lādġit-he w-ǧaʕad yišḥat-ha ǧāy. ǧāy b-as-saččīne w-gāyil l-umm-ha taʕāli ta-ngaṭṭíḥḥe (&lt; ʕhe) w-gāymīn ygaṭṭʕūn-ha. mgaṭṭīn-ha w-ḥāṭṭ-ha b-al-ǧidir ḥāṭṭ-ha ʕa-n-nār gāyil l-umm-ha: taʕāli ṭbaxīhe!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a51"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-gāyme umm-ha tuṭbax-ha. ʕugub-mi ṭābxət-he w-šāḥle al-laḥam w-mṣaffīye b-al-lgāne ysawwi subze mṣaffi b-al-lgāne w-ṭāliʕ laḥam-he.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a56"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-ǧāyib aǧ-ǧidir gāyil: sawwī-li ʕēš burġul! msawwit-illu ʕēš burġul umm-ha. w-yǧīb al-laḥam, laḥam binit-he yḥuṭṭu ʕa-l-burgul w-gāyim yākul. hiyye yōm-in mṣaffīye as-summ ulugṭi  s-summ mn-al-gāʕ ha-l-gadd w-ṣurrī maḥramt-ič! aš-šāyib yōm-in min qādi gāyim yākul ǧībi as-summ ḥuṭṭī min yamm aš-šāyib.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a63"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts15">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>aš-šāyib gāyim yākul, yākul šnōn-mu māčil māčil as-summ ʕugub šuḥḥ gāyim yiḥtās w-mayyit. Yōm-inn-u mayyit ad-dinye lēl. mayyt aš-šāyib w-mǝǧǝrze xāyfe gāyle alḥaz ši-yšīr ʕaleye?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a70"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts14" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ṭālʕe b-ač-čōl ǧāʕde fōg al-maqāṛa. yōm-in-hi ǧāʕde fōg al-maqāṛa yiǧūn yibīʕūn xāṯir yibīʕūn ǧelle ʕa-l-balad, yiǧībūn awwali. Yōm-in-he mdaḥḥǧe aǧ-ǧḥīš ha-l-ǧḥīš gafal w-gāyme tōmī-lhum: taʕālu yōm-in… ǝš bī-č? š-inti inis ǧinis gāyle waḷḷa inis!</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a77"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-mart ᵊflān w-hīčiḏ w-hīčiḏ ṣār ʕalēyye. w-ḏibaḥ bint-i aš-šāyib ǝnṭā-ha l-al-ḥayye w-ḏibaḥ-ḥa. yunṭūn xabar ʕa-l-ᵊḥkūma yōm-in yiǧūn al-ᵊḥkūma inna l-maqāṛa kulla ʕǝḏ̣ām </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a82"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>win al-ḥayāye mṛabbaṭa b-az-zanāǧīr yāxḏ al-ʕiǧyān yāxḏ al… al-ᵊbanāt al yiḏ̣ḥak ʕalē-hin yinṭī-hin l-al-ḥayye tildaq-hin w-yuṭbaxhin ysawwī-hin zehīr w-ybīʕ. hāḏi zād hīčiḏ ʕind-i. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a88" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>(There was a girl) whose father was pasha in the town, he was the governor of Urfa, here it happened. He was very rich. After he had passed away, he left behind a daughter– she and her mother. Since she has remained (alone), the high official and (even) the ruler came to her in order to betroth her. But she did not want. She accepted nobody to get affianced, neither the big ones nor the rich</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a89" ANNOTATION_REF="a16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>One day an old man knocked the door. When he knocked her mother opened the door to him. He entered and said, “I came to ask for your daughter’s hand.” When he said, “I want your daughter”, she said to her, “My daughter, he is an old man and you are my child. Your father was well-known. The ruler and the governor and who else wanted to betroth you, but you rejected them. Do you want this old man?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a90" ANNOTATION_REF="a26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>She said, “Yes, I want him.” The old man was a magician, a wizard. He said (to himself), “When I have taken her, she will carry her clothes with her.” Her mother said, “I want to go with him to know her (new) home.” So they went to the mountains of Urfa. There was a cave. When they reached the cave, evening had fallen. The girl, her mother, and the old man sat down. Then he took the girl by the hand and pulled her inside saying, “I want to marry her.” When the mother heard the cries of the girl, </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a91" ANNOTATION_REF="a41">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>she sat down immediately. She was sitting for an hour like we are sitting here until he came out and said, “Come and help me!” When she came in the girl was dead. She was naked, a snake, a snake had thrown her (on the ground) and stung her. He (the wizard) pulled her near, he had a knife and said to her mother, “Come here and let’s cut her apart.” They cut her apart, put her into a pot and then on the fire. He said to her mother, “Come and cook it!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a92" ANNOTATION_REF="a51">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>So she started to cook it. After she had cooked it, she put aside the flesh and then sieved (the remaining liquid) into bowls to make poison. She had sieved it into bowls after she had taken out the flesh. He brought the pot and said, “Make a stew for me!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a93" ANNOTATION_REF="a56">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And her mother made a stew for him. Then he brought the meat, the meat of her daughter, put it onto the burgul and started eating. When filtering the poison, she had taken some of it secretly from the bottom (of the sieve) and had wrapped it into her headscarf. When the old man started to drink – lo and behold! – she took the poison and put it inside the food (lit. next to him).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a94" ANNOTATION_REF="a63">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The old man started to eat. He ate and as soon as he had eaten the poison, immediately after that, he began to tumble and died. When he died, it was night. The old man was dead; she had squatted down and was in fear. She said, “What will happen to me now?”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a95" ANNOTATION_REF="a70">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>She went outside and sat down in front of the cave. After she had sitten down in front of the cave, people came who went to the town to sell yoghurt and dried cow dung. They did like that in former times. When she saw the donkeys, this caravan of donkeys, she waved to them and said, “Come here!” They said, “What happened to you? Are you a human or a jinn?” She said, “By God, I’m human.”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a96" ANNOTATION_REF="a77">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“And I am the wife of so-and-so and this and that happened to me. This old man killed my daughter and gave her to a snake. He killed her. They informed the government and when (the men of) the government came they found the cave full of bones.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a97" ANNOTATION_REF="a82">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Look, the snakes were bound in chaines. He had taken the children, the girls. He laughed at them and then he gave them to the snake in order that it stings them. Then he cooked them to make poison for selling it. This is what I know (of stories).</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
