<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2023-12-19T17:14:49+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Z:/SHAWI/Recordings/Urfa-All Recordings/Urfa-046_Game_Xwetime-Harran-2010.wav" MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:23ae63ac-207a-4a71-9f9e-f69f633b13e4</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">132</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="10870"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="27300"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="27310"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="45580"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="45590"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="62180"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="62190"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="72170"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="72170"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="88340"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="88350"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="95590"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="95590"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="107400"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="107410"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="120580"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="120580"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="132490"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="132500"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="144980"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="144980"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="158920"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts23" TIME_VALUE="158930"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts24" TIME_VALUE="178320"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts25" TIME_VALUE="178330"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts26" TIME_VALUE="186420"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts27" TIME_VALUE="186430"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts28" TIME_VALUE="197050"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts29" TIME_VALUE="197050"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts30" TIME_VALUE="209430"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts31" TIME_VALUE="209440"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts32" TIME_VALUE="228760"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts33" TIME_VALUE="228770"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts34" TIME_VALUE="244380"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts35" TIME_VALUE="244390"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts36" TIME_VALUE="256960"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts37" TIME_VALUE="256960"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts38" TIME_VALUE="272480"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts39" TIME_VALUE="272495"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts40" TIME_VALUE="277020"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="default-lt" TIER_ID="default">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a1"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>al-liʕib, xōǧam, awwali iḥna l-ʕarab, ta-ngūl alḥaz fazla māmiš yaʕni miṯil alḥaz ṭāliʕ iskambīl, al-ōkēy, alḥaz alḥīn al-bilgisayār, yilʕabūn b-al-bilgisayār ōkēy ta-ngūl, oyun yaʕni ysammūn yilʕabūn,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>iḥna awwali al-ʕarab yilʕabūn ᵊxwētīme, xwētīme nsammī-he xwētīme, al-ᵊxwētīme rānāt haḏanne r-rānāt yiǧmaʕūn-hin hīčiḏ miṯl aṭ-ṭuppa, sabiʕ rānāt ysawwūn-hin ydaʕbilūn-hin, ydaʕbilūn-hin</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a18"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w yṣuffūn-hin b-at-tapsiyye, w-iḥna ta-ngūl arbaʕa yaʕni ǧāʕdīn ᵊntaʕallal b-al-bēt, āni w-ᵊStēfān xōǧa wāḥad-ne ǧimīʕ ṭāxəm ta-ngūl, w-ᵊMḥimmad ʕAli w Maʕrūf ᵊb-wurič, huṃṃa b-wurič w-iḥna b-wurič.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a25"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“nilʕab ʕalē-man?” ngūl alyōm ᵊnrīd nilʕab ᵊxwētīme ta-ntaʕallal ta-ntaharraǧ b-al-lēl. xayyo nilʕab ʕala arbaʕ tibāsi qadāyif, künefe.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a29"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts8" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ᵊšgadd al-arbaʕ tibāsi? ysawwūn arbaʕīn līra. aaaa, āni w Stēfān xōǧa ninṭi arbaʕīn w Maʕrūf w-ᵊMḥimmad ʕAli yinṭūn arbaʕīn, nirmī-hin ʕidd Melek, al-məṣāri. w-ᵊngūl “minu yuqlub tinṭīn-u arbaʕīn-u</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a36"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts13">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-ᵊngūl: “minu yuqlub tinṭīn-u arbaʕīn-u w-al yxasarūn arbaʕīn-hum ᵊnrūḥ w-ᵊnǧīb bī-ha qadāyif w nākul-he. yaʕni nilʕab ʕala šakle.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a39"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts12" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>nidaššir ʕād ᵊngūl “aṭ-ṭalʕa čam ṣāyir raqam?” ta-ngūl “aṭ-ṭalʕa miyye wəḥde, raqam.” awwal nōb minhu yilʕab yrīd yqabbi al-xātam?” ʕAli di-yqabbi l-xātam. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a45"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts17">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>awwal nōb yāxḏūn ᵊhnītēn, rāntēn, ta-ngūl Melek tāxuḏ rāntēn, ᵊtḥuṭṭ al-xātam ᵊb-wəḥde tqabbī-hin. w tiǧīb-hin tirmī-hin ʕind Stēfān xōǧa wēya Mḥimmad ʕAli, yaʕni yfaḏ̣ḏ̣lūn ᵊb-baʕaḏ̣-hum ygūlūn “inte daḥḥiǧ!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a53"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts16" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ᵊStēfān xōǧa ʕād yōm-in yiǧi ar-rāntēn marmiyyāt hīčiḏ, yšīl hāḏi ydaḥḥiǧ al-xātam bī-he, huwwa nōb yqabbi l-liʕbe lilhum ᵊṣṣīr awwal ydaššnūn huṃṃa ydaššnūn.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a58"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts21">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ydaššin ʕād ᵊStēfān xōǧa wēya Ismāʕīl, āni w huwwa ǧimīʕ, nugḏ̣ub as-sabəʕ ar-rānāt ʕād ᵊntiqabba ǧawwa al-… al-šāle wēya b-al-kōše. hīčiḏ ba… ᵊntiqabba tā ḏōlak mā yšūfūn-he.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a62"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts20" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>m-as-sabʕ w-ᵊnḥuṭṭ al-xātam ᵊb-wəḥde w-ᵊnǧīb at-tapsiyye nirmī-ha ǧiddām Maʕrūf w-ᵊMḥimmad ʕAli, yōm-in nirmī-ha ʕād huṃṃa, al-xātam in ligū-´ awwal marra, awwal, awwal-ma ymidd īd-u, ta-ngūl awwal marra,</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a67"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts23" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts24">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>in liga al-xātam yāxḏūn al-liʕbe, oynu alıyorlar, yāxḏūn al-liʕbe, in mā ligā-´ awwal marra in ligā-´ ṯāni marra, haḏāk iḥna nsammī-´ dīmi, yinṭi ʕašər raqamāt, nōba wəḥde, ikincisinde.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a74"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts25" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts26">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ᵊngūl “ʔāx! dīmi! Ismāʕīn w Mḥa… Stēfān xōǧe  ysaǧǧlūn ʕašər raqamāt yaʕni puan.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a77"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts27" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts29">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>uxṛa yqabbi Stēfān xōǧe, ṯāni marra, uxṛa ʕayne ydaššin awwal marra, awwal marra, mā yil… al ligā-´ yāxuḏ al-liʕbe, yāxḏ aṣ-ṣīniyye.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a81"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts28" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts30">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ṯāni marra al in ligā-´ dīmi, ṯāliṯ marra al in ligā-´ xaməs raqamāt yinṭī b-aṯ ṯāliṯ in ligā-´, ysaǧǧlū-l-u xaməs raqamāt uxṛa yqabbi, Stēfān xoǧe.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a85"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts31" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts32">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>rābiʕ ta-ngūl ṯāliṯ marra ʕād uxṛa yḥuṭṭ al-xātam ᵊb-qēr wəḥde, yiǧi ʕād hinne mihin sabʕe? awwal marra mā ligā-´, ṯāni marra mā lig ā-´, ṯāliṯ marra mā lig ā-´, arbaʕa ta-ngūl dört, arbaʕ marra mā lig ā-´, xamis marrāt ʕād yḏ̣all iṯnēne, yḏ̣allin iṯnēne ta-ngūl ᵊhnītēn.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a92"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts33" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts34">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yōm-in yḏ̣allin iṯnēne in ligā-´ yāxuḏ al-liʕbe, w-in mā ligā-´, yḏ̣all en son b-at-tāli uxṛa yinṭi puanēn, yiktib ʕalē-´, ysaǧǧil iṯnēne. al-xātam ᵊšnōn yāxḏūn-u? </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a99"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts35" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts37">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>yā trīd tilgā-´ awwal marra yōma en son b-al-ikinǧiyye, b-haḏanne in ligēt-u tāxḏ-u w mā ligēt-u al-liʕbe tḏ̣all ᵊddāwim w tinṭi raqam. uxṛa yiǧi ta… al-xātam ʕād ygūm ydaḥḥiǧ ʕala l-ʕēn, iḥna ʕād al-awwalīn yāxḏūn-u m-al-ʕēn.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a104"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts36" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts38">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ygūl ygūm al-ᵊmẓaffar ¬ē¬¬ē¬ē Stēfān xōǧe, mū qabba l-xātam, ygūm yqabbi ʕēn-u hīčiḏ ma-ydaḥḥiǧ ʕa-t-tapsiyye, in daḥḥag ᵊb-ʕēn-u yāxḏūn-u min ʕēn-u hīčiḏ ydaḥḥiǧ ʕala ʕēn-u, ygūl ydaḥḥiǧ ʕal¬ē-´ hīčiḏ ygūl gāyde ʕēn-u ʕal-he hāḏi yaʕni ygūl.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a111"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts39" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts40">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“ʔā!” ygūl “ligēt-u!”  w yāxḏ al-liʕbe, hāḏi liʕbit al-xwētīme</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Translation" PARENT_REF="default" TIER_ID="Translation">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a113" ANNOTATION_REF="a1">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Playing games, my teacher; in former times, we Arabs; let’s say nowadays there is not many of it. I mean nowadays cards and the game Okay have come in fashion. And now they play on the computer (and) Okay. Let’s say they call it oyun, they play</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a114" ANNOTATION_REF="a9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>As for us, in former times the Arabs used to play xwētīme, xw¬ētīme. We call it xw-ētīme, the xw¬ētīme is played with socks. They form them into a ball; out of seven socks they form it, they bring them into a round shape.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a115" ANNOTATION_REF="a18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>They place them in a row on a tray. And we are, let’s say, four people. I mean sitting at home having a good time, teacher Stephan and I are together in one team, let’s say, and Mḥimmad ʕAli and Maʕrūf are on the other side. They are on one side and we are on the other side.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a116" ANNOTATION_REF="a25">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“Against whome will we play?” We say, “We want to play xw¬ētīme today, just to have fun and entertain ouselves at night. Bro, let’s play for four plates of qadāyif or künefe.” </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a117" ANNOTATION_REF="a29">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>How much are the four plates? They make fourty liras. Teacher Stephan and I will give fourty and Maʕrūf and Mḥimmad ʕAli will give fourty. We leave the money with Melek.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a118" ANNOTATION_REF="a36">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>And we tell her, “Who wins, you give him his fourty and those who lose (we take) their fourty and go buying with it qadāyif and eat them. That means we play in a certain manner.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a119" ANNOTATION_REF="a39">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Then we start and we say, “At how many points does the game end?” Let’s say, “It ends at 101 points. Who wants to play and hide the ring first?” ʕAli wants to hide the ring.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a120" ANNOTATION_REF="a45">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>At first they take two pieces, two socks, let’s say Melek takes two socks, puts the ring in one of them and hides them. Then she brings them and throws them to teacher Stephan or to Mḥimmad ʕAli. I mean they choose who wants to go first and say, “Look it up!”</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a121" ANNOTATION_REF="a53">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Then teacher Stephan, when there are the two socks left for him, he takes one and looks if the ring is in it. If is (in it), it is his turn now to hide, the game is theirs, they start first.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a122" ANNOTATION_REF="a58">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Then teacher Stephan or Ismāʕīl would start; him and me together. We take the seven socks and we hide under a scarf or in the corner. Like this, we hide in order that they cannot see it. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a123" ANNOTATION_REF="a62">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>We put the ring in one of the seven, bring the tray and throw it in front of Maʕrūf and Mḥimmad ʕAli. When we throw them, then they, if they had found the ring on the first time, the first time he puts his hand to draw, let’s say, first try.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a124" ANNOTATION_REF="a67">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>If he finds the ring, they take the game, oynu alıyorlar (in Turkish), they take the game. If he does not find it the first time, if he finds it on the second time, we call it “dīmi” and it counts ten points; at once, if he finds it on the second time.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a125" ANNOTATION_REF="a74">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>On the second time we say, “Ah! dīmi!” Ismāʕīl and teacher Stephan score ten points.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a126" ANNOTATION_REF="a77">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Again, teacher Stephan hides it for the second time, once again the same. He starts first, first time. If he finds it, he takes the game, he takes the tray.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a127" ANNOTATION_REF="a81">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>On the second try it is dīmi; if he finds it on the third try, it gets him five points. On the third time, if he finds it, he scores five points and he hides it again, teacher Stephan.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a128" ANNOTATION_REF="a85">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The fourth, let’s say the third time he puts the ring in another one; aren’t they seven? He does not find it the first time, he does not find it the second time, he does not find it the third time, four, let’s say four, he does not even find it the fourth time, the fifth time, there is two left, two are left, let’s say two tries.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a129" ANNOTATION_REF="a92">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>When there are two left, if he finds it, he takes the game, and if he doesn’t, he has one last chance in the end, again it gives two points, he scores, he scores two points. , how do they take the ring? </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a130" ANNOTATION_REF="a99">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>You either want to find it the first time or at the end, in the second time. If you find it in those tries, you take it, if you don’t the game goes on and gives on points. Another time, the ring… he starts to look at the eye. Our ancestors, they used to take it from the eye.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a131" ANNOTATION_REF="a104">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Let’ say Mẓaffar, eeh, teacher Stephan, hasn’t he hid the ring? So he hides his eye like this, so he does not look at the tray. If he looks by his eye, they take it from his eye (by the help of his eye). He looks with his eye like this, so he looks at it like this and says, his eye is on it, I mean he says that</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a132" ANNOTATION_REF="a111">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>“Ah!,” he says, “I have found it!” And he takes the game. This is the game xwētīme.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="default-lt" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Translation" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
